<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2023-09-03T12:31:58+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">From HK to SG | Expat Living Guide in Singapore</title><entry><title type="html">Best Singapore travel itinerary for tourists</title><link href="/singapore-travel-itinerary/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Best Singapore travel itinerary for tourists" /><published>2023-09-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-travel-itinerary</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-travel-itinerary/"><![CDATA[<p>Apologies for the gaps in posts - things have been hectic over the last month, and with the introduction of our Chinese language posts, I simply haven’t had the time to post new content. However, we are now back!</p>

<p>A few of my friends have been visiting Singapore and have asked me to create an itinerary for them. Many ask whether there are things to do in Singapore. The answer is yes and no. Singapore is a small but mighty city-state that offers a world of experiences within its compact borders. Despite its size, this dynamic metropolis is packed with iconic landmarks, cultural enclaves, stunning gardens, delectable cuisine, and much more. Overall, I recommend 3 days as the optimal amount of time to spend in Singapore. Anything more and you’ll be struggling to find things to do. Here’s the itinerary below. Note - we’ll save a more in-depth restaurant / bars guide for another time.</p>

<h4 id="day-1">Day 1:</h4>

<p><u>Morning<u></u></u></p>
<ul>
  <li>Breakfast at Ya Kun: Start your Singapore adventure with a hearty breakfast at Ya Kun Kaya Toast, a local favorite known for its traditional Singaporean breakfast. Indulge in crispy toast slathered with kaya (coconut jam) and paired with soft-boiled eggs and a cup of aromatic kopi (local coffee). Ya Kun’s are everywhere so it’s not hard to find. Alternatively, visiting Toast Box is ok too.</li>
  <li>Chinatown: After breakfast, make your way to Chinatown, a vibrant district teeming with colorful shophouses, bustling markets, and rich cultural heritage. Take a leisurely stroll along the vibrant streets, visit the historic Sri Mariamman Temple, and savor delicious local street food at the Chinatown Food Street.</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Afternoon<u></u></u></p>
<ul>
  <li>Tiong Bahru: Afterward, make your way to Tiong Bahru, a hip neighborhood known for its trendy cafes and charming heritage buildings. Enjoy a leisurely dinner at one of the local eateries, and explore the neighborhood’s unique boutiques and art galleries. Alternatively, check out the large Tiong Bahru Hawker center market for a local lunch, including Char Kway Teow, Chicken rice and Bak Chor Mee</li>
  <li>Artscience museum: Head to the ArtScience Museum, located within the iconic Marina Bay Sands complex. Explore the museum’s interactive exhibits that blend art, science, and technology, offering a unique and immersive experience.</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Evening<u></u></u></p>
<ul>
  <li>Gardens by the Bay / MBS: As the sun sets, head to Marina Bay Sands (MBS) to witness the spectacular light and sound show at the Marina Bay Sands SkyPark. Enjoy panoramic views of the city skyline and the dazzling light show that illuminates the night sky. At night, head to Gardens by the Bay, a stunning nature park that boasts iconic Supertrees and beautiful flower domes. Explore the various themed gardens and check out the free Garden Rhapsody performance.</li>
  <li>Dinner recommendations - Makansutra Gluttons Bay, Lau Pa Sat hawker center, Bread Street Kitchen by Gordon Ramsay, Extra Virgin Pizza. Plenty to eat around that area</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="day-2">Day 2:</h4>

<p><u>Morning / Afternoon<u></u></u></p>
<ul>
  <li>Sentosa: Head to Sentosa Island, a popular resort island with a myriad of attractions. Spend the afternoon enjoying the sandy beaches, visiting Universal Studios Singapore for thrilling rides and entertainment, or exploring the S.E.A. Aquarium for an underwater adventure. On the way out of Sentosa, check out Vivo City. Plenty to shop at that mall</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Evening<u></u></u></p>
<ul>
  <li>Clarke Quay: Take the MRT from Harborfront (Vivo City) to Clarke Quay. Enjoy a leisurely dinner at one of the many riverside restaurants offering a variety of cuisines. My recommendation is the Song Fa Ba Ku Teh there, a restaurant renowned for its flavorful pork rib soup. If you’re a party person, plenty of clubs / bars here, including the infamous Zouk</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="day-3">Day 3:</h4>

<p><u>Morning:<u></u></u></p>
<ul>
  <li>Little India: Start your day with a visit to Little India, a vibrant cultural enclave filled with colorful shops, aromatic spice stalls, and traditional Indian eateries. Immerse yourself in the vibrant atmosphere, visit Sri Veeramakaliamman Temple, and savor authentic Indian cuisine for breakfast. MTR is a great restaurant here</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Afternoon<u></u></u></p>
<ul>
  <li>Orchard: Explore Orchard Road, Singapore’s premier shopping belt. Stroll along this bustling street lined with luxurious malls, fashion boutiques, and international brands. Shop to your heart’s content or simply soak in the vibrant atmosphere.</li>
  <li>Dempsey: If shopping is not your thing, head to Dempsey Hill, Dempsey Hill offers a unique blend of history, dining, and shopping experiences. Explore the charming colonial-era buildings, indulge in a diverse range of cuisines at the various restaurants (Jumbo, Red Sparrow, Burnt Ends), and browse through the boutique shops and galleries for a delightful day out. FWIW, there’s a Dover Street Market there too</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Evening<u></u></u></p>
<ul>
  <li>Night Safari: Spend the evening at the Singapore Zoo, a world-class wildlife park known for its immersive and naturalistic enclosures. Discover a wide variety of animals and enjoy entertaining animal shows. Experience the unique Night Safari, where you can observe nocturnal animals in their natural habitats</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="some-other-experience-to-consider">Some other experience to consider</h4>
<ul>
  <li>East coast Park: Explore the scenic East Coast Park and enjoy activities like cycling, rollerblading, or simply relaxing on the beach.</li>
  <li>Joo Chiat: Immerse yourself in the colorful heritage of Joo Chiat, known for its Peranakan architecture, vibrant murals, and delicious local food.</li>
  <li>Jewel Airport: Visit Jewel Changi Airport, an architectural marvel that offers a wide range of shopping, dining, and entertainment options, including the stunning indoor waterfall, Canopy Park, and the Sky Nets.</li>
  <li>MacRitchie Reservoir: Embark on a nature adventure at MacRitchie Reservoir, where you can hike along the treetop walk, explore the nature trails, and spot wildlife such as monkeys and birds.</li>
  <li>Sungei Buloh: Discover the beauty of Sungei Buloh Wetland Reserve, a nature reserve teeming with diverse flora and fauna, including migratory birds, reptiles, and mudskippers. This is one of my personal favourites</li>
  <li>Fort Canning Park: Step back in time at Fort Canning Park, a historic landmark with lush greenery, ancient artifacts, and historical significance. Explore the park’s archaeological dig site, visit the Battle Box museum, and enjoy scenic views of the city.</li>
</ul>

<p>With this carefully curated three-day itinerary, you’ll have the opportunity to experience the best of Singapore’s iconic landmarks, vibrant neighborhoods, delicious cuisine, and unique attractions. Get ready for an unforgettable adventure in the Lion City.</p>

<h4 id="recommended-hotels-to-stay-in">Recommended hotels to stay in</h4>

<p>Singapore offers a wide range of hotel options to suit various preferences and budgets. From luxurious 5-star hotels that exude opulence and offer world-class amenities to trendy boutique hotels with unique designs and personalized service, there is something for every traveler. Additionally, budget-friendly accommodations such as hostels and budget hotels provide affordable options without compromising on comfort. Whether you seek a lavish retreat, a charming boutique experience, or a wallet-friendly stay, Singapore has an extensive selection of hotels to cater to diverse needs and enhance your overall travel experience. My personal recs -</p>

<p><u>5 stars<u></u></u></p>

<p>Luxury</p>
<ul>
  <li>Marina Bay Sands</li>
  <li>The Ritz-Carlton, Millenia Singapore</li>
  <li>The Fullerton Bay Hotel</li>
  <li>Mandarin Oriental, Singapore</li>
  <li>Raffles Hotel Singapore</li>
</ul>

<p>Business-y</p>
<ul>
  <li>JW Marriott</li>
  <li>Shangri-La Hotel, Singapore</li>
</ul>

<p>Getaway</p>
<ul>
  <li>W Hotel Sentosa (if Sentosa isn’t too far for you)</li>
  <li>Shangri-La Rasa Sentosa</li>
</ul>

<p><u>4 stars<u></u></u></p>
<ul>
  <li>Hotel Jen Tanglin / Orchard</li>
  <li>Studio M</li>
  <li>Holiday Inn Singapore Atrium</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="things-to-look-out-for">Things to look out for</h4>

<ul>
  <li>Strict Laws: Singapore is known for its strict laws, so it’s important to be mindful of local regulations. Avoid littering, spitting, or engaging in any form of vandalism. Also, remember that chewing gum is not allowed in public.</li>
  <li>Respect for Customs and Culture: Singapore is a multicultural country with diverse customs and traditions. Show respect for local customs, traditions, and religions. Dress modestly when visiting religious sites, and be mindful of local practices and sensitivities.</li>
  <li>Efficient Public Transportation: Singapore has an excellent public transportation system, including buses and trains. Familiarize yourself with the various modes of transportation and their respective routes. Be sure to tap your transport card (EZ-Link or Singapore Tourist Pass) when boarding buses and trains.</li>
  <li>Cleanliness and Hygiene: Singapore prides itself on cleanliness, and littering is heavily frowned upon. Dispose of trash in designated bins, and keep public spaces clean. Be mindful of personal hygiene, especially during the current COVID-19 pandemic. Follow health and safety guidelines, such as wearing masks in public and maintaining social distancing.</li>
  <li>Tipping Culture: Tipping is not a common practice in Singapore, as a service charge is usually included in bills at hotels, restaurants, and cafes.</li>
</ul>

<p>And here it is! I hope you like my Singapore 3-day itinerary and can put it to good use. Let me know if there are other recommendations that you think should be on this list! Comment in your thoughts. Subscribe now to see more content like this.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="expat" /><category term="tourists" /><category term="itinerary" /><category term="Singapore" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Apologies for the gaps in posts - things have been hectic over the last month, and with the introduction of our Chinese language posts, I simply haven’t had the time to post new content. However, we are now back!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/travel.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/travel.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Singapore expat resources now in Chinese</title><link href="/singapore-expats-blog-in-chinese-copy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Singapore expat resources now in Chinese" /><published>2023-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-expats-blog-in-chinese%20copy</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-expats-blog-in-chinese-copy/"><![CDATA[<p>We haven’t posted for two weeks, but there’s a good reason for it. We’re excited to announce the official launch of Chinese translations for our cherished posts! Given the numerous requests from our users for content in Chinese alongside English, we’re delighted to oblige. To access this feature, simply go to our homepage, locate the language selection option at the top, and choose 中文 (Chinese). It’s that simple! Enjoy.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="expat" /><category term="Chinese" /><category term="move" /><category term="relocation" /><category term="Singapore" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We haven’t posted for two weeks, but there’s a good reason for it. We’re excited to announce the official launch of Chinese translations for our cherished posts! Given the numerous requests from our users for content in Chinese alongside English, we’re delighted to oblige. To access this feature, simply go to our homepage, locate the language selection option at the top, and choose 中文 (Chinese). It’s that simple! Enjoy.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/chinese.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/chinese.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">10 reasons to move to Singapore</title><link href="/move-to-singapore/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="10 reasons to move to Singapore" /><published>2023-07-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/move-to-singapore</id><content type="html" xml:base="/move-to-singapore/"><![CDATA[<p>I have been asked many times what the main reasons are for moving to Singapore. I discussed my personal reasons in an earlier post, but that was based on my pre-move conception of the country. Now, after residing here for 5 years and witnessing the experiences of expats in Singapore, as well as interacting with locals, I can confidently state that there are clear-cut reasons for choosing to move to Singapore. With that in mind, I present to you my top ten reasons for living in Singapore.</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Strong Economy: Singapore’s robust and thriving economy is one of the key reasons why many people choose to move here. As a global financial hub, the city-state provides abundant job opportunities in sectors such as finance, technology, healthcare, and logistics. Its business-friendly environment and supportive infrastructure make it an attractive destination for professionals seeking career growth. Singapore is also a stable nation that many value. The job opportunity I’ve had here parallels that of the US and is stronger than that of Hong Kong.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Safety and Security: No country is safer than Singapore. No one will deny this. Singapore consistently ranks among the safest countries in the world, with low crime rates and efficient law enforcement. You can enjoy peace of mind and a secure environment for yourself and your family. Worried about going home at 3am? That’s not a concern in Singapore. Worried about getting pickpocketed on the train? That’s not a concern in Singapore. Worried about your kids being kidnapped from a park? That’s not a concern in Singapore. This is the biggest reason of why expats want to move to Singapore</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Excellent Infrastructure: Singapore boasts world-class infrastructure, which is essential for a comfortable and convenient lifestyle. From a well-connected public transportation system to efficient public services, you’ll find that everything runs smoothly in this city-state. The MRT (subway) connects all over the island and is still expanding its presence with new train lines being built. Well-maintained roads, advanced healthcare facilities, and modern amenities contribute to a high standard of living. I</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Cultural Diversity: One of Singapore’s greatest assets is its cultural diversity. With a mix of Chinese, Malay, Indian, and Western influences, the city-state embraces a multicultural society. This diversity is evident in its vibrant festivals, mouthwatering cuisine, and traditional customs. Living in Singapore means being part of a rich tapestry of cultures and enjoying a truly global experience. Is there racism? Yes. But that’s in any country, especially if you are an expat there. Are there clashes because of cultures and race? Yes. But that’s in any country as well. If anything, Singapore does a great job in maintaining racial harmony.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Education System: If you have children or are pursuing higher education, Singapore’s renowned education system will be of great interest. The city-state is home to top-ranking universities (NUS broke into the top 10 in the world this year I believe), international schools, and well-structured academic programs. The emphasis on quality education ensures that students receive a solid foundation for their future success. For expats, Singapore international schools are some of the top notch in the world (see more about education here). The local education system is intense, but that’s why you send your child to private or international school if you can afford it. The same applies to other countries</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Clean: Despite being a bustling urban center, Singapore is committed to maintaining a clean and green environment. The government’s strict environmental policies have resulted in well-managed parks, gardens, and nature reserves. You can enjoy green spaces, pristine streets, and a city that takes pride in its cleanliness. Now, it’s almost hysterical to complain about this but all the cleanliness takes away from the grunge that any country should have. However, this is about reasons to live in Singapore, and cleanliness is apparent</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Healthcare Excellence: Singapore’s healthcare system is world-class, with state-of-the-art medical facilities and highly skilled healthcare professionals. The country consistently ranks among the best in terms of healthcare outcomes and accessibility. You can have peace of mind knowing that quality healthcare services are readily available when you need them. Private and public healthcare is both amazing too. The country is tiny so a hospital is always at arms reach. Doctors are all quality (even the GPs though they look miserable) and it’s a luxury locals and expats in Singapore always forget</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Food and Dining: Prepare your taste buds for an unforgettable culinary adventure in Singapore. The city-state is renowned for its diverse food scene, offering a wide range of cuisines to satisfy every palate. From affordable street food at hawker centers to Michelin-starred restaurants, you’ll discover a gastronomic paradise where culinary delights await at every turn. I love that you can eat cheap if you want and then eat expensive the next day if that’s what you desire. Moving here for the food isn’t something people usually think about but it’s an unassuming luxury too. The issue with Singapore right now is that there are too many medium-priced food establishments that are not worth, but it takes time to really find what restaurants should be on your blacklist.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Travel Opportunities: Singapore’s strategic location in Southeast Asia makes it an ideal base for exploring the region. With excellent connectivity and transportation links, you can easily travel to neighboring countries and immerse yourself in diverse cultures, stunning landscapes, and unique experiences. Satiate your wanderlust and embark on exciting adventures just a short distance away. You’ll be able to get some great flight deals from this SEA hub too. I averaged 15-20 trips prior to COVID and now 5-7 trips post COVID. All from the heart of Singapore.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Quality of Life: Ultimately, moving to Singapore promises a high quality of life. With efficient public services, good infrastructure, a safe environment, and various amenities, you can enjoy a comfortable and prosperous lifestyle. Singapore consistently ranks well in global quality of life indexes, reflecting its commitment to providing a thriving and inclusive community for residents. Yes, the cost of living is high but taxes are low. You have the choice to live lavishly or not.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>If you’re seeking a dynamic and cosmopolitan city that offers tremendous opportunities, a diverse culture, and an excellent standard of living, Singapore could be the perfect destination for you. From its strong economy to its safe environment, world-class healthcare, and culinary delights, Singapore has much to offer. Consider these 10 compelling reasons as you contemplate your next chapter in life. I’ve talked about Singapore’s weaknesses. It’s time to talk about Singapore’s strengths too. Don’t forget to subscribe to follow more content like this.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Immigration" /><category term="move" /><category term="relocation" /><category term="Singapore" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I have been asked many times what the main reasons are for moving to Singapore. I discussed my personal reasons in an earlier post, but that was based on my pre-move conception of the country. Now, after residing here for 5 years and witnessing the experiences of expats in Singapore, as well as interacting with locals, I can confidently state that there are clear-cut reasons for choosing to move to Singapore. With that in mind, I present to you my top ten reasons for living in Singapore.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/movetosg.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/movetosg.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Best doctors, clinics and hospitals in Singapore</title><link href="/best-doctor-singapore/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Best doctors, clinics and hospitals in Singapore" /><published>2023-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/best-doctor-singapore</id><content type="html" xml:base="/best-doctor-singapore/"><![CDATA[<p>In an <a href="https://fromhktosg.github.io/singapore-healthcare-copy/">earlier article</a>, I talked about the healthcare system in Singapore and how robust it is, be it in the public or private sector. Since then, a few readers have asked me to recommend my go-to doctors so here’s my curated list of the best doctors, hospitals and clinics in Singapore.</p>

<p>In general, I’m a big fan of Raffles Hospital but have slowly begun seeing more doctors in Gleneagles as I think the nurses at Raffles aren’t that great. P.S. - yes, I have a lot of health problems so I’ve seen a lot of doctors.</p>

<h4 id="preferred-hospitals-in-singapore">Preferred hospitals in Singapore</h4>

<p>Gleneagles, Mount Elizabeth, Raffles Hospital. These are the best.</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/assets/images/glen.jpg" alt="Mte" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>Mount Elizabeth Novena Hospital Lobby</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<h4 id="preferred-health-checks-in-singapore">Preferred health checks in Singapore</h4>

<p>All of the ones I went to are subpar but Raffles hospital is the best of the lot. If anyone has a better option, please message me.</p>

<h4 id="preferred-doctors--clinics-in-singapore-western-medicine">Preferred doctors / clinics in Singapore (Western Medicine)</h4>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>General Practitioner (GP)  - <a href="https://www.healthcare.com.sg/item/dr-steven-ang-anesthetic-family-clinic/">Dr Steven Ang</a> (Dr Steven Ang Aesthetic &amp; Family Clinic)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Ophthalmologist (eye) - <a href="https://www.rafflesmedicalgroup.com/doctor/a-prof-johnson-tan-choon-hwai/">A/Prof Johnson Tan Choon Hwai</a> (Raffles Hospital)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>ENT (ear, throat, nose) - <a href="https://www.rafflesmedicalgroup.com/doctor/dr-chan-siew-chee/">Dr Chan Siew Chee</a> (Raffles Hospital), <a href="https://www.drjeeve.com/">Dr Jeeve Kanagalingam</a> (The ENT Clinic Gleneagles)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Rheumatologist (allergies) - <a href="https://www.rafflesmedicalgroup.com/doctor/dr-chong-yong-yeow/">Dr Chong Yong Yeow</a> (Raffles Hospital)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Dermatologist (skin) - <a href="https://www.rafflesmedicalgroup.com/doctor/dr-tan-siew-kiang/">Dr Tan Siew Kiang</a> (Raffles Hospital), <a href="https://www.dermatologyandco.sg/">Dr Tan Wei Sheng</a> (Dermatology and co)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Counseling (mental health) - <a href="https://www.rafflesmedicalgroup.com/doctor/ms-saras-atre/">Ms Saras Atre</a> (Raffles Hospital)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Surgery / Colorectal - <a href="https://www.rafflesmedicalgroup.com/doctor/dr-wong-kutt-sing/">Dr Wong Kutt Sing</a> (Raffles hospital)</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>This roster of doctors is absolutely A-grade. N/A - Oncologist, OBGYN, pediatrician.</p>

<h4 id="preferred-traditional-chinese-medicine-tcm">Preferred traditional Chinese medicine (TCM)</h4>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Tui Na - <a href="https://sinkangtcm.com.sg/?gad=1">Sin Kang TCM</a></p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Bo Jin - <a href="https://www.yongkangtcm.com/refresh-tcm-wellness">Refresh TCM</a></p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>Don’t have too much experience on this one so please let me know what the best TCM places are out there.</p>

<h4 id="preferred-physiotherapy-and-functional-training">Preferred physiotherapy and functional training</h4>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://www.coreconcepts.com.sg/">Core concepts</a> - most of the physiotherapists there are fantastic and caring.</li>
</ul>

<p>I have not found a podiatrist with whom I am satisfied, so please let me know if you have any suggestions for one. A short post today but I hope this helps in finding your ideal doctor in Singapore. Subscribe now to see more content like this.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Healthcare" /><category term="hospitals" /><category term="doctors" /><category term="clinics" /><category term="Singapore" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In an earlier article, I talked about the healthcare system in Singapore and how robust it is, be it in the public or private sector. Since then, a few readers have asked me to recommend my go-to doctors so here’s my curated list of the best doctors, hospitals and clinics in Singapore.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/penthouse.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/penthouse.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Tuition addiction: Unpacking tuition in Singapore</title><link href="/singapore-tuition/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tuition addiction: Unpacking tuition in Singapore" /><published>2023-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-tuition</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-tuition/"><![CDATA[<p>During a casual lunch with a friend, I was taken aback when he revealed that he spends a staggering $1000 SGD per month on tuition for his 5-year-old child, highlighting the extent to which some parents prioritize academic enrichment from an early age. My friend’s kid seemed like a smart one - why drill more knowledge in her from such a young age? In an earlier post, I touched on the education system in Singapore and Hong Kong. Both countries place great emphasis on academic excellence, leading to a thriving tuition landscape in both regions. The perception of tuition being ingrained as a necessity by parents has sparked debates on its potential negative impact on children’s well-being and overall education system. In today’s post, we’ll dive into the emergence of tuition, effects the industry has on parents and children and a comparison of the top tuition centers and their marketing tactics in Hong Kong and Singapore. I’d say tuition is more common with locals, but an increasing number of expats in Singapore is exploring this. In case you missed out, check out my <a href="https://fromhktosg.github.io/education/">earlier article</a> on the education system of Singapore and how it fares against Hong Kong.</p>

<h4 id="emergence-of-tuition-as-an-industry">Emergence of tuition as an industry</h4>

<p><u> Hong Kong <u></u></u></p>

<p>The first tuition center in Hong Kong is believed to be Modern Education, established in 1971 by Mr. Lam Wing-kee. Initially, it aimed to provide supplementary education to students who needed extra assistance. Over time, tuition centers gained popularity due to the competitive nature of the education system and the desire for academic excellence. They became more mainstream in the 1980s and 1990s as the demand for additional academic support grew. Today, tuition centers are a common feature of the education landscape in Hong Kong, catering to students of all ages and academic levels.</p>

<p><u> Singapore <u></u></u></p>

<p>Tuition centers started emerging in Singapore in the late 1970s and early 1980s. As the education system became more competitive, the demand for additional academic support outside of school grew. This led to the establishment of the first tuition centers, which offered supplementary classes and coaching to help students excel in their studies. Over the years, the tuition industry in Singapore has continued to expand and evolve, with a wide range of centers catering to various subjects and academic levels.</p>

<h4 id="why-send-your-children-to-tuition-in-singapore">Why send your children to tuition in Singapore?</h4>

<p>TL;DR - helicopter parents are stressed about their kids not being superstars so they’ll do everything to give their kids a boost</p>

<ul>
  <li>Academic Excellence: Tuition is seen as a pathway to help children achieve better academic results and excel in their studies.</li>
  <li>Supplementing School Education: Tuition provides additional support beyond the regular school curriculum, helping students understand challenging subjects or topics.</li>
  <li>Competitive Academic Environment: Singapore’s competitive education system motivates parents to enroll their children in tuition to gain a competitive edge over their peers.</li>
  <li>Confidence Building: Tuition boosts students’ confidence by providing personalized attention, addressing their weaknesses, and enhancing their understanding of subjects.</li>
  <li>Individualized Learning: Tuition offers a customized learning experience, catering to each child’s unique learning style, pace, and specific needs.</li>
  <li>Addressing Learning Gaps: Tuition helps bridge any knowledge gaps, ensuring students keep up with the rigorous curriculum and stay on track with their peers.</li>
  <li>Enrichment Opportunities: Tuition can provide enrichment activities, projects, and resources that go beyond the school syllabus, broadening students’ knowledge and skills.</li>
  <li>Holistic Development: Some parents see tuition as a means to foster holistic development, focusing on critical thinking, problem-solving, and cultivating a passion for learning.</li>
  <li>Exam Preparation: Tuition centers often specialize in exam preparation, equipping students with effective study strategies, exam techniques, and practice materials.</li>
  <li>Parental Expectations: Parents may send their kids to tuition due to societal and parental expectations, believing that it is essential for their children’s academic success.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="how-do-these-tuition-centers-teach">How do these tuition centers teach?</h4>

<p>Every format you can think of. Depending on whether it’s catered to local Singaporeans or expats in Singapore, they can differ given a preference for smaller class size for the former. Listing a few here -</p>

<ul>
  <li>One-on-one sessions: Personalized attention and focused guidance.</li>
  <li>Group classes: Opportunities for interaction and peer learning.</li>
  <li>Large classes: A cost-effective option with a diverse learning environment.</li>
  <li>Recordings: Flexibility to revisit lessons and review materials.</li>
  <li>Mass streaming: Access to educational content on a larger scale.</li>
  <li>Hybrid models: Combination of in-person and online teaching for flexibility.</li>
  <li>Online platforms: Convenient and accessible learning experience.</li>
  <li>Classroom-based: Traditional setting with teacher-student interaction.</li>
  <li>Tutorial centers: Dedicated centers for subject-specific instruction.</li>
  <li>Home tuition: Individualized teaching in a familiar environment.</li>
  <li>Online tutoring: Virtual tutoring sessions for remote learning.</li>
  <li>Exam-focused crash courses: Intensive courses for exam preparation.</li>
  <li>Subject-specific coaching: Specialized instruction to enhance understanding.</li>
  <li>Remedial tuition: Targeted support for students who need extra help.</li>
  <li>Enrichment programs: Supplementary classes to broaden knowledge and skills.</li>
  <li>Preparatory classes: Preparation for educational transitions and exams.</li>
</ul>

<p>Covid accelerated the online models, and as shown in kdramas, you’ll get masses of students listening to a tutor livestream their teachings.</p>

<h4 id="tuition-in-relations-to-gifted-education-program-in-singapore">Tuition in relations to Gifted Education Program in Singapore</h4>

<p>One ting expats in Singapore may not know is that many go through tuition to get into a Gifted Education Program in Singapore. A Gifted Education Program (GEP) is a specialized educational program designed to meet the needs of academically gifted or talented students. It aims to provide a more challenging and enriched learning experience for students who demonstrate exceptional abilities in intellectual, creative, or specific academic domains. Funnily enough, those who get into GEP continue with education</p>

<p>The specific structure and implementation of GEP may vary between countries and educational systems. In general, however, the program identifies gifted students through various assessment methods, such as standardized tests, teacher recommendations, or portfolio assessments. Once identified, these students are offered specialized instruction and curriculum that goes beyond the standard curriculum provided to their peers.</p>

<p>Gifted education programs often feature accelerated learning, in-depth study of subjects, problem-solving activities, and opportunities for creativity and critical thinking. They may involve small class sizes, specialized teachers, and access to resources and enrichment activities not typically available in regular classrooms.</p>

<p>The goals of a Gifted Education Program are to nurture the talents and potential of gifted students, provide appropriate intellectual stimulation, foster their social and emotional development, and support their overall growth. These programs aim to challenge gifted students academically, help them reach their full potential, and prepare them for future academic and professional success.</p>

<p>Gifted education programs can be found at various levels of education, ranging from primary and secondary schools to higher education institutions. The specific criteria for eligibility and the nature of the program may differ based on the country’s educational policies and practices.</p>

<p>It is important to note that gifted education programs are designed to meet the unique needs of gifted students and provide them with an educational environment that supports their advanced abilities. The aim is to ensure that gifted students are appropriately challenged, engaged, and given opportunities to thrive academically and personally.</p>

<h4 id="so-how-much-is-spent-on-tuition">So how much is spent on tuition?</h4>

<p>The average spend on tuition in Singapore and Hong Kong varies based on factors such as the level of education, subjects, and the individual preferences of students and parents. In Singapore, where tuition is highly prevalent, the average monthly expenditure on tuition can range from SGD 200 to SGD 1,000 or more, depending on the grade level and intensity of the tuition sought. Some families may spend even higher amounts for specialized programs or individual tutoring. Here are a few stats for Singapore - 1) In 2019, Singapore families spent $1.4b on private tuition for kids last year, 2) 70% of parents send their child for tuition. 8 in 10 Primary school students and 6 in 10 Secondary school students pay for private tuition. This sounds pretty unhealthy to me, given the dollars and time invested.</p>

<p>In Hong Kong, the average spend on tuition is also significant, reflecting the competitive academic environment. The monthly expenditure on tuition can range from HKD 1,000 to HKD 5,000 or higher. Like in Singapore, the costs can vary based on the grade level, subjects, and the reputation and quality of the tuition center or private tutor.</p>

<p>It’s important to note that these figures are approximate averages and can vary significantly depending on individual circumstances. Factors such as the number of subjects, frequency of tuition sessions, and the specific educational goals of students and parents can influence the overall expenditure on tuition.</p>

<p>Furthermore, it’s worth mentioning that the tuition landscape in both Singapore and Hong Kong is highly diverse, with a wide range of options available at various price points. Families have the flexibility to choose from group tuition, private tutoring, online platforms, and specialized programs, each with its own cost structure.</p>

<p>Overall, while tuition can be a substantial financial commitment for families in both Singapore and Hong Kong, it is considered a valuable investment in students’ academic success and future prospects. The average spend on tuition reflects the importance placed on education and the willingness of parents to provide additional support to enhance their children’s learning experiences.</p>

<h4 id="negative-effects-of-tuition-and-enrichment-centers">Negative effects of tuition and enrichment centers</h4>

<p>Listing just a few…</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Increased Academic Pressure:
Statistics from the Programme for International Student Assessment (PISA) showed that Singaporean students reported higher levels of academic pressure compared to their international counterparts.
According to a survey conducted by the National Youth Council, around 90% of students in Singapore feel stressed about academic performance.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Impact on Mental Health:
The Institute of Mental Health reported that about 1 in 7 students aged 13 to 16 in Singapore experienced significant symptoms of anxiety and depression.
A study by the National University of Singapore found that high-stress levels due to academic pressure were associated with higher rates of mental health issues among students.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Reduced Creativity and Well-Rounded Development:
The emphasis on academic achievement and structured learning in enrichment centers may limit opportunities for students to explore their creativity and develop a well-rounded skill set.
The Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD) reported that Singaporean students had lower levels of creative problem-solving skills compared to their international peers.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Financial Burden:
Enrichment programs can be expensive, adding to the financial burden on families. According to a survey by the Singapore Department of Statistics, education expenses accounted for a significant portion of household expenditure.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Educational Inequality:
Higher-income families have greater access to enrichment centers, creating educational disparities between socioeconomic groups. This may perpetuate inequality and hinder equal opportunities for academic success.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>I’m sure parents know of these reasons already, but it’s just part of Singapore society now. Tuition centers have woven themselves into the very fabric of Singapore, perpetuating a culture of excessive academic pressure and fostering a dependency on external help for success. This pervasive reliance on tuition has created a system where students feel inadequate without constant supplementary support, breeding a sense of insecurity and stifling their true potential.</p>

<h4 id="top-tuition-centers-in-hong-kong-and-singapore">Top tuition centers in Hong Kong and Singapore</h4>

<p>Top Tuition Centers in Hong Kong: In Hong Kong, several prominent tuition centers have established themselves as leaders in the industry. For instance, Beacon College, known for its strong track record in helping students excel in examinations, offers comprehensive programs and experienced tutors. Similarly, Modern Education, with its personalized approach and small class sizes, aims to provide individual attention to students. These centers employ marketing tactics such as testimonials from successful students, showcasing their achievements and emphasizing the effectiveness of their teaching methods. They also organize workshops and seminars to engage parents and highlight their centers’ expertise.</p>

<p>Top Tuition Centers in Singapore: Likewise, Singapore boasts several renowned tuition centers that have gained popularity among students and parents. The Learning Lab, known for its structured curriculum and highly qualified tutors, focuses on holistic development and academic excellence. Another notable center is MindChamps, which combines academic enrichment with character development, offering a unique approach to education. These centers employ marketing strategies such as informative websites, featuring their success stories and testimonials from satisfied parents. They also leverage social media platforms and collaborate with schools to enhance their visibility and reputation.</p>

<h4 id="marketing-tactics-of-these-tuition-centers">Marketing tactics of these tuition centers</h4>

<p>Let’s switch gears and discuss the marketing tactics of tuition centers.</p>

<p>In a predatory manner, tuition centers in both Hong Kong and Singapore employ manipulative marketing tactics to prey on students and their parents. Exploiting the fears and insecurities surrounding academic success, these centers boast about their high success rates, using testimonials and selective statistics to lure in vulnerable students. By forging partnerships with schools and leveraging online platforms, they establish an air of legitimacy and credibility, deceiving parents into believing that their services are necessary for their child’s educational advancement. These profit-driven establishments capitalize on the educational anxiety of families, perpetuating a toxic cycle of dependency and extracting financial gains at the expense of students’ well-being.</p>

<p>I see photos of young adults and their grades littered across mall banners, bus ads and building displays in Singapore. Great marketing, not healthy for society.</p>

<h4 id="how-is-the-industry-regulated">How is the industry regulated?</h4>

<p>Both Hong Kong and Singapore have regulations in place regarding tuition centers to ensure quality education and safeguard the interests of students.</p>

<p>In Hong Kong, tuition centers are governed by the Education Bureau (EDB) and are required to register with the government. The Education Ordinance sets out guidelines for tuition centers, including requirements for proper facilities, qualified teachers, and adherence to safety regulations. The EDB conducts inspections and imposes penalties for non-compliance or operating without registration.</p>

<p>Similarly, in Singapore, tuition centers are regulated by the Ministry of Education (MOE). Tuition centers must comply with the Private Education Act and the Committee for Private Education (CPE) regulations. They need to be registered with the MOE or be exempted from registration. The MOE monitors tuition centers to ensure they meet the necessary standards, including teacher qualifications, premises safety, and appropriate pedagogical practices.</p>

<p>Both jurisdictions also have regulations in place to prevent excessive advertising and misleading claims by tuition centers. Advertisements must be accurate, transparent, and adhere to guidelines set by the respective authorities. This is to protect consumers, particularly parents and students, from false or exaggerated promises.</p>

<p>These regulations aim to maintain the quality and integrity of tuition services, ensuring that students receive effective and reliable educational support. By imposing standards on tuition centers, the authorities seek to safeguard the educational well-being of students and promote a fair and transparent learning environment.</p>

<h4 id="is-tuition-an-addiction">Is tuition an addiction?</h4>

<p>Yes. Tuition has become an addiction in many educational systems, including in Hong Kong and Singapore. The intense pressure to excel academically, coupled with the fear of falling behind, has created a culture where students and parents alike feel compelled to rely on tuition as a crutch. This addiction is fueled by the belief that extra classes and constant studying are the only pathways to success, leaving little room for personal growth, hobbies, or a balanced lifestyle. Students become dependent on the constant validation and reassurance that tuition provides, fearing that without it, they will lose their competitive edge. The addictive nature of tuition perpetuates a cycle of high expectations, stress, and burnout, ultimately undermining the intrinsic joy of learning and stifling individual creativity and curiosity.</p>

<p>My recommendation to parents is to let the kids learn through school and self study and if they are really struggling in some subjects or want a leg up in another, then explore tuition as an option. Don’t put your kids through enrichment classes every evening. Let them play, enjoy themselves and build knowledge through their own curiosity.</p>

<p>What do you think of the enrichment center system? Comment in your thoughts. Subscribe now to see more content like this.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Education" /><category term="tuition" /><category term="Hong Kong" /><category term="Singapore" /><category term="parents" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[During a casual lunch with a friend, I was taken aback when he revealed that he spends a staggering $1000 SGD per month on tuition for his 5-year-old child, highlighting the extent to which some parents prioritize academic enrichment from an early age. My friend’s kid seemed like a smart one - why drill more knowledge in her from such a young age? In an earlier post, I touched on the education system in Singapore and Hong Kong. Both countries place great emphasis on academic excellence, leading to a thriving tuition landscape in both regions. The perception of tuition being ingrained as a necessity by parents has sparked debates on its potential negative impact on children’s well-being and overall education system. In today’s post, we’ll dive into the emergence of tuition, effects the industry has on parents and children and a comparison of the top tuition centers and their marketing tactics in Hong Kong and Singapore. I’d say tuition is more common with locals, but an increasing number of expats in Singapore is exploring this. In case you missed out, check out my earlier article on the education system of Singapore and how it fares against Hong Kong.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/bamboo.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/bamboo.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Guide to Singapore’s healthcare system: Public vs Private</title><link href="/singapore-healthcare/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Guide to Singapore’s healthcare system: Public vs Private" /><published>2023-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-healthcare</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-healthcare/"><![CDATA[<p>The pandemic’s over. Wahoo! Singapore’s healthcare system, renowned for its efficiency, quality, and accessibility, was put under the spotlight during the past 3 years of COVID. This post explores the distinctions between private and public healthcare in Singapore, examining factors such as cost, accessibility, and quality of care. Additionally, it delves into the remuneration of doctors in Singapore, shedding light on their earning potential and the considerations surrounding their salaries. Oh, you’ll also find out about the best hospitals and where you can find them. By understanding the dynamics of Singapore’s healthcare landscape, we gain insights into the complex interplay between private and public sectors and the compensation structures that shape the medical profession in the country. We won’t be covering insurance in-depth in this post (especially cheap health insurance). We’ll save that for another time.</p>

<h4 id="hk-vs-singapore---a-little-on-their-healthcare-systems">HK vs Singapore - a little on their healthcare systems</h4>

<p>Let’s begin with comparing these two Asian countries before we double click into Singapore. The healthcare systems in Hong Kong and Singapore are often praised for their efficiency, accessibility, and quality of care. Comparing across a few criteria -</p>

<p>Healthcare Expenditure: In terms of healthcare expenditure, Hong Kong and Singapore differ significantly. According to the World Bank, Hong Kong’s healthcare expenditure accounted for approximately 17.5% of its GDP in 2019, while Singapore’s healthcare expenditure was around 4.8% of its GDP in the same year. This substantial disparity suggests that Hong Kong allocates a higher proportion of its resources to healthcare compared to Singapore.</p>

<p>Infrastructure and Facilities: Both Hong Kong and Singapore boast well-developed healthcare infrastructures. Hong Kong features a mix of public and private hospitals, including several renowned medical centers and specialty hospitals. Singapore, on the other hand, is known for its excellent public healthcare system, with a network of public hospitals and polyclinics. Additionally, Singapore has actively promoted medical tourism, attracting patients from around the world to seek specialized treatments.</p>

<p>Healthcare Outcomes: When examining healthcare outcomes, both Hong Kong and Singapore demonstrate commendable results. According to the World Health Organization (WHO), Hong Kong’s life expectancy at birth is approximately 84 years, while Singapore’s stands at around 83 years. These figures indicate that residents of both regions enjoy relatively long and healthy lives.</p>

<p>Patient Satisfaction: Patient satisfaction is a crucial aspect of healthcare delivery. In a survey conducted by the Hong Kong Hospital Authority in 2020, 76% of respondents expressed satisfaction with the quality of healthcare services provided. Similarly, a survey conducted by the Ministry of Health in Singapore in the same year reported that 85% of patients were satisfied with the overall quality of care received. These high satisfaction rates reflect the emphasis placed on patient-centered care in both systems.</p>

<p>Challenges and Opportunities: Despite the positive aspects, both healthcare systems face challenges. In Hong Kong, long waiting times for specialist appointments and limited resources are areas of concern. In Singapore, the rising cost of healthcare and an aging population present challenges to sustainability and affordability. However, these challenges also present opportunities for continuous improvement, innovation, and policy reforms in both regions.</p>

<p>Overall, both systems are robust, advanced and managed well. If you’re deciding which country to live in, I wouldn’t use healthcare as a deciding factor.</p>

<h4 id="cost-of-healthcare">Cost of healthcare</h4>

<p>The average cost of healthcare in Singapore can vary depending on factors such as the type of medical service needed, the healthcare facility, and whether an individual is a citizen, permanent resident, or foreigner. However, it’s important to note that the healthcare system in Singapore operates on a mixed financing model, with government subsidies and insurance coverage helping to make healthcare more affordable for residents.</p>

<p>For Singapore citizens and permanent residents, a significant portion of healthcare costs is covered by government subsidies and the mandatory national health insurance scheme known as MediShield Life. MediShield Life provides basic coverage for hospitalization and selected outpatient treatments.</p>

<p>That being said, there may still be out-of-pocket expenses, such as deductibles, co-payments, and non-subsidized services. The specific costs can vary widely based on factors like the complexity of the medical procedure, the ward class chosen (e.g., public hospital A ward, B1 ward, etc.), and the specific healthcare provider.</p>

<p>For foreigners or individuals without permanent residency in Singapore, the cost of healthcare can be higher (significantly). They are generally not eligible for government subsidies and may need to rely on private insurance or self-payment for medical expenses. Private healthcare providers in Singapore often have their own pricing structures, which can vary significantly. All that being said, expats are most likely covered by private insurance from the company, with most being top-class. My company’s insurance covers $500 USD worth of eyeglasses every year. You just can’t complain. Insurance for expats in Singapore if out of pocket is expensive, but we’ll save that for another time.</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/assets/images/supportsystems.jpg" alt="supportsystems" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>Singapore healthcare is one of the best support systems for the nation’s prosperity</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<h4 id="service-providers">Service providers</h4>

<p>Public Singapore hospitals form the backbone for most of the country. Whilst the wait for public hospitals is generally much longer, the quality of them is top notch in Singapore. These hospitals provide high-quality medical services to cater to the healthcare needs of both local residents and international patients. Here are some features of public hospitals in Singapore:</p>
<ul>
  <li>High-quality medical services: Singapore’s public hospitals have modern facilities and advanced medical technology to deliver excellent healthcare services. These hospitals have top-notch medical experts and nursing staff dedicated to the treatment and care of patients (comparable to private)</li>
  <li>Wide range of specialized healthcare: Singapore’s public hospitals cover various specialized fields, including internal medicine, surgery, obstetrics and gynecology, pediatrics, cardiology, ophthalmology, orthopedics, and more. Whether it’s routine health check-ups or complex surgeries, these hospitals provide comprehensive specialized medical services.</li>
  <li>Medical technology and innovation: Singapore’s public hospitals are committed to driving medical technology innovation and application. These hospitals adopt advanced diagnostic and treatment technologies, including medical imaging, surgical robotics, genetic testing, precision medicine, and more, to provide more accurate and effective healthcare.</li>
  <li>Medical research and education: Public hospitals in Singapore collaborate closely with academic and research institutions to advance medical research and education. These hospitals constantly strive to enhance the level of healthcare and service quality through scientific research and the exchange of medical knowledge.</li>
  <li>Comprehensive healthcare services: Singapore’s public hospitals offer comprehensive healthcare services, including preventive care, health screenings, chronic disease management, and rehabilitation care. These hospitals are committed to maintaining people’s overall health and provide various preventive measures and health promotion activities.</li>
</ul>

<p>In conclusion, public hospitals in Singapore provide top-quality medical services, advanced technology, and a wide range of specialized healthcare. They prioritize patient care and continuously contribute to medical research and education. These hospitals play a crucial role in ensuring the well-being and health of the population in Singapore.</p>

<p>Here’s a list of the popular public hospitals</p>
<ul>
  <li>Singapore General Hospital (SGH): SGH is the largest and oldest public hospital in Singapore. It offers a comprehensive range of medical services and specialties, including general medicine, surgery, cardiology, oncology, and more.</li>
  <li>National University Hospital (NUH): NUH is a tertiary hospital linked to the National University of Singapore. It provides specialized medical care in various areas, including cardiology, orthopedics, neurology, and pediatrics.</li>
  <li>Changi General Hospital (CGH): CGH is located in the eastern part of Singapore and offers a wide range of medical services, including emergency care, surgery, women’s health, and geriatrics.</li>
  <li>Khoo Teck Puat Hospital (KTPH): KTPH is a community hospital with a focus on holistic healthcare and patient-centered services. It provides general medical and surgical services, as well as specialized care in areas such as psychiatry and rehabilitation.</li>
  <li>Tan Tock Seng Hospital (TTSH): TTSH is a leading acute care general hospital in Singapore. It offers a comprehensive range of medical services, including infectious diseases, respiratory medicine, gastroenterology, and more.</li>
</ul>

<p>Others include Alexandra hospital, KK Women’s and Children’s Hospital (KKH), national university hospital and woodlands hospital. When looking for a hospital, remember to see what’s your nearest hospital and the hospital visiting hours.</p>

<h4 id="what-are-polyclinics">What are polyclinics?</h4>
<p>Polyclinics in Singapore are primary healthcare facilities that provide a range of general medical services to the public. These clinics are operated by the National Healthcare Group (NHG) and SingHealth, two major healthcare clusters in Singapore. Polyclinics aim to offer accessible and affordable healthcare services to Singaporean residents.</p>

<p>Here are some key features and services provided by polyclinics:</p>
<ul>
  <li>General Medical Services: Polyclinics offer general outpatient services such as consultations, examinations, diagnosis, and treatment for common medical conditions. They are staffed by a team of general practitioners (GPs) who provide primary healthcare.</li>
  <li>Chronic Disease Management: Polyclinics play a vital role in managing chronic diseases such as diabetes, hypertension, asthma, and others. They provide regular monitoring, health education, and medication management to help patients manage their conditions effectively.</li>
  <li>Health Screening: Polyclinics offer health screening programs that cover various age groups and specific health concerns. These screenings help detect and prevent potential health problems at an early stage.</li>
  <li>Dental Services: Many polyclinics have dental clinics that provide basic dental services like check-ups, scaling, polishing, and extractions.</li>
  <li>Health Promotion and Education: Polyclinics conduct health promotion activities and provide education on preventive measures, healthy lifestyle practices, and disease management.</li>
  <li>Allied Health Services: Some polyclinics have allied health professionals such as dietitians, physiotherapists, and occupational therapists who offer specialized services to support patient care.</li>
</ul>

<p>Polyclinics in Singapore operate on an appointment-based system, although walk-in consultations may be available for urgent cases. The fees charged at polyclinics are subsidized for Singaporean citizens and permanent residents, making healthcare services more affordable. Patients can also use their national health insurance, MediSave, to pay for eligible services at polyclinics. Polyclinics serve as an essential component of Singapore’s primary healthcare system, providing accessible and comprehensive care to the community.</p>

<h3 id="on-to-private-hospitals">On to private hospitals</h3>

<h4 id="why-go-private">Why go private?</h4>

<p>There are several reasons why individuals might choose to go to private hospitals instead of public hospitals in Singapore. Here are some possible reasons:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Shorter waiting times: Private hospitals generally have shorter waiting times for consultations, treatments, and surgeries compared to public hospitals. This can be appealing for individuals who prefer quicker access to medical services.</li>
  <li>More personalized care: Private hospitals often provide a more personalized and luxurious healthcare experience. They may offer amenities such as private rooms, personalized attention from medical staff, and a greater focus on patient comfort and convenience.</li>
  <li>Access to specific doctors or specialists: Private hospitals may have a wider selection of doctors and specialists who may be renowned in their respective fields. Patients who have specific preferences or seek specialized care from a particular doctor may opt for private hospitals to access their preferred healthcare providers.</li>
  <li>Comprehensive health screening packages: Private hospitals often offer comprehensive health screening packages that cater to individuals who prioritize preventive care and regular health check-ups. These packages may include a wide range of tests and examinations to assess overall health and detect potential health issues at an early stage.</li>
  <li>Greater flexibility and choice: Private hospitals provide individuals with more flexibility and choice in terms of appointment scheduling, treatment options, and hospital preferences. Patients may have more control over their healthcare decisions and the ability to tailor their treatment experience according to their preferences.</li>
  <li>Availability of alternative therapies: Private hospitals may offer a broader range of alternative therapies and complementary medicine options that are not typically available in public hospitals. This can attract individuals who prefer a more holistic approach to healthcare. We’ll cover Traditional Chinese Medicine (TCM) another time, but that’s also a huge industry in Singapore.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="popular-private-hospitals">Popular private hospitals</h4>
<p>Here are some notable private hospitals in Singapore:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Mount Elizabeth Hospital: Mount Elizabeth Hospital is one of the largest private hospitals in Singapore. It has two branches, Mount Elizabeth Orchard and Mount Elizabeth Novena, and offers a comprehensive range of medical specialties and advanced treatment options. This is part of the Parkway Health Group.</li>
  <li>Gleneagles Hospital: Gleneagles Hospital is a renowned private hospital in Singapore known for its high-quality healthcare services. It provides specialized care in areas such as cardiology, oncology, orthopedics, and women’s health. This is also part of the Parkway Health Group</li>
  <li>Raffles Hospital: Raffles Hospital is a leading private hospital that offers a wide range of medical services and specialties. It is known for its advanced diagnostic and treatment capabilities and provides personalized and holistic healthcare.</li>
  <li>Thomson Medical Centre: Thomson Medical Centre is a private hospital that specializes in women’s and children’s healthcare. It offers a comprehensive range of obstetrics, gynecology, and pediatric services.</li>
  <li>Parkway East Hospital: Parkway East Hospital is a private general acute care hospital located in the eastern part of Singapore. It provides a broad range of medical services, including surgery, internal medicine, and specialized outpatient care.</li>
</ul>

<p>My humnble opinion of what’s best - I’ve spent a long time at Raffles and recently moved over to Gleneagles / Mount E. Whilst Raffles doctors are fantastic, I struggle with their nurses, booking systems that surprisingly don’t communicate much with each other and insurance expenses (despite having the best medical insurance policy in Singapore). P.S., their health checks all suck.</p>

<h4 id="private-versus-public-comparison">Private versus public comparison</h4>

<p>Whilst these are just approximates, here are cost ranges for healthcare services in Singapore, comparing public and private sectors:</p>

<p><u> Consultation fees <u></u></u></p>
<ul>
  <li>Public healthcare: GP consultation fees range from SGD 20 to SGD 50.</li>
  <li>Private healthcare: GP consultation fees can range from SGD 50 to SGD 150 or more.</li>
</ul>

<p><u> Hospitalization costs (per day) <u></u></u></p>

<p>Public healthcare:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Class B2 ward (shared room): SGD 200 to SGD 400.</li>
  <li>Class B1 ward (semi-private room): SGD 500 to SGD 800.</li>
  <li>Class A ward (single room): SGD 800 to SGD 2,000 or more.</li>
</ul>

<p>Private healthcare: Hospitalization costs can range from SGD 1,000 to SGD 3,000 or more, depending on the ward type and hospital.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Outpatient services and treatments:</li>
  <li>Public healthcare: Diagnostic tests and procedures may have subsidized rates, varying depending on the specific service.</li>
  <li>Private healthcare: Diagnostic tests and procedures in private clinics or specialist centers can range from SGD 100 to SGD 500 or more, depending on the test or procedure.</li>
</ul>

<p>Medications:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Public healthcare: Medications in public hospitals are typically available at subsidized rates, with prices varying based on the specific medication.</li>
  <li>Private healthcare: Medication costs in private healthcare settings can vary significantly depending on the medication and the pharmacy. Branded or specialized medications may be more expensive.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="singapore-absolutely-crushed-the-pandemic">Singapore absolutely crushed the pandemic</h4>

<p>Singapore has been widely recognized for its effective management of the COVID-19 pandemic. The government implemented a comprehensive and proactive approach to control the spread of the virus and protect public health. Here are some key measures and strategies employed by Singapore:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Early Response and Preparedness: Singapore responded swiftly to the outbreak by establishing a multi-ministry task force and implementing a range of preventive measures even before the first local cases were reported. This included border controls, contact tracing, quarantine measures, and public communication campaigns.</li>
  <li>Robust Testing and Contact Tracing: Singapore implemented widespread testing to identify and isolate infected individuals. Contact tracing efforts were intensified through the use of technology, such as the + TraceTogether mobile app, which helped identify and notify close contacts of confirmed cases.</li>
  <li>Stringent Quarantine and Isolation Measures: Infected individuals and close contacts were required to undergo mandatory quarantine or isolation in dedicated facilities or at home. Strict enforcement and monitoring were in place to ensure compliance.</li>
  <li>Public Health Measures: Singapore implemented various public health measures such as mask-wearing, safe distancing, and regular hand hygiene. These measures were communicated to the public through extensive public education campaigns.</li>
  <li>Effective Healthcare System: Singapore’s healthcare system, with its strong infrastructure and capacity, played a crucial role in managing the pandemic. The government worked closely with healthcare institutions to increase testing capabilities, hospital capacity, and ensure sufficient resources for patient care.</li>
  <li>Clear Communication and Public Engagement: Regular updates and clear communication from government authorities helped to keep the public informed and educated about the evolving situation. Public engagement and adherence to guidelines were emphasized to foster a collective responsibility in managing the pandemic.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="given-the-healthcare-system-is-so-robust-how-much-are-doctors-being-paid">Given the healthcare system is so robust, how much are doctors being paid?</h4>

<p>You’ll be surprised with this one.</p>

<p>1st year doctor pay in USD</p>
<ul>
  <li>SG: $3400</li>
  <li>HK: $10K</li>
  <li>US: $5400</li>
</ul>

<p>Median gross monthly salary for Singapore fresh graduates is $3.1K USD. (source - Strait times). It baffles me how little these first year doctors earn. For context, a fresh non-tech grad at Google in the US earns $8000 working 40 hours a week. Singapore first year doctors work at least 60% more hours.</p>

<p>I personally know 1st year doctors who were thrown into COVID wards, and whilst there was overall fear, the resounding message was the government is in control. All that being said, they were awarded with medals (versus any sort of monetary reward) for their service. I understand doctors are here to serve the public but it’d be nice for them to be compensated.</p>

<h4 id="no-wonder-theres-a-shortage-on-doctors">No wonder there’s a shortage on doctors…</h4>

<p>What’s interesting now is that there’s a shortage of doctors. As of my knowledge cutoff in September 2021, Singapore has been experiencing a relative shortage of doctors in certain specialties and settings. While Singapore has a well-established healthcare system and a sufficient number of doctors overall, there are specific areas that face challenges in terms of doctor availability.</p>

<p>One area of concern is the demand for specialized medical professionals, such as oncologists, cardiologists, and psychiatrists, which has been growing due to an aging population and increased healthcare needs. Additionally, some rural or remote areas in Singapore may have difficulty attracting doctors, leading to a disparity in healthcare access.</p>

<p>To address this, the Singaporean government has implemented various initiatives to increase the supply of doctors. These efforts include expanding medical education capacity, attracting foreign doctors, and offering scholarships and incentives to encourage medical students to specialize in needed fields.
It’s important to note that the situation may have evolved since my last update, and it’s recommended to refer to recent reports and studies for the most accurate and up-to-date information on the current doctor shortage in Singapore. Please increase pay for public doctors.</p>

<p>The healthcare system in Singapore is undeniably a privilege. With its efficient, high-quality, and accessible healthcare services, supported by well-funded public hospitals, advanced medical technology, and government subsidies, Singaporeans are fortunate to have comprehensive healthcare coverage that is the envy of many nations. The ability to receive top-notch medical care without significant financial burden truly makes Singapore’s healthcare system a valuable privilege for its expats and citizens.</p>

<p>Comment in your thoughts. Subscribe now to see more content like this.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Healthcare" /><category term="hospitals" /><category term="cost of living" /><category term="Hong Kong" /><category term="Singapore" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The pandemic’s over. Wahoo! Singapore’s healthcare system, renowned for its efficiency, quality, and accessibility, was put under the spotlight during the past 3 years of COVID. This post explores the distinctions between private and public healthcare in Singapore, examining factors such as cost, accessibility, and quality of care. Additionally, it delves into the remuneration of doctors in Singapore, shedding light on their earning potential and the considerations surrounding their salaries. Oh, you’ll also find out about the best hospitals and where you can find them. By understanding the dynamics of Singapore’s healthcare landscape, we gain insights into the complex interplay between private and public sectors and the compensation structures that shape the medical profession in the country. We won’t be covering insurance in-depth in this post (especially cheap health insurance). We’ll save that for another time.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/supportsystems.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/supportsystems.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hong Kong versus Singapore: same food items, different taste</title><link href="/hk-versus-sg-food/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hong Kong versus Singapore: same food items, different taste" /><published>2023-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/hk-versus-sg-food</id><content type="html" xml:base="/hk-versus-sg-food/"><![CDATA[<p>When I first arrived in Singapore, I recall ordering barbecue pork rice at a hawker center, thinking it would taste like the same comforting dish I had in Hong Kong. However, after receiving my plate of food, I found the dish surprisingly different. The cha siu was thinly sliced versus thickly sliced, there was too much sauce and the sauce was too sweet and viscous. In fact, a barbeque pork rice in San Francisco drew a much closer comparison to that of Hong Kong’s. In today’s post, we’ll dissect some iconic differences between Hong Kong Chinese cuisine versus Singapore Chinese cuisine. For best comparison, we’ll use that of a Cha Chaan Teng / Maxim’s in Hong Kong versus that of a hawker center / coffee shop in Singapore so we can get closest to what the general population consumes on a day to day. Of course, the food items will be much more similar in an authentic higher end eatery in both countries, but that won’t be our focus for today. In case you missed my earlier post on the best <a href="https://fromhktosg.github.io/dimsum/">dim sum in Singapore</a>, check it out too.</p>

<h4 id="history-behind-hong-kong-versus-singapore-chinese-cuisine">History behind Hong Kong versus Singapore Chinese cuisine</h4>

<p>Chinese cuisine is renowned worldwide for its rich flavors, diverse ingredients, and culinary traditions that have evolved over centuries. Two prominent centers of Chinese culinary excellence are Hong Kong and Singapore. Both regions boast a vibrant and distinct Chinese food culture that reflects their unique historical, cultural, and geographical contexts.</p>

<p>Chinese immigrants began settling in Hong Kong during the early colonial period, bringing their culinary traditions with them. Hong Kong’s cuisine is heavily influenced by Cantonese culinary traditions, renowned for its finesse, subtle flavors, and emphasis on fresh ingredients. It stands out with its delicate cooking techniques, preserving the natural taste and texture of ingredients. The cuisine showcases a wide range of ingredients, including seafood, poultry, and exotic delicacies, creating a harmonious balance of flavors and textures. Light seasonings, such as soy sauce and fermented ingredients, enhance the natural flavors without overpowering them. Simply exquisite.</p>

<p>Chinese cuisine entered Singapore through a combination of historical factors, migration, and cultural exchanges. Chinese immigrants from various regions, such as Fujian, Guangdong, and Hainan, brought their culinary traditions when they settled in Singapore. Additionally, Singapore has developed its own blend of Chinese cuisine, infused with Malay, Indian, and Peranakan influences. Hence, the cuisine incorporates an additional array of herbs, spices, and sauces in their dishes.</p>

<h4 id="lets-start-off-with-seasoning-behind-the-two-cuisines">Let’s start off with seasoning behind the two cuisines</h4>

<p>When my parents visited Singapore two years back, they commented that ‘Singapore Chinese food is like Hong Kong Chinese food 25 years back. Oilier, saltier, heavier, bolder and more fragrant.’ Basically, more flavourful. A couple of things that I notice from hawker centers that may be surprising to Hong Kong visitors or expats -</p>

<ul>
  <li>Jalapenos - everybody asks for Jalapenos. These are green chilis that are pickled and sliced and go well with any noodle or rice based dish. I love the pickled jalapenos in Singapore as they add a burst of flavour to your meal</li>
  <li>Chili - everybody asks for Chili. By chili, we mean this as something like 豆瓣醬 without the fermented bean paste in. Think something similar to Lao gan ma without the additional crispiness. Singaporeans love their spice and chili adds an extra dimension to the dish. To be fair, this is something you’ll also find in Hong Kong Cha Chaan Tengs</li>
  <li>Gravy - aka more sauce. This can be curry if you’re eating a Hainan curry rice, or more 勾芡 (mostly chicken soup thickened by starch) on a rice noodle dish. Locals love their gravy and often ask for their dishes to be drenched in it. Not the most refined approach but hey, people are saucy. I much prefer a moderate amount instead of having food all slathered by sauce</li>
  <li>Soy sauce - it’s not uncommon to see soy sauce in a tub or little bag with diced up red chilis inside. Be it with soup noodles or rice, people want their soy sauce to their dish. It’s horrible for your sodium levels but the takeaway is Singaporeans love their bold flavours</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="same-same-but-different-food-dishes">Same same but different food dishes</h4>

<p>On to food dishes that share the same name but are executed differently.</p>

<p><u> Carrot cake (蘿蔔糕) <u></u></u></p>

<p>Hong Kong’ers are familiar with our usual rectangular block carrot cakes that we get at the usual dim sum establishments. Singapore carrot cake is different. Singapore carrot cake, or chai tow kway, differs from Hong Kong carrot cake in both preparation and flavor. Singapore carrot cake is stir-fried and made with cubes of radish cake, resulting in a soft yet slightly crispy texture. It is seasoned with a combination of sauces, including soy sauce and oyster sauce, and often spiced up with chili paste. On the other hand, Hong Kong carrot cake is steamed, sliced, and then pan-fried, offering a firmer texture and a subtle sweet and savory taste. The two versions showcase distinct cooking methods and flavor profiles, highlighting the diverse culinary variations within Chinese cuisine.</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/assets/images/carrotcake.jpg" alt="Carrotcake" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>Radish and flour cubes pressed and fried together with egg and scallions</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p><u> Barbeque pork (叉燒) <u></u></u></p>

<p>Let me be clear here. There’s some damn good cha siu in Singapore. I’ve talked about Jiang Nan Chun before for traditional cha siu, and Fook Kin is another one of my favourites for a more modern twist to cha siu. All that being said, if you visit a generic hawker store i.e. to a wanton chasiu noodle store, the cha siu you will get will differ from an ingredient selection standpoint and a technique standpoint.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Thinly sliced versus thickly sliced</li>
  <li>Leaner versus fattier</li>
  <li>Dyed artificially red</li>
  <li>No honey glaze</li>
  <li>Rice will be drenched with soy sauce</li>
</ul>

<p>Pretty much, the Singapore version is a more stripped down version of the Hong Kong iteration given slimmer margins of operations as well. If you are from Hong Kong, you will notice the difference versus a HK barbeque meat (燒臘) shop. The same applies to pork belly. A much thinner and leaner cut.</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/assets/images/chasiu.jpg" alt="Fookin" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>Fook Kin. The thick cut slices that you usually find in Hong Kongd</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p><u> Fried Rice (炒飯) <u></u></u></p>

<p>If we want to be more specific, let’s compare yangzhou fried rice (揚州炒飯). Yangzhou fried rice is a flavorful Chinese dish made with ingredients such as diced cha siu, shrimp, eggs, carrots, peas, and green onions. The ingredients are stir-fried together with soy sauce, oyster sauce, and seasonings. At least that’s what we’re familiar with in Hong Kong. In Singapore. In Singapore, a lot of the core ingredients are stripped away. Again, an adaptation to maintain margins given prices are so much cheaper in Singapore. You’re usually left with tiny pieces of cha siu, scallions and eggs. This is not a critique to the dish itself, but just a heads up of the differences. All that being said, wok hey is still there and taste is just fine.</p>

<p><u> Congee <u></u></u></p>

<p>Singapore congee, often known as “bubur,” features a rich and thick consistency with a wide range of ingredients. It is typically cooked with long-grain rice and a variety of meats, such as chicken, pork, or seafood. Singaporean-style congee incorporates various herbs, spices, and condiments to enhance the flavor, such as ginger, garlic, fried shallots, and soy sauce. The result is a flavorful and hearty porridge, often served with additional toppings like century eggs, sliced spring onions, and crispy fried dough fritters (you tiao). In contrast, Hong Kong congee, also known as “jook,” tends to have a smoother and silkier texture. It is traditionally made with short-grain rice, which creates a softer consistency. Hong Kong-style congee is typically simpler in terms of ingredients, often featuring just a few key components such as lean pork or fish. The focus is on the delicate and subtle flavors of the main ingredient, allowing the natural taste of the rice and meat to shine.</p>

<p>It fascinates me how these basic dishes all have their own local twists to it. They’re all delicious too.</p>

<h4 id="a-little-on-dining-know-hows">A little on dining know-hows</h4>

<p>Small little things on dining know-hows caught my attention after visiting hawker centers a few times.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Water / tea is not free: It usually is for a cha chaan teng but not in a coffee shop / hawker center in Singapore</li>
  <li>You have to busk: Saves labour cost especially in community eateries
Portion size flexibility: You have the ability to select your meal size. Small rice? $4. Medium rice? $4.5. Large rice? $5</li>
  <li>Plastic bags for drinks: Drinking coffee? Have it in a plastic bag. Obviously, it’s a plastic bag tailored for a drink and you stick a straw through it but it’s definitely old school</li>
  <li>Wet towels / tissue: Bring your own. If you dine in a coffee shop and they have a wet wipe, it’ll most likely cost you money</li>
</ul>

<p>I hope this post shows the little nuances between basic food items and dining experiences between Hong Kong and Singapore. What other differences have you noticed? Comment in your thoughts. Subscribe now to see more content like this.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Food" /><category term="hawker center" /><category term="restaurants" /><category term="surprise" /><category term="Hong Kong" /><category term="Singapore" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[When I first arrived in Singapore, I recall ordering barbecue pork rice at a hawker center, thinking it would taste like the same comforting dish I had in Hong Kong. However, after receiving my plate of food, I found the dish surprisingly different. The cha siu was thinly sliced versus thickly sliced, there was too much sauce and the sauce was too sweet and viscous. In fact, a barbeque pork rice in San Francisco drew a much closer comparison to that of Hong Kong’s. In today’s post, we’ll dissect some iconic differences between Hong Kong Chinese cuisine versus Singapore Chinese cuisine. For best comparison, we’ll use that of a Cha Chaan Teng / Maxim’s in Hong Kong versus that of a hawker center / coffee shop in Singapore so we can get closest to what the general population consumes on a day to day. Of course, the food items will be much more similar in an authentic higher end eatery in both countries, but that won’t be our focus for today. In case you missed my earlier post on the best dim sum in Singapore, check it out too.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/chasiu.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/chasiu.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Uncovering Singapore’s sports scene and facilities</title><link href="/sports-singapore/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Uncovering Singapore’s sports scene and facilities" /><published>2023-06-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-06-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/sports-singapore</id><content type="html" xml:base="/sports-singapore/"><![CDATA[<p>In an earlier article, we discussed the lack of things to do in Singapore. Well, one activity that many locals engage in is sports. Sports facilities in a nation showcase its commitment to promoting health and well-being, investing in infrastructure development, nurturing a sporting culture, and fostering community engagement and social inclusion. Today, we will delve into sports facilities in Singapore, exploring their purpose, accessibility for the public and private sectors, and the top venues available.</p>

<h4 id="singapores-commitment-to-sports">Singapore’s Commitment to Sports</h4>

<p>Singapore is truly committed to the sporting scene. Well-maintained and accessible facilities demonstrate a focus on physical fitness and recreational opportunities, while modern and diverse facilities signify investment in infrastructure and a vibrant sports scene. World-class facilities contribute to a nation’s competitive sporting achievements, while inclusive facilities promote community engagement and equal opportunities for participation. Collectively, sports facilities serve as visible symbols of a nation’s dedication to promoting an active lifestyle, supporting athletic development, and enhancing the overall quality of life for its citizens.</p>

<p>According to Sport Singapore’s “Sport Participation Survey 2019,” it was reported that 84% of Singapore residents aged 15 years and above participated in sports or physical exercise at least once a week. This indicates a significant number of Singaporeans actively involved in sports and recreational activities.</p>

<h4 id="singapores-public-sports-facilities">Singapore’s Public Sports Facilities</h4>

<p>With over 40 stadiums, more than 120 community sports centers, and a network of well-designed parks and recreational areas, the city offers a diverse range of spaces to accommodate different sports and cater to varying levels of expertise. However, despite having these sports facilities, Singapore has yet to make a significant impact on the world’s sports stage (aside from Joseph Schooling’s exceptional performance).
At the heart of Singapore’s sporting landscape stands the magnificent Singapore Sports Hub, a world-class integrated sports and entertainment complex. The hub’s centerpiece, the National Stadium, boasts a capacity of 55,000 and has hosted major international events, including the Southeast Asian Games and international football matches. It is here that we witness the unifying power of sport, as the cheers of fans reverberate through the stands, creating an electric atmosphere that ignites the spirit within.
While the Singapore Sports Hub showcases the pinnacle of sports infrastructure, it is the community sports centers that form the backbone of grassroots sporting engagement. With more than 120 centers strategically located across the island, these facilities offer a wide range of amenities, including basketball courts, swimming pools, futsal courts, football fields, tennis courts, and fitness gyms. They serve as the beating heart of local communities, providing accessible and inclusive spaces for everyone to participate in sports activities. From children honing their skills to seniors staying active, these centers embody the spirit of camaraderie and play.</p>

<p>In a bustling city where green spaces are treasured, parks and recreational areas offer a respite for those seeking a closer connection to nature while engaging in physical activities. Singapore’s meticulously designed parks, such as the iconic East Coast Park and the sprawling Bishan-Ang Mo Kio Park, provide an abundance of options for outdoor sports and recreation. Jogging trails, cycling paths, fitness corners, and skate parks are thoughtfully integrated, creating a haven for active living amidst the urban landscape. These green havens offer a unique blend of serenity and vitality, where individuals can exercise while immersing themselves in the beauty of nature.</p>

<h4 id="main-public-sports-facilities-in-singapore">Main public sports facilities in Singapore</h4>

<p>Here are some locations of the main public sports facilities in Singapore:</p>

<p>Tennis:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Kallang Tennis Centre: 52 Stadium Road, Singapore.</li>
  <li>Farrer Park Tennis Centre: 1 Rutland Road, Singapore.</li>
  <li>Heartbeat @ Bedok Tennis Centre: 11 Bedok North Street 1, Singapore.</li>
  <li>Yio Chu Kang Tennis Centre: 200 Ang Mo Kio Avenue 9, Singapore.</li>
</ul>

<p>Swimming:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Toa Payoh Swimming Complex: 301 Toa Payoh Lorong 6, Singapore.</li>
  <li>Jurong East Swimming Complex: 21 Jurong East Street 31, Singapore.</li>
  <li>Sengkang Swimming Complex: 57 Anchorvale Road, Singapore.</li>
  <li>Bishan Swimming Complex: 1 Bishan Street 14, Singapore.</li>
</ul>

<p>Athletics:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Choa Chu Kang Stadium: 1 Choa Chu Kang Street 53, Singapore.</li>
  <li>Bishan Stadium: 5 Bishan Street 14, Singapore.</li>
  <li>Queenstown Stadium: 473A Stirling Road, Singapore.</li>
  <li>Clementi Stadium: 31 West Coast Walk, Singapore.</li>
</ul>

<p>Basketball:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Our Tampines Hub: 1 Tampines Walk, Singapore.</li>
  <li>Heartbeat @ Bedok: 11 Bedok North Street 1, Singapore.</li>
  <li>Yio Chu Kang Sports Centre: 200 Ang Mo Kio Avenue 9, Singapore.</li>
  <li>Jurong East Sports Centre: 21 Jurong East Street 31, Singapore.</li>
</ul>

<p>Badminton:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Yio Chu Kang Sports Centre: 200 Ang Mo Kio Avenue 9, Singapore.</li>
  <li>Jurong East Sports Centre: 21 Jurong East Street 31, Singapore.</li>
  <li>Heartbeat @ Bedok: 11 Bedok North Street 1, Singapore.</li>
  <li>Bishan Sports Centre: 5 Bishan Street 14, Singapore.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="sports-facilities-in-condo">Sports facilities in condo</h4>

<p>A big reason why people live in condos is because of the so called ‘amenities’. This generally breaks down to a pool, a gym and if you’re lucky, a tennis court. Sports facilities in condominiums have become increasingly popular, offering residents the convenience of accessing recreational activities right at their doorstep. I love my condo’s pool, especially in the hot Singapore weather.</p>

<p>In the older condos that are larger, for example Mandarin Gardens, you’d find a larger range of sports facilities, for example a standard 25m pool, snooker tables, squash and table tennis courts and even a Mahjong room (we classify this as a sport too).</p>

<p>The presence of sports facilities in condominiums adds value to the overall living experience.</p>

<h4 id="what-about-country-clubs">What about country clubs…</h4>

<p>Singapore’s country clubs boast an impressive array of sports facilities, catering to a wide range of athletic interests. From golf courses designed by renowned architects to world-class tennis courts and state-of-the-art swimming pools, these clubs leave no stone unturned when it comes to sporting amenities. Additionally, you can find well-equipped fitness centers, squash courts, badminton courts, and even bowling alleys. Whether you’re a golf enthusiast, a tennis aficionado, or simply seeking a great workout, Singapore’s country clubs offer top-notch facilities to elevate your sports experience. Shit’s expensive but if it fits your lifestyle, why not? We’ll cover this in more detail another time.</p>

<p>In conclusion, Singapore offers a wide range of public sports facilities that cater to various sports and recreational activities. These facilities are strategically located throughout the country, providing accessible spaces for residents and visitors to engage in physical fitness, competitive sports, and leisurely pursuits. The well-maintained facilities reflect Singapore’s commitment to promoting an active lifestyle, nurturing sporting talents, and fostering a vibrant sports culture. With state-of-the-art stadiums, swimming complexes, sports halls, and outdoor spaces, Singapore provides ample opportunities for individuals to pursue their athletic passions, stay fit, and enjoy the benefits of sports and recreation.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Sports" /><category term="Country club" /><category term="facilities" /><category term="Hong Kong" /><category term="Singapore" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In an earlier article, we discussed the lack of things to do in Singapore. Well, one activity that many locals engage in is sports. Sports facilities in a nation showcase its commitment to promoting health and well-being, investing in infrastructure development, nurturing a sporting culture, and fostering community engagement and social inclusion. Today, we will delve into sports facilities in Singapore, exploring their purpose, accessibility for the public and private sectors, and the top venues available.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/sports.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/sports.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">2023 dating guide: Finding love in Singapore</title><link href="/Dating-singapore/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 dating guide: Finding love in Singapore" /><published>2023-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/Dating-singapore</id><content type="html" xml:base="/Dating-singapore/"><![CDATA[<p>A close expat friend of mine found herself caught in the twists and turns of the challenging Singapore dating scene. Despite her best efforts, meaningful connections seemed to elude her. The usual reasons creep in. ‘The best is already taken’, ‘It’s me, not you’, ‘Singapore’s too small to date’. Each disappointment weighed heavily on her heart. Frankly speaking, dating in Singapore is not easy and this is just one of few cases I’m aware of. Today, we’ll examine dating in Singapore including comparisons versus Hong Kong, casual dating and societal expectations. I’d preface - I’m no expert and nor am I experienced in this dating space. Let’s get started.</p>

<p>Hong Kong and Singapore, two dynamic and cosmopolitan cities in Asia, offer unique dating experiences shaped by similar societal norms and cultural backgrounds. However, you don’t hear people complaining that ‘HK is boring’ when it comes to dating. Why’s that the case?</p>

<p><u> Comparing both countries - <u></u></u></p>
<ul>
  <li>Cultural Background: Singapore is a multicultural society with influences from Chinese, Malay, Indian, and Western cultures. Hong Kong has a predominantly Chinese cultural background with Western influences. It’s much easier to find a mainland Chinese person to date in Hong Kong versus Singapore, whilst it’s much easier to find a Malay to date in Singapore versus Hong Kong. Both countries have expats so that’s one similarity.</li>
  <li>Casual dating is more common in Hong Kong: Because of the BTO housing system in Singapore, Singaporeans tend to get married earlier than Hong Kongers. This not only reduces the dating population in Singapore, but also means that dating is a little more serious. The exception to this is generally expats alongside a growing number of young adults.</li>
  <li>Work-Life Balance: Hong Kong is known for its fast-paced and competitive work environment, which can make it challenging to find time for dating. In Singapore, work-life balance is also valued, but the pace of life may be slightly more relaxed compared to Hong Kong.</li>
  <li>More fish in the ocean in Hong Kong: Perhaps the most important reason. Larger population, easier to date around</li>
  <li>Party scenes: LKF, Wan Chai, TST, speakeasies in HK. Clarke quay, boat quay in Singapore. The magnitude is just different and the party DNA is a lot wilder in HK.</li>
</ul>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/assets/images/W.jpg" alt="W" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>W Hotel Singapore - a signature party spot at night</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<h4 id="a-gross-summarization-of-the-dating-scene-in-singapore">A gross summarization of the dating scene in Singapore</h4>

<p>In summary - dating apps, organic and Zouk. That’s a gross summarization. University is a big one where people meet their +1s. More on the dating apps later. Do people hook up? Yes. However, I’ve noticed that discussions and public displays of affection are generally not common due to conservative values.</p>

<h4 id="dating-in-singapore-is-difficult-though">Dating in Singapore is difficult though</h4>

<p>In 2021’s marriage and parenthood survey data, 50% were not currently dating. 38% of those who were not currently dating had never dated before (Annex B, Chart 8). Among those not currently dating, top reasons cited were having a limited social circle (58%), not having many opportunities to meet potential partners (57%), and their preference to leave dating to chance (48%).</p>

<p>Other factors -</p>
<ul>
  <li>Competitive Environment: Singapore is known for its highly competitive society, where individuals often prioritize education, career, and financial stability. As a result, people may have limited time and energy for dating, making it challenging to establish and maintain romantic relationships.</li>
  <li>High Cost of Living: Singapore has a relatively high cost of living, which can impact dating experiences. Planning and affording activities such as dinners, movies, or outings can be expensive, particularly for individuals on a tight budget</li>
  <li>Where do you have sex?: Most unmarried Singaporeans live with their parents. Unless the parents are progressive or are out of home, you’d have to find a different location to have sex. Staycations are popular here for obvious reasons</li>
  <li>Cultural Pressures and Expectations: Singaporean society places importance on family values and can have traditional expectations regarding relationships. This can create pressure to settle down at a certain age or follow societal norms, which can be challenging for those who prefer alternative dating styles or have unconventional preferences.</li>
  <li>Limited Social Circles: Singapore’s small geographic size and fast-paced lifestyle can sometimes limit opportunities for meeting new people outside of established social circles. As a result, individuals may find it more challenging to expand their social networks and encounter potential dating partners.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="societal-pressures-of-getting-married">Societal pressures of getting married</h4>

<p>Related to dating difficulties is the pressure to get married</p>

<p>Expectation 1: Timely Marriage:
One prevailing societal expectation in Singapore is to get married at a “timely” age, often seen as late 20s to early 30s. Family, friends, and acquaintances may inquire about one’s marital status, placing pressure on individuals to conform to this timeline. This expectation can be rooted in traditional values and a desire to maintain stability and continuation of family lineage. We’re slowly heading away from this as Singapore society gets more progressive, but it’ll take some time.</p>

<p>Reality 1: Shifting Priorities:
The reality is that individuals today prioritize personal growth, education, and career advancement. They may choose to delay marriage to establish financial stability or pursue personal goals. This shift challenges the traditional notion of timely marriage and emphasizes the importance of individual agency and fulfillment. Wokege.</p>

<p>Expectation 2: Finding a Suitable Partner
Singaporean society places importance on finding a “suitable” partner, often defined by factors such as education, occupation, and socio-economic status. This expectation can create pressure to meet societal standards, leading to a perception of limited options or the fear of being judged for unconventional choices.</p>

<p>Reality 2: Diverse Definitions of Compatibility
The reality is that compatibility cannot be reduced to a checklist of superficial criteria. Individuals today seek partners who share similar values, aspirations, and emotional compatibility. This broader perspective challenges societal expectations, allowing for more diverse and meaningful connections beyond external attributes.</p>

<p>Expectation 3: Marriage as a Life Milestone
Marriage is often seen as a significant life milestone in Singaporean society, symbolizing adulthood, stability, and success. The pressure to attain this milestone can stem from familial and social expectations, creating a sense of urgency to conform and avoid societal judgment.</p>

<p>Reality 3: Multiple Pathways to Fulfillment:
The reality is that marriage is not the only path to fulfillment. Many individuals prioritize personal growth, career achievements, and other life experiences. They challenge the notion that marriage is a prerequisite for happiness, focusing on individual goals and relationships beyond the traditional scope.</p>

<p>Impact: Emotional and Mental Well-being:
The societal pressures surrounding marriage in Singapore can have a significant impact on individuals’ emotional and mental well-being. Constant inquiries, comparisons, and societal judgments can lead to anxiety, self-doubt, and feelings of inadequacy. It is crucial to recognize the emotional toll and foster a supportive environment that respects diverse choices.</p>

<p>The discourse on societal pressures of getting married in Singapore reveals the clash between expectations and the realities faced by individuals. By acknowledging the shifting priorities, diverse definitions of compatibility, and multiple pathways to fulfillment, Singaporean society can foster a more inclusive and supportive environment. Empowering individuals to make choices aligned with their own aspirations and timelines will lead to a more progressive and understanding society.</p>

<h4 id="government-playing-a-part-with-the-singapore-dating-scene">Government playing a part with the Singapore dating scene</h4>

<p>The Singapore government recognizes the importance of social relationships and has taken various initiatives to encourage dating and foster a conducive environment for individuals to meet and form connections. Here are some ways the Singapore government promotes dating:
Social Development Network (SDN): The Social Development Network is a government agency established to promote social interaction and marriage within Singapore. SDN organizes events and activities, such as speed dating sessions, social mixers, and relationship workshops, to provide opportunities for singles to meet and connect.
Funding and Support for Dating Events: The government provides funding and support for organizations that organize dating events and activities. This assistance helps create a diverse range of opportunities for singles to engage in social activities, attend matchmaking events, and participate in relationship-building programs.
Online Dating Platforms: The government encourages the use of online dating platforms by partnering with reputable dating websites. These platforms provide a convenient and accessible way for singles to connect and find potential partners. The government promotes the use of safe and secure online platforms, emphasizing the importance of personal safety and responsible online behavior.
Housing Policies: The government’s housing policies also play a role in encouraging dating and marriage. The Housing and Development Board (HDB) offers various housing schemes and grants that incentivize young adults to settle down and form families. These policies aim to provide affordable housing options for couples and support the institution of marriage.
Public Awareness Campaigns: The government conducts public awareness campaigns to promote dating and healthy relationships. These campaigns focus on educating individuals about the importance of social interaction, communication skills, and building meaningful connections. They also aim to break down stereotypes and encourage individuals to be more open-minded in their dating preferences.</p>

<h4 id="do-dating-apps-work-in-singapore">Do dating apps work in Singapore?</h4>

<p>Yes and no. All the dating apps are in town so let’s break them down -
Tinder - the OG of dating apps. You swipe right if you like someone and left if you’re not feeling it. It’s known for casual flings and hook-ups globally. No difference in Singapore
Bumble - Ladies take the lead here. Once you match, the ladies gotta make the first move within 24 hours. Good luck to all you men
Coffee Meets Bagel - They send you a limited number of matches (aka “bagels”) every day. Quality over quantity, they say. It’s for those who want something more meaningful
OkCupid - all about compatibility. They’ve got this fancy algorithm that matches you based on your preferences and values. Plus, you can answer a bunch of questions to improve your match quality
Paktor - Popular in Southeast Asia, including Singapore. They’ve got cool features like virtual gifting and group chats. It’s got a diverse user base and caters to different preference
Happn - It’s all about those chance encounters. Happn matches you with people you’ve crossed paths with in real life. It’s perfect for those who believe in serendipity.</p>

<p>Remember, these apps might change over time, so it’s good to give a few a try and see which one suits your dating style and goals. I know multiple friends who met their now-wife through dating apps. It’s possible. One thing I have to call out is for both Hong Kong and Singapore, my expat friends all say they have an advantage in casual dating over the local population. Call it yellow fever or asian girls liking expat guys, but this is an existing phenomenon.</p>

<p>What about matchmaking? It’s a well-established practice but not the most common.</p>

<h4 id="popular-date-spots-in-singapore">Popular date spots in Singapore</h4>

<p>It really depends what kind of couple you are but here’s a general list of the evergreen generic ones. Personally, I’d love to check Time Out and Vogue for ‘what to do this weekend in Singapore’ as they have curated lists of events happening in town. That’s a much better approach</p>

<ul>
  <li>Hiking at MacRitchie Reservoir: Explore the lush greenery and scenic trails around the reservoir. It’s a great way to enjoy nature together and have a peaceful and active date.</li>
  <li>Katong and Joo Chiat: Take a stroll through these charming neighborhoods known for their rich heritage, colorful Peranakan shophouses, and delicious local food. It’s a hidden gem for an authentic and cultural experience. East coast adventures.</li>
  <li>Kranji Countryside: Escape the city and visit the tranquil Kranji countryside. Explore the farms, go on a nature walk, or enjoy a cozy meal at one of the farm-to-table restaurants. It’s a unique and serene setting for a date. I love a trip to Bollywood veggies</li>
  <li>The Projector: Watch an indie or classic film at this independent cinema located in an old-school building. It’s a cozy and nostalgic experience that movie lovers would appreciate.</li>
  <li>Art Jamming or pottery at a Studio: Get creative together and unleash your artistic side at an art jamming studio. It’s a fun and interactive date where you can paint and express yourselves.</li>
  <li>Gardens by the Bay: Take a romantic stroll through the stunning gardens and Supertree Grove. Don’t miss the Flower Dome and Cloud Forest conservatories.</li>
  <li>Sentosa Island: Relax on the beautiful beaches, visit Universal Studios Singapore, or try thrilling water sports. One of my favourite places to kick it</li>
  <li>Singapore Botanic Gardens: Explore the lush greenery, have a picnic by the Swan Lake, or visit the National Orchid Garden.</li>
  <li>Shopping: Depends if you want to splurge but shopping at Ion / MBS can’t really go wrong.</li>
</ul>

<p><u> Summing it up <u></u></u></p>

<p>In this fast-paced dance of love, time is precious, but commitment is held dear. Singapore’s dating scene is a whirlwind of efficiency and heartfelt connections, where couples envision a future hand-in-hand. Would I prefer dating in Hong Kong or dating in Singapore? Obviously the former. But it’s not that bad in Singapore.</p>

<p>What dating experiences do you have in Singapore? Comment in your thoughts. Subscribe now to see more content like this.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Dating" /><category term="Relationships" /><category term="Marriage" /><category term="Hong Kong" /><category term="Singapore" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A close expat friend of mine found herself caught in the twists and turns of the challenging Singapore dating scene. Despite her best efforts, meaningful connections seemed to elude her. The usual reasons creep in. ‘The best is already taken’, ‘It’s me, not you’, ‘Singapore’s too small to date’. Each disappointment weighed heavily on her heart. Frankly speaking, dating in Singapore is not easy and this is just one of few cases I’m aware of. Today, we’ll examine dating in Singapore including comparisons versus Hong Kong, casual dating and societal expectations. I’d preface - I’m no expert and nor am I experienced in this dating space. Let’s get started.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/W.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/W.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Guide to the best shopping malls in Singapore</title><link href="/shopping-in-singapore/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Guide to the best shopping malls in Singapore" /><published>2023-06-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-06-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/shopping-in-singapore</id><content type="html" xml:base="/shopping-in-singapore/"><![CDATA[<p>Shopping malls have become an integral part of Singapore’s urban landscape, with their ubiquitous presence contributing significantly to the city’s social, economic, and cultural fabric. These vast complexes have become more than mere retail destinations, but rather serve as multifaceted hubs of activity where Singaporeans can meet, shop, dine, and socialize. In this post we will delve into the critical role that shopping malls play, the popular malls in town and overall shopping strategy in Singapore.</p>

<h4 id="why-are-shopping-malls-everywhere-in-singapore">Why are shopping malls everywhere in Singapore</h4>

<p>Every MRT stop has a shopping mall. Almost every. Why is that the case?</p>

<p>One of the reasons why many MRT stations in Singapore have shopping malls is because of the government’s urban planning strategy. The government has been actively promoting the concept of “integrated developments” where residential, commercial, and transportation facilities are located in close proximity to each other. This strategy aims to promote convenience and accessibility for residents and visitors to Singapore.</p>

<p>In the case of MRT stations, the idea is to create a seamless and convenient shopping experience for commuters. By having shopping malls located directly adjacent to MRT stations, commuters can easily access these malls without having to walk long distances or take additional transportation. This also provides an opportunity for businesses to benefit from the high traffic flow of commuters passing through the MRT stations.</p>

<p>Additionally, the government also aims to encourage the development of commercial spaces within the city to increase employment opportunities and boost the economy. Having shopping malls connected to MRT stations can attract more visitors, further increasing the commercial value of these spaces. This is not rocket science given a similar model exists in JP and HK.</p>

<h4 id="the-role-of-shopping-malls-in-singapore">The role of shopping malls in Singapore</h4>

<p>Shopping malls have emerged as essential spaces for social interaction, providing a comfortable and safe environment for people to connect with friends and family. Malls offer a myriad of entertainment options, including cinemas, game arcades, and food courts, making them an ideal location for people to spend their leisure time. The presence of social amenities such as restrooms, nursing rooms, and free Wi-Fi makes shopping malls an attractive location for people from all walks of life to come together and interact.</p>

<p>In fact, shopping malls are crucial drivers of Singapore’s economy, offering a wide range of job opportunities in the retail and non-retail sectors. Singapore’s malls attract a significant number of tourists who come to experience the city’s vibrant shopping scene, contributing to Singapore’s economy through their expenditure on retail, food, and accommodation. Shopping malls also play an essential role in creating a thriving retail industry that generates jobs and income for Singaporeans.</p>

<p>Shopping malls play a critical role in Singapore’s urban planning and development, forming part of larger integrated developments that include residential, office, and hotel components. These developments create a vibrant and diverse environment that provides a holistic experience for residents, workers, and visitors alike. They also contribute to the value of the surrounding properties, leading to a multiplier effect on the overall growth of the local economy. And free aircon is great.</p>

<h4 id="best-shopping-malls-in-singapore">Best shopping malls in Singapore</h4>

<p>Criteria of assessment:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Volume of shops</li>
  <li>Major brands available</li>
  <li>Food options</li>
  <li>Proximity to city center</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="in-order-of-best-shopping-experience-1--best">In order of best shopping experience (1 = best)</h4>

<ol>
  <li>Ion Orchard - Located on <a href="https://fromhktosg.github.io/neighbourhood/">Orchard Road</a>, this high-end mall features luxury brands and high street fashion. Some call it Orchard Ion</li>
  <li>Marina Bay Sands - This iconic mall boasts luxury brands, high-end restaurants, and stunning views of the Marina Bay</li>
  <li>Ngee Ann City / Takashimaya - Another popular shopping destination on Orchard Road, Takashimaya offers a range of products, from luxury brands to electronics and beauty products</li>
  <li>313@Somerset - This mall offers a range of international and local brands, as well as a wide range of dining options</li>
  <li>VivoCity - One of the largest shopping malls in Singapore, VivoCity features a wide range of shops, restaurants, and entertainment options</li>
  <li>Suntec City - Located in the heart of the city, Suntec City offers a range of retail and entertainment options, as well as convention and exhibition facilities</li>
  <li>Jewel Changi Airport - This world-class mall features a stunning indoor waterfall, a vast array of shopping and dining options, and entertainment attraction</li>
  <li>IMM - popular destination for outlet shopping and home furnishing, located in the west of Singapore</li>
</ol>

<p>Other malls near the Heartlands include City Square mall, Queensway Shopping Center (great for sports items) and Raffles City Shopping Center.</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/assets/images/fareast.jpg" alt="Fareastplaza" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>Far East Plaza in Orchard</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<h4 id="loyalty-programs">Loyalty programs</h4>

<p>An explosion of shopping mall loyalty programs have cropped up in the past few years. Along with loyalty points, malls have credit card partnerships that open up to further discounts. Here are a couple of examples -</p>
<ul>
  <li>CapitaStar - offered by CapitaLand Malls, including malls such as Plaza Singapura, Bugis Junction, and Raffles City. American Express Platinum Credit Card offers 10X Membership Rewards points at participating malls under CapitaLand Malls</li>
  <li>Frasers Rewards - offered by Frasers Property Malls, including malls such as The Centrepoint, Causeway Point, and Northpoint City. Citi Rewards Card offers 4 miles per S$1 spent</li>
  <li>Changi Rewards - offered by Jewel Changi Airport and participating retailers in Changi Airport.</li>
  <li>Ion+ Rewards - offered by Ion Orchard, providing members with exclusive access to events, promotions, and rewards at the mall. Earn ION⁺ Points for every block of $100 same-day spend. 25 ION points convert to $10 ecapitavoucher. That means you get $10 back for $2500 of spend - pretty rough.</li>
  <li>MBS Rewards - offered by Marina Bay Sands, providing members with exclusive discounts and privileges at the mall’s shops, restaurants, and attractions. Each $1.2 Reward Dollar earned can be redeemed for $1 worth of goods and services at participating partners</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="my-two-cents-of-shopping-in-singapore-versus-in-hk">My two cents of shopping in Singapore versus in HK</h4>

<p>We’re referring to shopping for goods vs groceries here.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Singapore is more expensive due to sales tax. Take Uniqlo in SG vs HK. Hong Kong is cheaper. Same with the US</li>
  <li>All the essential brands are there. For luxury, you’ll be able to get most of the latest items although they do run out quick</li>
  <li>There’s a lot less foot traffic versus Hong Kong. This makes shopping more comfortable and relaxing. This might change when tourists flood back in both countries</li>
  <li>Consistent quality of mid-tier shopping malls. Few large scale luxury malls exist, but for all the mid-tier ones, they are of consistent quality across the nation. Food options are similar and store options are similar</li>
  <li>Limited number of boutiques and thrifts</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<p>My recommendation - only buy essentials or things that really catch your eye in Singapore. Buy luxury abroad for tax refund and buy staples and boutiques abroad for a wider selection at a lower price. If you really have to buy, I’d recommend going to MBS as the loyalty program is more friendly.  All that being said, Singapore’s shopping malls are some of the best in the world. With plenty of aircon to shelter from heat and a plethora of dining and shops options, shopping malls have become a haven and pastime for locals. I love my malls and so should you.</p>

<p>Let me know what’s your favourite mall. Subscribe now to see more content like this.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Shopping" /><category term="Hong Kong" /><category term="Malls" /><category term="Loyalty program" /><category term="Singapore" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shopping malls have become an integral part of Singapore’s urban landscape, with their ubiquitous presence contributing significantly to the city’s social, economic, and cultural fabric. These vast complexes have become more than mere retail destinations, but rather serve as multifaceted hubs of activity where Singaporeans can meet, shop, dine, and socialize. In this post we will delve into the critical role that shopping malls play, the popular malls in town and overall shopping strategy in Singapore.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/ion.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/ion.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>