<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2024-02-02T08:50:02+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">From HK to SG</title><entry><title type="html">Ultimate 5-day trip to Hong Kong from Singapore</title><link href="/singapore-best-sushi/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ultimate 5-day trip to Hong Kong from Singapore" /><published>2024-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-best-sushi</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-best-sushi/"><![CDATA[<p>Embark on an unforgettable journey through the bustling streets and vibrant neighborhoods of Hong Kong, a perennial favorite among Singaporeans for its captivating allure. Our ultimate 5-day travel guide invites you to discover the harmonious blend of tradition and modernity in this enchanting city where East meets West. Join us as we navigate the iconic landmarks, savor culinary delights, and dive into the cultural tapestry that defines Hong Kong. Whether you’re a history enthusiast, a foodie, or a thrill-seeker, our meticulously crafted itinerary promises an immersive experience, uncovering hidden gems and must-visit spots. Get ready to explore Hong Kong like never before!</p>

<h4 id="getting-to-hong-kong">Getting to Hong Kong</h4>

<p>Traveling from Singapore to Hong Kong offers various options, ensuring a convenient and enjoyable journey. Here are some of the best ways and flights to get from Singapore to Hong Kong:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Direct Flights: Direct flights from Singapore Changi Airport (SIN) to Hong Kong International Airport (HKG) are the most time-efficient option. Singapore Airlines and Cathay Pacific, renowned for their service, operate direct flights, providing comfort and a shorter travel time. Flight Duration: Direct flights typically take around 4 hours, making it a quick and convenient journey.</li>
  <li>Budget Airlines: Consider budget airlines like Scoot or AirAsia for more affordable options. Although these flights might have layovers, they can be a cost-effective choice.</li>
  <li>Connecting Flights: Connecting flights with layovers in other Asian cities may offer flexibility in terms of schedules and prices. Common layover cities include Kuala Lumpur, Bangkok, or Manila.</li>
</ul>

<p>Before booking, consider factors such as your budget, travel preferences, and schedule flexibility. Always check travel restrictions, visa requirements, and health protocols, especially in light of any ongoing global situations. To be honest, a direct flight should be between $350-500 SGD.</p>

<h4 id="getting-around-hk">Getting around HK</h4>

<p>Navigating Hong Kong is a breeze thanks to its efficient and well-connected public transportation system. Here are the best ways to get around in Hong Kong:</p>
<ol>
  <li>MTR (Mass Transit Railway): The MTR is the backbone of Hong Kong’s public transportation, covering the majority of the city. It’s fast, reliable, and connects key areas, making it an ideal choice for both locals and tourists.</li>
  <li>Buses: Hong Kong has an extensive bus network, offering routes that cover almost every corner of the city. Buses are a cost-effective way to explore areas not directly served by the MTR.</li>
  <li>Trams: Hong Kong’s iconic double-decker trams are a charming and leisurely way to see the city. They operate on Hong Kong Island and provide a unique perspective of the streets.</li>
  <li>Ferries: With its numerous islands, Hong Kong offers ferry services that provide scenic views of the skyline. Ferries connect Central to outlying islands like Lantau, Cheung Chau, and Lamma.</li>
  <li>Taxis: Taxis are readily available, especially in urban areas. They are a convenient option for reaching destinations not directly accessible by public transportation.</li>
  <li>Minibuses: Minibuses operate on fixed routes and are a flexible mode of transportation. They can take you to destinations that might not be easily reachable by larger buses.</li>
  <li>Octopus Card: The Octopus Card is a smart payment card that can be used on all forms of public transportation. It offers a cashless and convenient way to pay for MTR, buses, trams, and even purchases at various shops.</li>
  <li>Walk and Explore: Hong Kong is a pedestrian-friendly city, especially in areas like Central, Tsim Sha Tsui, and Causeway Bay.
Walking allows you to immerse yourself in the vibrant street life and discover hidden gems.</li>
</ol>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/assets/images/old.jpg" alt="old" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>Charming architecture of the old Hong Kong</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<h4 id="cost-of-travel">Cost of travel</h4>

<p>The costs of traveling around Hong Kong can vary based on your preferred mode of transportation, the duration of your stay, and your activity choices. Here’s a breakdown of some typical expenses:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Public Transportation: MTR (Mass Transit Railway): Fares depend on the distance traveled, ranging from HKD 4 to HKD 55. Buses: Bus fares start at around HKD 4, with additional charges for longer distances or specific routes.</li>
  <li>Taxis: Flagfall: Around HKD 24, with additional charges for distance traveled. Airport to Central: Approximately HKD 300.</li>
  <li>Ferries: Star Ferry: HKD 2.7 to HKD 3.7 per adult ticket. Outlying Islands: Ferry fares vary; for example, the Lantau Island ferry can cost around HKD 35.</li>
  <li>Trams: Tram rides: A flat fare of HKD 2.6 per adult, regardless of the distance traveled.</li>
  <li>Minibuses: Minibus fares: Typically around HKD 8-10, but can vary.</li>
  <li>Octopus Card: The Octopus Card is a convenient way to pay for public transportation and some purchases. The initial cost is HKD 150, inclusive of a HKD 50 deposit and HKD 100 usable value.</li>
  <li>Attractions: Peak Tram: Around HKD 37 for a one-way adult ticket. Ngong Ping 360: Prices vary based on the type of ticket, ranging from HKD 135 to HKD 235. Disneyland: Ticket prices start at around HKD 639 for adults.</li>
  <li>Food: Local Eateries: Meals at local eateries can range from HKD 30 to HKD 100 per person. Mid-Range Restaurants: Expect to spend HKD 200 to HKD 500 per person. Fine Dining: Fine dining can range from HKD 500 to HKD 1,500 or more per person.</li>
  <li>Accommodation:
    <ul>
      <li>Budget Hotels: Starting from HKD 400 per night.</li>
      <li>Mid-Range Hotels: Starting from HKD 800 per night.</li>
      <li>Luxury Hotels: Starting from HKD 1,500 per night.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Miscellaneous: Shopping, Entertainment, and Miscellaneous Expenses: Varies based on personal preferences and activities.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="best-time-to-visit-hong-kong">Best time to visit Hong Kong</h4>

<p>The best time to visit Hong Kong depends on your preferences and the type of experience you’re seeking. The great thing is that Hong Kong is fantastic to visit across all seasons (though it’s a tad hot in the summer). Here are some considerations for different seasons:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Autumn (September to November): Weather: Autumn is one of the most pleasant times to visit, with mild temperatures and lower humidity. Average temperatures range from 20°C to 28°C (68°F to 82°F). Activities: Enjoy outdoor activities, festivals, and sightseeing without the discomfort of high heat.</li>
  <li>Winter (December to February): Weather: Hong Kong experiences a mild winter, with temperatures ranging from 12°C to 20°C (54°F to 68°F). Activities: While it’s the coolest time, it’s still comfortable for exploring. Winter is also a festive season with Christmas and Chinese New Year celebrations.</li>
  <li>Spring (March to May): Weather: Spring brings warmer temperatures, ranging from 17°C to 26°C (63°F to 79°F). Activities: Enjoy blooming flowers, outdoor events, and cultural festivals. It’s a good time for hiking and exploring nature.</li>
  <li>Summer (June to August): Weather: Hong Kong’s summer is hot and humid, with temperatures ranging from 26°C to 31°C (79°F to 88°F). Activities: While summer brings typhoons and occasional heavy rainfall, it’s also a vibrant season with events, festivals, and lively atmosphere. Beach activities are popular during this time.</li>
</ul>

<p>Considerations during seasonal periods:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Crowds: Hong Kong can be crowded during festivals and holidays, so plan accordingly.</li>
  <li>Budget: Prices for accommodation and flights may vary, with high demand during peak seasons.</li>
  <li>Events: Check the calendar for major events, such as the Hong Kong Arts Festival, Chinese New Year, and the Dragon Boat Festival.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="best-places-to-stay-in-hong-kong">Best places to stay in Hong Kong</h4>

<p>Here are hotel recommendations for the specified locations in Hong Kong:</p>

<p><u>Central<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>The Murray, Hong Kong: A luxury hotel with contemporary design and excellent amenities.</li>
  <li>Four Seasons Hotel Hong Kong: Known for its stunning harbor views and world-class service.</li>
  <li>The Landmark Mandarin Oriental: Offers a blend of elegance and modern luxury.</li>
  <li>Island Shangri-La: Iconic luxury hotel with spacious rooms and panoramic views.</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Tsim Sha Tsui (TST)<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>The Peninsula Hong Kong: An iconic hotel offering a blend of colonial elegance and modern luxury.</li>
  <li>K11 ARTUS: A boutique hotel with artistic flair and personalized service.</li>
  <li>InterContinental Hong Kong: Known for its harborfront location and luxurious accommodations.</li>
  <li>The Langham, Hong Kong: A five-star hotel with a touch of European elegance.</li>
</ul>

<p><u> Mong Kok<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>Cordis, Hong Kong: Located in the heart of Mong Kok, it offers a mix of luxury and convenience.</li>
  <li>The Olympian Hong Kong: A boutique hotel with spacious rooms and a tranquil atmosphere.</li>
  <li>Royal Plaza Hotel: Combines modern comforts with easy access to shopping and entertainment.</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Causeway Bay<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>Lanson Place Hotel: A stylish boutique hotel in the heart of Causeway Bay.</li>
  <li>Regal Hongkong Hotel: Offers a central location with easy access to shopping and dining.</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Admiralty<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>JW Marriott Hotel Hong Kong: Luxury hotel with a central location and elegant design.</li>
  <li>The Upper House: A sophisticated hotel offering panoramic views and contemporary luxury.</li>
  <li>Rosewood Hong Kong: A prestigious hotel offering luxurious accommodations, stunning harbor views, and top-notch facilities. Known for its sophisticated design and exceptional service.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="the-ultimate-5-day-itinerary">The ultimate 5 day itinerary</h4>

<h5 id="day-1-tsim-sha-tsui-extravaganza">Day 1: Tsim Sha Tsui Extravaganza</h5>
<ul>
  <li>Morning: Start your day with shopping in Tsim Sha Tsui’s bustling markets and luxury malls. Enjoy a sumptuous dim sum brunch.</li>
  <li>Afternoon: Visit the iconic Victoria Harbour for a stunning view and take a leisurely stroll along the Tsim Sha Tsui Promenade.</li>
  <li>Evening: Explore Avenue of Stars, indulge in some more shopping, and have a delightful dinner at one of the harbor-view restaurants.</li>
</ul>

<h5 id="day-2-ngong-ping-adventure">Day 2: Ngong Ping Adventure</h5>
<ul>
  <li>Morning: Head to Ngong Ping to witness the majestic Tian Tan Buddha and explore Ngong Ping 360 for breathtaking scenery.</li>
  <li>Afternoon: Enjoy a vegetarian meal in Po Lin Monastery and take a serene walk around the Ngong Ping Village.</li>
  <li>Evening: Return to the city for a relaxed dinner and unwind.</li>
</ul>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/assets/images/old.jpg" alt="Bud" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>A tranquil adventure in the mountains</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<h5 id="day-3-sai-kung-seaside-bliss">Day 3: Sai Kung Seaside Bliss</h5>
<ul>
  <li>Morning: Take a boat ride to Sai Kung for island hopping. Visit nearby beaches and enjoy the scenic beauty.</li>
  <li>Afternoon: Try some seafood delicacies at Sai Kung’s famous seafood street. Explore cafes and relax.</li>
  <li>Evening: Choose from the various hiking trails or simply enjoy the serene atmosphere.</li>
</ul>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/assets/images/old.jpg" alt="sai" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>Glorious sea views in Sai Kung</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<h5 id="day-4-mong-kok-shopping-spree">Day 4: Mong Kok Shopping Spree</h5>
<ul>
  <li>Morning: Dive into the bustling markets and malls of Mong Kok for a unique shopping experience.</li>
  <li>Afternoon: Grab a quick bite from local street food stalls. Explore the vibrant street life.</li>
  <li>Evening: Continue shopping or relax at one of the many themed cafes.</li>
</ul>

<h5 id="day-5-central-causeway-bay-and-beyond">Day 5: Central, Causeway Bay, and Beyond</h5>
<ul>
  <li>Morning: Explore the Central Business District (CBD) with its modern architecture and bustling streets.</li>
  <li>Afternoon: Head to Causeway Bay for more shopping and enjoy a leisurely lunch.</li>
  <li>Evening: Experience the nightlife in Wan Chai or enjoy a sophisticated dinner in one of the upscale restaurants.</li>
</ul>

<h5 id="bonus-day-islands-escape">Bonus Day: Islands Escape</h5>
<ul>
  <li>Lamma Island: Spend a day hiking through the scenic landscapes, exploring old villages, and enjoying the island’s tranquility.</li>
  <li>The Peak: Take the Peak Tram for breathtaking views of the city and explore the attractions at The Peak.</li>
  <li>Repulse Bay and Stanley: Relax at Repulse Bay’s beautiful beach and explore the cafes and beaches in Stanley.</li>
</ul>

<p>This 5-day itinerary offers a perfect blend of culture, adventure, shopping, and relaxation, allowing you to experience the diverse facets of Hong Kong.</p>

<h4 id="list-of-restaurants-to-visit-in-hong-kong">List of restaurants to visit in Hong Kong</h4>

<p>Some of my favourites</p>

<p><u>Tim Ho Wan<u>
Location: Various locations
Specialty: Dim Sum, Michelin-starred</u></u></p>

<p><u>Maxim's Palace<u>
Location: 3/F, City Hall, Central
Specialty: Dim Sum, traditional Cantonese</u></u></p>

<p><u>Little Bao<u>
Location: 66 Staunton St, Central
Specialty: Modern Asian cuisine, inventive bao creations</u></u></p>

<p><u>Yung Kee<u>
Location: 32-40 Wellington St, Central
Specialty: Roast Goose, Cantonese cuisine</u></u></p>

<p><u>Mak's Noodle<u>
Location: Various locations
Specialty: Wonton Noodle Soup</u></u></p>

<p><u>Ho Lee Fook<u>
Location: G/F, 1–5 Elgin St, Central
Specialty: Modern Chinese, fusion cuisine</u></u></p>

<p><u>Joy Hing Roasted Meat<u>
Location: 265-267 Hennessy Rd, Wan Chai
Specialty: Roast meat, Michelin-recommended</u></u></p>

<p><u>The Chairman<u>
Location: 18 Kau U Fong, Central
Specialty: Chinese dishes with a focus on locally sourced ingredients</u></u></p>

<p><u>Tsim Chai Kee Noodle<u>
Location: 98 Wellington St, Central
Specialty: Wonton Noodle Soup, Michelin-recommended</u></u></p>

<p><u>Amber<u>
Location: 7/F, The Landmark Mandarin Oriental, 15 Queen's Road Central
Specialty: French cuisine, Michelin-starred</u></u></p>

<p>Hong Kong stands out as a truly unparalleled destination, capturing the hearts of travelers from around the world. Its unique blend of cultural richness, modern vibrancy, and natural beauty creates an irresistible allure. The city’s dynamic energy, showcased through its bustling markets, towering skyscrapers, and diverse neighborhoods, ensures a constant sense of excitement.Hong Kong’s culinary scene, ranging from street food to Michelin-starred restaurants, caters to every palate, making it a gastronomic paradise. The seamless integration of traditional heritage with cutting-edge innovation is evident in its architecture, festivals, and day-to-day life. The convenience of efficient public transportation, coupled with a myriad of attractions and activities, allows visitors to explore the city effortlessly. Whether it’s the panoramic views from Victoria Peak, the spiritual ambiance at Ngong Ping, or the island retreats like Lamma Island, Hong Kong offers a multifaceted experience that caters to diverse interests. Beyond the cityscape, Hong Kong’s warm hospitality and a harmonious blend of East and West contribute to its enduring charm. The resilience and adaptability of its people, paired with a commitment to maintaining its unique identity, make Hong Kong not just a destination but an immersive journey.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Singapore" /><category term="travel" /><category term="Hong Kong" /><category term="vacation" /><category term="itinerary" /><category term="guide" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Embark on an unforgettable journey through the bustling streets and vibrant neighborhoods of Hong Kong, a perennial favorite among Singaporeans for its captivating allure. Our ultimate 5-day travel guide invites you to discover the harmonious blend of tradition and modernity in this enchanting city where East meets West. Join us as we navigate the iconic landmarks, savor culinary delights, and dive into the cultural tapestry that defines Hong Kong. Whether you’re a history enthusiast, a foodie, or a thrill-seeker, our meticulously crafted itinerary promises an immersive experience, uncovering hidden gems and must-visit spots. Get ready to explore Hong Kong like never before!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/hk.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/hk.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ultimate 5-day trip to Hong Kong from Singapore</title><link href="/hongkong-vacation-from-singapore/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ultimate 5-day trip to Hong Kong from Singapore" /><published>2024-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/hongkong-vacation-from-singapore</id><content type="html" xml:base="/hongkong-vacation-from-singapore/"><![CDATA[<p>Embark on an unforgettable journey through the bustling streets and vibrant neighborhoods of Hong Kong, a perennial favorite among Singaporeans for its captivating allure. Our ultimate 5-day travel guide invites you to discover the harmonious blend of tradition and modernity in this enchanting city where East meets West. Join us as we navigate the iconic landmarks, savor culinary delights, and dive into the cultural tapestry that defines Hong Kong. Whether you’re a history enthusiast, a foodie, or a thrill-seeker, our meticulously crafted itinerary promises an immersive experience, uncovering hidden gems and must-visit spots. Get ready to explore Hong Kong like never before!</p>

<h4 id="getting-to-hong-kong">Getting to Hong Kong</h4>

<p>Traveling from Singapore to Hong Kong offers various options, ensuring a convenient and enjoyable journey. Here are some of the best ways and flights to get from Singapore to Hong Kong:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Direct Flights: Direct flights from Singapore Changi Airport (SIN) to Hong Kong International Airport (HKG) are the most time-efficient option. Singapore Airlines and Cathay Pacific, renowned for their service, operate direct flights, providing comfort and a shorter travel time. Flight Duration: Direct flights typically take around 4 hours, making it a quick and convenient journey.</li>
  <li>Budget Airlines: Consider budget airlines like Scoot or AirAsia for more affordable options. Although these flights might have layovers, they can be a cost-effective choice.</li>
  <li>Connecting Flights: Connecting flights with layovers in other Asian cities may offer flexibility in terms of schedules and prices. Common layover cities include Kuala Lumpur, Bangkok, or Manila.</li>
</ul>

<p>Before booking, consider factors such as your budget, travel preferences, and schedule flexibility. Always check travel restrictions, visa requirements, and health protocols, especially in light of any ongoing global situations. To be honest, a direct flight should be between $350-500 SGD.</p>

<h4 id="getting-around-hk">Getting around HK</h4>

<p>Navigating Hong Kong is a breeze thanks to its efficient and well-connected public transportation system. Here are the best ways to get around in Hong Kong:</p>
<ol>
  <li>MTR (Mass Transit Railway): The MTR is the backbone of Hong Kong’s public transportation, covering the majority of the city. It’s fast, reliable, and connects key areas, making it an ideal choice for both locals and tourists.</li>
  <li>Buses: Hong Kong has an extensive bus network, offering routes that cover almost every corner of the city. Buses are a cost-effective way to explore areas not directly served by the MTR.</li>
  <li>Trams: Hong Kong’s iconic double-decker trams are a charming and leisurely way to see the city. They operate on Hong Kong Island and provide a unique perspective of the streets.</li>
  <li>Ferries: With its numerous islands, Hong Kong offers ferry services that provide scenic views of the skyline. Ferries connect Central to outlying islands like Lantau, Cheung Chau, and Lamma.</li>
  <li>Taxis: Taxis are readily available, especially in urban areas. They are a convenient option for reaching destinations not directly accessible by public transportation.</li>
  <li>Minibuses: Minibuses operate on fixed routes and are a flexible mode of transportation. They can take you to destinations that might not be easily reachable by larger buses.</li>
  <li>Octopus Card: The Octopus Card is a smart payment card that can be used on all forms of public transportation. It offers a cashless and convenient way to pay for MTR, buses, trams, and even purchases at various shops.</li>
  <li>Walk and Explore: Hong Kong is a pedestrian-friendly city, especially in areas like Central, Tsim Sha Tsui, and Causeway Bay.
Walking allows you to immerse yourself in the vibrant street life and discover hidden gems.</li>
</ol>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/assets/images/old.jpg" alt="old" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>Charming architecture of the old Hong Kong</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<h4 id="cost-of-travel">Cost of travel</h4>

<p>The costs of traveling around Hong Kong can vary based on your preferred mode of transportation, the duration of your stay, and your activity choices. Here’s a breakdown of some typical expenses:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Public Transportation: MTR (Mass Transit Railway): Fares depend on the distance traveled, ranging from HKD 4 to HKD 55. Buses: Bus fares start at around HKD 4, with additional charges for longer distances or specific routes.</li>
  <li>Taxis: Flagfall: Around HKD 24, with additional charges for distance traveled. Airport to Central: Approximately HKD 300.</li>
  <li>Ferries: Star Ferry: HKD 2.7 to HKD 3.7 per adult ticket. Outlying Islands: Ferry fares vary; for example, the Lantau Island ferry can cost around HKD 35.</li>
  <li>Trams: Tram rides: A flat fare of HKD 2.6 per adult, regardless of the distance traveled.</li>
  <li>Minibuses: Minibus fares: Typically around HKD 8-10, but can vary.</li>
  <li>Octopus Card: The Octopus Card is a convenient way to pay for public transportation and some purchases. The initial cost is HKD 150, inclusive of a HKD 50 deposit and HKD 100 usable value.</li>
  <li>Attractions: Peak Tram: Around HKD 37 for a one-way adult ticket. Ngong Ping 360: Prices vary based on the type of ticket, ranging from HKD 135 to HKD 235. Disneyland: Ticket prices start at around HKD 639 for adults.</li>
  <li>Food: Local Eateries: Meals at local eateries can range from HKD 30 to HKD 100 per person. Mid-Range Restaurants: Expect to spend HKD 200 to HKD 500 per person. Fine Dining: Fine dining can range from HKD 500 to HKD 1,500 or more per person.</li>
  <li>Accommodation:
    <ul>
      <li>Budget Hotels: Starting from HKD 400 per night.</li>
      <li>Mid-Range Hotels: Starting from HKD 800 per night.</li>
      <li>Luxury Hotels: Starting from HKD 1,500 per night.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Miscellaneous: Shopping, Entertainment, and Miscellaneous Expenses: Varies based on personal preferences and activities.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="best-time-to-visit-hong-kong">Best time to visit Hong Kong</h4>

<p>The best time to visit Hong Kong depends on your preferences and the type of experience you’re seeking. The great thing is that Hong Kong is fantastic to visit across all seasons (though it’s a tad hot in the summer). Here are some considerations for different seasons:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Autumn (September to November): Weather: Autumn is one of the most pleasant times to visit, with mild temperatures and lower humidity. Average temperatures range from 20°C to 28°C (68°F to 82°F). Activities: Enjoy outdoor activities, festivals, and sightseeing without the discomfort of high heat.</li>
  <li>Winter (December to February): Weather: Hong Kong experiences a mild winter, with temperatures ranging from 12°C to 20°C (54°F to 68°F). Activities: While it’s the coolest time, it’s still comfortable for exploring. Winter is also a festive season with Christmas and Chinese New Year celebrations.</li>
  <li>Spring (March to May): Weather: Spring brings warmer temperatures, ranging from 17°C to 26°C (63°F to 79°F). Activities: Enjoy blooming flowers, outdoor events, and cultural festivals. It’s a good time for hiking and exploring nature.</li>
  <li>Summer (June to August): Weather: Hong Kong’s summer is hot and humid, with temperatures ranging from 26°C to 31°C (79°F to 88°F). Activities: While summer brings typhoons and occasional heavy rainfall, it’s also a vibrant season with events, festivals, and lively atmosphere. Beach activities are popular during this time.</li>
</ul>

<p>Considerations during seasonal periods:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Crowds: Hong Kong can be crowded during festivals and holidays, so plan accordingly.</li>
  <li>Budget: Prices for accommodation and flights may vary, with high demand during peak seasons.</li>
  <li>Events: Check the calendar for major events, such as the Hong Kong Arts Festival, Chinese New Year, and the Dragon Boat Festival.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="best-places-to-stay-in-hong-kong">Best places to stay in Hong Kong</h4>

<p>Here are hotel recommendations for the specified locations in Hong Kong:</p>

<p><u>Central<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>The Murray, Hong Kong: A luxury hotel with contemporary design and excellent amenities.</li>
  <li>Four Seasons Hotel Hong Kong: Known for its stunning harbor views and world-class service.</li>
  <li>The Landmark Mandarin Oriental: Offers a blend of elegance and modern luxury.</li>
  <li>Island Shangri-La: Iconic luxury hotel with spacious rooms and panoramic views.</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Tsim Sha Tsui (TST)<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>The Peninsula Hong Kong: An iconic hotel offering a blend of colonial elegance and modern luxury.</li>
  <li>K11 ARTUS: A boutique hotel with artistic flair and personalized service.</li>
  <li>InterContinental Hong Kong: Known for its harborfront location and luxurious accommodations.</li>
  <li>The Langham, Hong Kong: A five-star hotel with a touch of European elegance.</li>
</ul>

<p><u> Mong Kok<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>Cordis, Hong Kong: Located in the heart of Mong Kok, it offers a mix of luxury and convenience.</li>
  <li>The Olympian Hong Kong: A boutique hotel with spacious rooms and a tranquil atmosphere.</li>
  <li>Royal Plaza Hotel: Combines modern comforts with easy access to shopping and entertainment.</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Causeway Bay<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>Lanson Place Hotel: A stylish boutique hotel in the heart of Causeway Bay.</li>
  <li>Regal Hongkong Hotel: Offers a central location with easy access to shopping and dining.</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Admiralty<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>JW Marriott Hotel Hong Kong: Luxury hotel with a central location and elegant design.</li>
  <li>The Upper House: A sophisticated hotel offering panoramic views and contemporary luxury.</li>
  <li>Rosewood Hong Kong: A prestigious hotel offering luxurious accommodations, stunning harbor views, and top-notch facilities. Known for its sophisticated design and exceptional service.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="the-ultimate-5-day-itinerary">The ultimate 5 day itinerary</h4>

<h5 id="day-1-tsim-sha-tsui-extravaganza">Day 1: Tsim Sha Tsui Extravaganza</h5>
<ul>
  <li>Morning: Start your day with shopping in Tsim Sha Tsui’s bustling markets and luxury malls. Enjoy a sumptuous dim sum brunch.</li>
  <li>Afternoon: Visit the iconic Victoria Harbour for a stunning view and take a leisurely stroll along the Tsim Sha Tsui Promenade.</li>
  <li>Evening: Explore Avenue of Stars, indulge in some more shopping, and have a delightful dinner at one of the harbor-view restaurants.</li>
</ul>

<h5 id="day-2-ngong-ping-adventure">Day 2: Ngong Ping Adventure</h5>
<ul>
  <li>Morning: Head to Ngong Ping to witness the majestic Tian Tan Buddha and explore Ngong Ping 360 for breathtaking scenery.</li>
  <li>Afternoon: Enjoy a vegetarian meal in Po Lin Monastery and take a serene walk around the Ngong Ping Village.</li>
  <li>Evening: Return to the city for a relaxed dinner and unwind.</li>
</ul>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/assets/images/old.jpg" alt="Bud" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>A tranquil adventure in the mountains</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<h5 id="day-3-sai-kung-seaside-bliss">Day 3: Sai Kung Seaside Bliss</h5>
<ul>
  <li>Morning: Take a boat ride to Sai Kung for island hopping. Visit nearby beaches and enjoy the scenic beauty.</li>
  <li>Afternoon: Try some seafood delicacies at Sai Kung’s famous seafood street. Explore cafes and relax.</li>
  <li>Evening: Choose from the various hiking trails or simply enjoy the serene atmosphere.</li>
</ul>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/assets/images/old.jpg" alt="sai" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>Glorious sea views in Sai Kung</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<h5 id="day-4-mong-kok-shopping-spree">Day 4: Mong Kok Shopping Spree</h5>
<ul>
  <li>Morning: Dive into the bustling markets and malls of Mong Kok for a unique shopping experience.</li>
  <li>Afternoon: Grab a quick bite from local street food stalls. Explore the vibrant street life.</li>
  <li>Evening: Continue shopping or relax at one of the many themed cafes.</li>
</ul>

<h5 id="day-5-central-causeway-bay-and-beyond">Day 5: Central, Causeway Bay, and Beyond</h5>
<ul>
  <li>Morning: Explore the Central Business District (CBD) with its modern architecture and bustling streets.</li>
  <li>Afternoon: Head to Causeway Bay for more shopping and enjoy a leisurely lunch.</li>
  <li>Evening: Experience the nightlife in Wan Chai or enjoy a sophisticated dinner in one of the upscale restaurants.</li>
</ul>

<h5 id="bonus-day-islands-escape">Bonus Day: Islands Escape</h5>
<ul>
  <li>Lamma Island: Spend a day hiking through the scenic landscapes, exploring old villages, and enjoying the island’s tranquility.</li>
  <li>The Peak: Take the Peak Tram for breathtaking views of the city and explore the attractions at The Peak.</li>
  <li>Repulse Bay and Stanley: Relax at Repulse Bay’s beautiful beach and explore the cafes and beaches in Stanley.</li>
</ul>

<p>This 5-day itinerary offers a perfect blend of culture, adventure, shopping, and relaxation, allowing you to experience the diverse facets of Hong Kong.</p>

<h4 id="list-of-restaurants-to-visit-in-hong-kong">List of restaurants to visit in Hong Kong</h4>

<p>Some of my favourites</p>

<p><u>Tim Ho Wan<u>
Location: Various locations
Specialty: Dim Sum, Michelin-starred</u></u></p>

<p><u>Maxim's Palace<u>
Location: 3/F, City Hall, Central
Specialty: Dim Sum, traditional Cantonese</u></u></p>

<p><u>Little Bao<u>
Location: 66 Staunton St, Central
Specialty: Modern Asian cuisine, inventive bao creations</u></u></p>

<p><u>Yung Kee<u>
Location: 32-40 Wellington St, Central
Specialty: Roast Goose, Cantonese cuisine</u></u></p>

<p><u>Mak's Noodle<u>
Location: Various locations
Specialty: Wonton Noodle Soup</u></u></p>

<p><u>Ho Lee Fook<u>
Location: G/F, 1–5 Elgin St, Central
Specialty: Modern Chinese, fusion cuisine</u></u></p>

<p><u>Joy Hing Roasted Meat<u>
Location: 265-267 Hennessy Rd, Wan Chai
Specialty: Roast meat, Michelin-recommended</u></u></p>

<p><u>The Chairman<u>
Location: 18 Kau U Fong, Central
Specialty: Chinese dishes with a focus on locally sourced ingredients</u></u></p>

<p><u>Tsim Chai Kee Noodle<u>
Location: 98 Wellington St, Central
Specialty: Wonton Noodle Soup, Michelin-recommended</u></u></p>

<p><u>Amber<u>
Location: 7/F, The Landmark Mandarin Oriental, 15 Queen's Road Central
Specialty: French cuisine, Michelin-starred</u></u></p>

<p>Hong Kong stands out as a truly unparalleled destination, capturing the hearts of travelers from around the world. Its unique blend of cultural richness, modern vibrancy, and natural beauty creates an irresistible allure. The city’s dynamic energy, showcased through its bustling markets, towering skyscrapers, and diverse neighborhoods, ensures a constant sense of excitement.Hong Kong’s culinary scene, ranging from street food to Michelin-starred restaurants, caters to every palate, making it a gastronomic paradise. The seamless integration of traditional heritage with cutting-edge innovation is evident in its architecture, festivals, and day-to-day life. The convenience of efficient public transportation, coupled with a myriad of attractions and activities, allows visitors to explore the city effortlessly. Whether it’s the panoramic views from Victoria Peak, the spiritual ambiance at Ngong Ping, or the island retreats like Lamma Island, Hong Kong offers a multifaceted experience that caters to diverse interests. Beyond the cityscape, Hong Kong’s warm hospitality and a harmonious blend of East and West contribute to its enduring charm. The resilience and adaptability of its people, paired with a commitment to maintaining its unique identity, make Hong Kong not just a destination but an immersive journey.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Singapore" /><category term="travel" /><category term="Hong Kong" /><category term="vacation" /><category term="itinerary" /><category term="guide" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Embark on an unforgettable journey through the bustling streets and vibrant neighborhoods of Hong Kong, a perennial favorite among Singaporeans for its captivating allure. Our ultimate 5-day travel guide invites you to discover the harmonious blend of tradition and modernity in this enchanting city where East meets West. Join us as we navigate the iconic landmarks, savor culinary delights, and dive into the cultural tapestry that defines Hong Kong. Whether you’re a history enthusiast, a foodie, or a thrill-seeker, our meticulously crafted itinerary promises an immersive experience, uncovering hidden gems and must-visit spots. Get ready to explore Hong Kong like never before!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/hk.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/hk.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Best bak ku teh recommendations in Singapore</title><link href="/singapore-bak-ku-teh/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Best bak ku teh recommendations in Singapore" /><published>2024-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-bak-ku-teh</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-bak-ku-teh/"><![CDATA[<p>Nestled within the rich tapestry of Singapore’s culinary landscape is a dish that not only tantalizes the taste buds but also echoes the island’s cultural heritage - Bak Kut Teh. Translating to “meat bone tea” in Hokkien, this flavorful concoction has woven itself into the fabric of Singaporean cuisine, offering a unique and comforting experience for locals and visitors alike. In this culinary exploration, we embark on a savory journey to uncover the origins, significance, and preparation of Bak Kut Teh, as well as unveil the best spots across the Lion City to savor this aromatic delight.</p>

<h4 id="what-is-bak-ku-teh">What is bak ku teh</h4>

<p>Bak Kut Teh, a beloved culinary treasure in Singapore and across various Southeast Asian nations, derives its name from the Hokkien dialect, translating to “meat bone tea.” This iconic dish boasts a symphony of rich flavors and tender textures, with succulent pork ribs taking center stage in a meticulously crafted broth. The broth itself is a masterpiece, infused with a harmonious blend of aromatic herbs and spices, showcasing the region’s culinary prowess. The slow and deliberate simmering process not only tenderizes the meat but also allows the infusion of medicinal herbs such as ginseng, cinnamon, cloves, and star anise, resulting in a luxurious and flavorful concoction.</p>

<h4 id="how-did-bak-ku-teh-come-about">How did Bak ku teh come about?</h4>

<p>The story of Bak Kut Teh’s creation dates back to the 19th century in China, where it is believed to have originated in the Fujian province. As the Chinese diaspora spread, the Hokkiens and Teochews brought this culinary tradition with them to regions like Malaysia and Singapore. This dish has evolved over time, transcending its origins to become a culinary icon. Beyond being a delightful meal, Bak Kut Teh encapsulates the spirit of Southeast Asian cuisine, a testament to the region’s diverse culinary heritage. Its popularity has extended far beyond local communities, making it a must-try for both locals and visitors seeking an authentic taste of the region.</p>

<h4 id="types-of-bak-ku-teh">Types of bak ku teh</h4>

<p>Bak Kut Teh comes in several variations, each offering a unique twist to the classic pork rib soup. Here are some popular types of Bak Kut Teh:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Teochew-style Bak Kut Teh: Broth Characteristics: Clear and peppery broth with a mild herbal flavor.
Key Ingredients: Garlic, pepper, and a variety of herbs, emphasizing a lighter taste.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Hokkien-style Bak Kut Teh:
Broth Characteristics: Dark and flavorful broth, rich in herbal and savory notes.
Key Ingredients: Soy sauce, dark soy sauce, and a mix of robust herbs for a heartier taste.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Klang-style Bak Kut Teh:
Broth Characteristics: Dark, herbal, and intense flavor, often accompanied by a thicker, more robust broth.
Key Ingredients: A unique spice blend, emphasizing strong herbal and savory elements.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Claypot Bak Kut Teh:
Presentation: Served in a clay pot, keeping the soup piping hot.
Broth Characteristics: Similar to Hokkien-style or Teochew-style, depending on the region.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Dry Bak Kut Teh:
Preparation: Pork ribs are stir-fried with a flavorful mixture of spices until the broth is reduced, resulting in a dry and fragrant dish.
Key Ingredients: Dried cuttlefish, dried chili, and other spices.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Premium Bak Kut Teh:
Variation: Some establishments offer premium versions, featuring high-quality ingredients like prime ribs and a more intricate blend of herbs and spices.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Herbal Bak Kut Teh:
Broth Characteristics: Emphasizes the use of various Chinese herbs, resulting in a more medicinal and herbal flavor.
These variations cater to different taste preferences, ensuring that Bak Kut Teh enthusiasts can find a version that resonates with their flavor preferences. Each type reflects the cultural diversity and culinary creativity surrounding this beloved dish.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<h4 id="best-places-to-eat-bak-ku-teh">Best places to eat bak ku teh</h4>

<p>Here are some of the top establishments known for serving outstanding Bak Kut Teh, along with their locations. My recommendations</p>

<p><u>Song Fa Bak Kut Teh<u></u></u></p>

<p>Location: 11 New Bridge Road, #01-01, Singapore 059383
Overview: Nestled in the heart of Chinatown, Song Fa is an iconic Bak Kut Teh institution that has been delighting diners since 1969. Renowned for its peppery and aromatic broth, the restaurant offers a comforting and authentic Bak Kut Teh experience.</p>

<p><u>Founder Bak Kut Teh<u></u></u></p>

<p>Location: Multiple outlets across Singapore
Overview: With a history dating back to 1978, Founder Bak Kut Teh is celebrated for its Teochew-style herbal broth. The tender pork ribs are simmered to perfection, creating a dish that’s both hearty and invigorating.</p>

<p><u>Ng Ah Sio Bak Kut Teh<u></u></u></p>

<p>Location: 208 Rangoon Road, Hong Building, Singapore 218453
Overview: Located near the vibrant Tiong Bahru Market, Ng Ah Sio Bak Kut Teh is synonymous with robust and flavorful soup. The restaurant’s secret recipe, passed down through generations, has made it a popular choice for both locals and tourists.</p>

<p><u>Friends Bak Kut Teh<u></u></u></p>

<p>Location: 155 Bukit Batok Street 11, Singapore 650155
Overview: A hidden gem that has gained a strong following, Friends Bak Kut Teh is known for its delightful mix of herbs and spices. The warm and inviting ambiance adds to the overall dining experience, making it a favorite among Bak Kut Teh enthusiasts.</p>

<p><u>Legendary Bak Kut Teh<u></u></u></p>

<p>Location: 30 South Bridge Road, #01-04, Singapore 058673
Overview: As the name suggests, Legendary Bak Kut Teh lives up to its reputation by serving a legendary bowl of flavorful goodness. With a commitment to quality ingredients and meticulous preparation, this establishment has earned its place among the best in the Bak Kut Teh scene.</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/assets/images/BKT2.jpg" alt="BKT2" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>My typical BKT meal</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<h4 id="how-do-you-cook-bak-ku-teh-at-home">How do you cook bak ku teh at home?</h4>

<p>Cooking Bak Kut Teh at home can be a rewarding culinary venture, allowing you to savor the comforting aroma and flavors in the comfort of your kitchen. Here’s a simplified recipe to guide you through the process:</p>

<p>Ingredients:</p>
<ul>
  <li>1 kg pork ribs, cut into bite-sized pieces</li>
  <li>2-3 cloves garlic, minced</li>
  <li>1 tablespoon vegetable oil</li>
  <li>2-3 dried shiitake mushrooms (optional)</li>
  <li>1 packet (about 40g) Bak Kut Teh spice mix (personally I prefer the Song Fa one)</li>
  <li>1.5 liters water</li>
  <li>Salt and pepper to taste</li>
  <li>Fresh coriander and sliced green onions for garnish</li>
</ul>

<p>Instructions:</p>
<ol>
  <li>Prepare the Ribs: Rinse the pork ribs thoroughly and set aside.</li>
  <li>Sauté Garlic:In a large pot, heat the vegetable oil over medium heat. Add minced garlic and sauté until fragrant.</li>
  <li>Add Bak Kut Teh Spice Mix: Add the Bak Kut Teh spice mix to the pot. Stir well to combine with the garlic, allowing the spices to release their flavors.</li>
  <li>Add Water: Pour in the water and bring the mixture to a boil. Once boiling, reduce the heat to low and let it simmer for about 30 minutes.</li>
  <li>Simmer the Ribs: Add the pork ribs to the pot. If using dried shiitake mushrooms, add them as well. Let the mixture simmer on low heat for another 1.5 to 2 hours, allowing the ribs to become tender and absorb the flavors.</li>
  <li>Season to Taste: Season the Bak Kut Teh with salt and pepper to taste. Adjust the seasoning based on your preference for saltiness and spiciness.</li>
  <li>Garnish and Serve: Once the pork ribs are tender and the broth is flavorful, it’s time to serve. Ladle the Bak Kut Teh into bowls, garnish with fresh coriander and sliced green onions.</li>
  <li>Serve with Accompaniments: Bak Kut Teh is traditionally served with steamed white rice, youtiao (Chinese fried dough), or other side dishes of your choice.</li>
</ol>

<p>Now, you can enjoy your homemade Bak Kut Teh! Feel free to customize the recipe to suit your taste preferences, experimenting with different spice levels and additional ingredients. Cooking Bak Kut Teh at home is not only a delightful culinary experience but also a wonderful way to share this beloved dish with family and friends.</p>

<p>I hope you get a chance to explore Bak Ku Teh in all it’s glory in Singapore. Let me know what’s your favourite go-to!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Singapore" /><category term="bak ku teh" /><category term="food" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nestled within the rich tapestry of Singapore’s culinary landscape is a dish that not only tantalizes the taste buds but also echoes the island’s cultural heritage - Bak Kut Teh. Translating to “meat bone tea” in Hokkien, this flavorful concoction has woven itself into the fabric of Singaporean cuisine, offering a unique and comforting experience for locals and visitors alike. In this culinary exploration, we embark on a savory journey to uncover the origins, significance, and preparation of Bak Kut Teh, as well as unveil the best spots across the Lion City to savor this aromatic delight.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/BKT.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/BKT.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Singapore KFC - recommendations, pricing and surprises</title><link href="/singapore-kfc/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Singapore KFC - recommendations, pricing and surprises" /><published>2024-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-kfc</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-kfc/"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome back to our blog! Following the success of our article on McDonald’s in Singapore, we’re now turning our attention to another fast food favorite - Kentucky Fried Chicken (KFC). In this article, we’ll be exploring the history of KFC in Singapore, discussing what makes it unique, and highlighting the must-try items on the menu. This piece promises to be as engaging and informative as our previous one, offering a closer look at why KFC has become a staple in Singapore’s fast food scene. Let’s dive in.</p>

<h4 id="history-of-kfc-in-singapore">History of KFC in Singapore</h4>

<p>Kentucky Fried Chicken (KFC) first opened its doors in Singapore in 1977. It was the first American fast food chain to set up shop in Singapore. The first KFC restaurant was located at Somerset Road, and it introduced Singaporeans to KFC’s signature fried chicken recipe, which was well-received.</p>

<p>Over the years, KFC Singapore grew steadily and adapted its menu to local tastes, introducing items like the Curry Crunch Chicken and the Zinger Rice Bowl. Today, KFC has over 80 outlets spread across Singapore, making it one of the most popular fast food chains in the country. In addition to its dine-in and takeaway services, KFC Singapore also offers efficient delivery services, further cementing its popularity among Singaporeans.</p>

<p>Throughout its history in Singapore, KFC has remained committed to serving high-quality food and providing excellent service, contributing to its continued success and popularity.</p>

<h4 id="why-is-kfc-so-loved-in-singapore">Why is KFC so loved in singapore</h4>

<p>The popularity of KFC in Singapore can be attributed to several factors:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Familiarity and Consistency: As a global franchise, KFC maintains a consistent taste and quality across its outlets worldwide, making it a reliable choice for many. Singaporeans, like many others around the world, appreciate the familiar taste of KFC’s original recipe chicken.</li>
  <li>Local Adaptation: KFC in Singapore has done a great job of adapting its menu to local tastes. This includes introducing items that cater to the Singaporean palate, such as the Curry Crunch Chicken and the Zinger Rice Bowl, which have been well-received by customers.</li>
  <li>Marketing and Promotions: KFC Singapore often runs promotions and deals that are attractive to consumers. These include bundle meals and limited-time offerings, which not only provide value for money but also add variety to their menu, keeping customers interested.</li>
  <li>Convenience: With numerous outlets spread across the island, KFC is easily accessible to most residents in Singapore. In addition, they offer efficient delivery services, making it a popular choice for those who prefer to dine at home.</li>
</ul>

<p>It’s KFC’s ability to provide consistent quality, cater to local tastes, offer attractive promotions, and their widespread presence that makes them so loved in Singapore.</p>

<h4 id="kfc-must-orders">KFC must orders</h4>

<p>In Singapore, KFC’s enticing menu beckons with an array of tempting choices, perfect for satisfying diverse cravings:</p>

<p><u>Original Recipe Chicken<u>
Indulge in the timeless delight of KFC's Original Recipe, a delectable blend of 11 herbs and spices that guarantees a flavor explosion with every bite.</u></u></p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/assets/images/kfc.jpg" alt="原味雞" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>The OG chicken</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p><u>Zinger Burger<u>
Spice up your meal with the Zinger Burger, where a crispy chicken fillet meets the zing of spicy mayonnaise, creating a harmonious symphony of flavors.</u></u></p>

<p><u>Cheesy Mayo Slider<u>
Experience pure joy in a compact form with the Cheesy Mayo Slider, a delightful snack that combines the richness of cheese with the creaminess of mayo.</u></u></p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/assets/images/mayo.jpg" alt="芝士美乃滋滑堡" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>Mayo burger</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p><u>Breakfast Twister<u>
Kickstart your day with the Breakfast Twister, a scrumptious wrap filled with morning favorites like eggs and hash browns, ensuring a hearty and satisfying breakfast.</u></u></p>

<p><u>Zinger Stacker<u>
Elevate your dining experience with the Zinger Stacker, a generous offering of multiple layers of spicy goodness, designed to satiate even the heartiest appetites.</u></u></p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/assets/images/stacker.jpg" alt="Zinger" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>Zinger stacker</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p><u>Egg Tarts<u>
Treat your sweet tooth to KFC's Egg Tarts, a heavenly dessert option that perfectly complements the savory notes of the main course.</u></u></p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/assets/images/tart.jpg" alt="Portugese" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>Portuguese egg tart</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p><u>BBQ Pockett Box<u>
Immerse yourself in a culinary adventure with the BBQ Pockett Box, a curated selection of barbecue-flavored delights, thoughtfully combined for a diverse and satisfying meal experience.</u></u></p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/assets/images/pocket.jpg" alt="pocket" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>BBQ Pockett Box</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<h4 id="watch-out-for-special-menu-items">Watch out for special menu items</h4>

<p>Special menu items emerge as limited-time delights that captivate taste buds with innovative twists on the fast-food giant’s classic offerings. These special editions, like the Brown Sugar Boba Tea Tart and the Waffle Original Recipe Double Down, showcase KFC’s commitment to culinary experimentation and responding to diverse food trends. The Brown Sugar Boba Tea Tart blends the sweetness of brown sugar with the delightful chewiness of boba pearls, creating a unique dessert experience. On the savory side, the Waffle Original Recipe Double Down elevates the iconic Double Down by sandwiching the signature Zinger fillet between two savory waffle patties. These special menu items not only cater to evolving flavor preferences but also add an element of excitement and anticipation for KFC enthusiasts in Singapore.</p>

<p>Personally, I think KFC is alright but compared to all the other fried chicken options in Singapore, it wouldn’t be my first choice. Let me know what are your favourite KFC items and whether you visit this place in Singapore.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Singapore" /><category term="fast food" /><category term="kfc" /><category term="food" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome back to our blog! Following the success of our article on McDonald’s in Singapore, we’re now turning our attention to another fast food favorite - Kentucky Fried Chicken (KFC). In this article, we’ll be exploring the history of KFC in Singapore, discussing what makes it unique, and highlighting the must-try items on the menu. This piece promises to be as engaging and informative as our previous one, offering a closer look at why KFC has become a staple in Singapore’s fast food scene. Let’s dive in.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/kfc.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/kfc.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Singapore weather and secrets to tracking it</title><link href="/singapore-weather/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Singapore weather and secrets to tracking it" /><published>2023-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-weather</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-weather/"><![CDATA[<p>In the heart of Southeast Asia lies the island city-state of Singapore, known for its bustling city life and rich cultural diversity. But there’s one more thing that’s constant in Singapore - its tropical climate. Located just a stone’s throw from the equator, Singapore experiences warm weather all year round, interspersed with sudden bursts of rainfall. In this blog post, we’ll explore Singapore’s climate and weather patterns, and how it shapes the daily lives of its residents. Whether you’re a new resident, a long-time local, or a potential tourist, this guide will help you understand and navigate Singapore’s unique weather conditions. So, let’s dive right in!</p>

<h4 id="what-is-singapores-weather-and-why-is-it-the-way-it-is">What is singapore’s weather and why is it the way it is</h4>

<p>Singapore is located 137 kilometers north of the Equator and does not experience the four traditional seasons of spring, summer, autumn, and winter. Instead, it has a tropical rainforest climate with no significant changes in temperature due to the proximity to the equator.</p>

<p>Singapore experiences a relatively uniform temperature, humidity, and precipitation throughout the year. The uniform temperature is a result of the city-state’s maritime exposure, which moderates the heat. However, the high humidity can make the actual temperature feel hotter than it is. This ‘feels-like’ temperature, factoring in the humidity, can reach up to 34°C (93°F) in the daytime.</p>

<p>While rainfall is a common occurrence throughout the year, the intensity of the rainfall varies. Singapore experiences two monsoon seasons - the Northeast Monsoon from December to early March, and the Southwest Monsoon from June to September. During these periods, rainfall is more frequent and intense with thunderstorms commonly occurring in the late afternoon and early evening.</p>

<p>Despite the generally high humidity and rainfall, Singapore gets plenty of sunshine. It’s sunny approximately 50% of the time during daylight hours, equating to about 12 hours of sunlight per day, as the country is located near the Equator.
Singapore’s weather can be quite unpredictable. Even on a sunny day, rain showers can suddenly occur, often brief but heavy. Therefore, it is always advisable for both residents and visitors to be prepared with an umbrella or raincoat when heading outdoors.</p>

<p>Overall, the climate in Singapore is warm and humid throughout the year, characterized by abundant rainfall and a significant amount of sunshine.</p>

<h4 id="how-best-to-adapt-for-singapore-weather">How best to adapt for singapore weather</h4>

<p>Here are some tips to best prepare for Singapore’s weather as a tourist:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Light Clothing: Singapore’s weather is hot and humid throughout the year, with temperatures usually between 25°C to 33°C. Light, breathable clothing is recommended. Cotton t-shirts, shorts, skirts, or light trousers are ideal.</li>
  <li>Sun Protection: Due to Singapore’s equatorial location, the sun can be quite strong. Sunscreen with a high SPF, sunglasses, and a hat or umbrella for sun protection are must-haves when venturing out during the day.</li>
  <li>Stay Hydrated: The humidity can make you sweat more than usual, so it’s important to keep hydrated. Always carry a water bottle with you and drink frequently.</li>
  <li>Umbrella or Raincoat: Rain showers can happen frequently and unexpectedly due to the tropical rainforest climate, so it’s a good idea to carry an umbrella or a small, packable raincoat.</li>
  <li>Comfortable Footwear: You’ll likely be walking a lot as a tourist, and combined with the hot weather, comfortable footwear is essential. Opt for breathable, comfortable shoes or sandals.</li>
  <li>Air-Conditioned Places: Plan some indoor activities as well. Singapore has many museums, shopping malls, and restaurants where you can escape the heat.</li>
  <li>Adaptation Time: Give yourself time to adapt to the hot and humid climate, especially if you’re from a cooler country. Take it easy for the first few days.</li>
</ul>

<p>Remember to check the weather forecast often, as it can change rapidly. Despite the heat and humidity, you’ll find that the weather won’t be a barrier to enjoying what Singapore has to offer.</p>

<h4 id="secret-way-of-tracking-singapore-weather">Secret way of tracking singapore weather</h4>

<p>There’s no ‘secret’ way to track Singapore’s weather, but there are several reliable sources and methods to keep updated:</p>
<ol>
  <li>Meteorological Service Singapore (MSS): The MSS website provides real-time weather updates, forecasts, and other meteorological information about Singapore.</li>
  <li>Weather Apps: Numerous weather apps, such as Weather@SG, AccuWeather, or the Weather Channel, provide real-time updates and forecasts. Remember to set your location to Singapore for accurate information.</li>
  <li>National Environment Agency (NEA): NEA’s website also monitors and provides updates about Singapore’s weather. They also have a mobile app that provides real-time weather updates and forecasts.</li>
  <li>News Channels: Local news channels in Singapore often provide weather forecasts and updates, especially during news broadcasts.</li>
  <li>Social Media: Some weather agencies and meteorological services have social media accounts where they post regular updates.</li>
</ol>

<p>Remember, Singapore’s weather can change quickly, so it’s a good idea to check the forecast regularly throughout the day. Google weather’s decent but NEA is always the best.</p>

<h4 id="where-can-you-find-cold-weather-in-singapore">Where can you find cold weather in singapore</h4>

<p>In Singapore, which is a tropical country, cold weather is not naturally occurring. However, there are several places where you can experience colder temperatures (not really…).</p>
<ul>
  <li>Shopping Malls: Singapore’s shopping malls, which have become an integral part of the urban landscape, are usually air-conditioned and can be quite cold. Some of the best shopping malls in Singapore are Ion Orchard, Vivocity, and Bugis Junction</li>
  <li>Switching on the Aircon: At home or in the office, turning on the air conditioning can create a colder environment</li>
  <li>Getting out of the country: Self-explanatory</li>
</ul>

<p>Overall, Singapore’s weather is known for its tropical rainforest climate, with high temperatures and humidity all year round. The rainy season mainly occurs from November to January, but it can rain at any time of the year. Singapore’s weather changes rapidly, so both locals and tourists need to keep a close eye on weather forecasts. Fortunately, there are various tools and methods to track Singapore’s weather, including the website of the Meteorological Service Singapore (MSS), weather apps, and the website and apps of the National Environment Agency (NEA). These sources provide real-time weather updates and forecasts, allowing people to make appropriate plans and preparations according to weather changes. Let me know your tips and tricks with Singapore’s weather.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Singapore" /><category term="weather" /><category term="rain" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the heart of Southeast Asia lies the island city-state of Singapore, known for its bustling city life and rich cultural diversity. But there’s one more thing that’s constant in Singapore - its tropical climate. Located just a stone’s throw from the equator, Singapore experiences warm weather all year round, interspersed with sudden bursts of rainfall. In this blog post, we’ll explore Singapore’s climate and weather patterns, and how it shapes the daily lives of its residents. Whether you’re a new resident, a long-time local, or a potential tourist, this guide will help you understand and navigate Singapore’s unique weather conditions. So, let’s dive right in!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/weather.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/weather.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Unveiling the Pinnacle of Luxury in Singapore’s Best Hotels</title><link href="/singapore-best-hotels/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Unveiling the Pinnacle of Luxury in Singapore’s Best Hotels" /><published>2023-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-best-hotels</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-best-hotels/"><![CDATA[<p>In the resplendent panorama of Singapore’s iconic skyline, a splendid tapestry of opulence and hospitality awaits the discerning traveler, promising an extraordinary sojourn like no other. Join us as we delve into the lap of luxury, exploring a curated selection of the city-state’s most exquisite hotels, each boasting its unique charm and allure. Oh, and learn more about how you can snag a great hotel deal.</p>

<h4 id="why-are-hotels-so-expensive-in-singapore">Why are hotels so expensive in Singapore</h4>

<p>Several factors contribute to the high cost of hotels in Singapore:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Limited Space and High Demand: Singapore is a small island nation with limited land space. The demand for accommodation, both for business and tourism, often exceeds the available supply, driving up prices</li>
  <li>Economic Prosperity: Singapore is a global financial hub and a major business destination in Asia. The city attracts a high number of business travelers, expatriates, and tourists seeking luxury experiences. The strong economy contributes to a higher overall cost of living, including hotel prices</li>
  <li>Luxury Tourism Market: Singapore has positioned itself as a luxury travel destination, offering high-end shopping, dining, and entertainment. Many hotels in Singapore cater to the luxury tourism market, providing premium services, amenities, and experiences, which naturally come at a higher cost</li>
  <li>Operational Costs: The cost of doing business in Singapore is relatively high. Labor costs, real estate prices, and operational expenses for maintaining high standards in facilities and services contribute to the overall cost of running hotels</li>
  <li>Strategic Location: Singapore’s strategic location in Southeast Asia makes it a hub for international travel. Hotels in prime locations, especially those with easy access to business districts, shopping areas, and tourist attractions, tend to command higher prices</li>
  <li>Strict Regulations and Standards: Singapore has stringent regulations and high standards for safety, cleanliness, and service quality in the hospitality industry. Meeting and maintaining these standards require significant investment, which is reflected in the pricing of hotel rooms</li>
  <li>Tourist Taxes and Fees: Singapore imposes taxes and fees on hotel stays, contributing to the overall cost. Additionally, hotels often include service charges and other fees in their pricing structure</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="what-i-look-for-in-quality-hotels">What I look for in quality hotels</h4>

<p>When embarking on a journey and choosing a hotel, certain personal touches can make all the difference. Here’s a heartfelt guide to ensuring your stay is not just accommodation but an experience:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Location: Seek a haven that resonates with your vibe, be it nestled near vibrant attractions, in the heart of business districts, or serenely close to nature</li>
  <li>Amenities and Services: Elevate your stay with hotels that understand your desires — whether it’s unwinding in a spa, staying connected with seamless Wi-Fi, or breaking a sweat in a well-equipped gym</li>
  <li>Room Quality: Your personal sanctuary should boast not just cleanliness but a cozy ambiance, modern conveniences, and perhaps a breathtaking view to make every moment memorable</li>
  <li>Hotel Reputation: Trust in the legacy of renowned hotels; their reputation is a testament to the enduring commitment to hospitality and guest satisfaction</li>
  <li>Loyalty Program: Consider hotels that reward your loyalty, transforming your visits into a series of cherished experiences and exclusive perks</li>
  <li>Price: While mindful of your budget, view the cost as an investment in a curated experience rather than a mere transaction</li>
  <li>Accessibility: Consider your unique needs, ensuring the hotel is not just a place to stay but one that seamlessly accommodates your journey, regardless of mobility requirements</li>
  <li>Dining Options: Indulge your palate with hotels that offer more than meals — they provide a culinary journey, whether it’s a sumptuous in-house restaurant, delightful room service, or a culinary adventure in the neighborhood</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="best-locations-to-stay-in-singapore">Best locations to stay in Singapore</h4>

<p>Choosing the best hotel location in Singapore depends on your preferences and the purpose of your visit. Here are some prime areas catering to different needs:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Marina Bay: Ideal for luxury seekers and those wanting a central location with stunning views of the skyline. Hotels like The + Fullerton Bay Hotel and Marina Bay Sands offer a lavish experience.</li>
  <li>Orchard Road: A shopping haven, perfect for those who want to be in the midst of Singapore’s premier shopping district. Consider hotels like JW Marriott Singapore South Beach for a touch of luxury.</li>
  <li>Sentosa Island: Great for a resort-style getaway with attractions like Universal Studios. Shangri-La’s Rasa Sentosa Resort &amp; Spa and Capella Singapore offer tranquility and luxury.</li>
  <li>City Hall: A central business district, suitable for business travelers. Raffles Hotel Singapore and The Capitol Kempinski Hotel are iconic choices.</li>
  <li>Bugis: Known for its eclectic mix of shopping, dining, and cultural experiences. Consider hotels like Andaz Singapore or InterContinental Singapore for a blend of luxury and local vibrancy.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="best-hotels-in-singapore-and-my-favourites-too">Best hotels in Singapore (and my favourites too)</h4>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>W Singapore - Sentosa Cove: A Whirlwind of Contemporary Glamour
Nestled in the exclusive enclave of Sentosa Cove, W Singapore invites guests on a journey of avant-garde design, breathtaking sea views, and the signature Whatever/Whenever service. This is not merely a stay; it’s an immersion into a realm of contemporary sophistication and unrivaled luxury, promising a transcendent experience.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>The Fullerton Hotel: Where Heritage Meets Grandeur
Housed within the majestic confines of a colonial-era architectural masterpiece, The Fullerton Hotel seamlessly blends timeless elegance with modern comfort. This iconic establishment, steeped in rich history, offers an unparalleled retreat, ensuring guests revel in impeccable service and panoramic views of the iconic Marina Bay.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Shangri-La’s Rasa Sentosa Resort &amp; Spa: Tropical Paradise on Sentosa Island
Venture to Sentosa Island’s verdant embrace, where Shangri-La’s Rasa Sentosa Resort &amp; Spa awaits. Surrounded by lush greenery and overlooking the azure South China Sea, this tropical oasis beckons with world-class amenities, gastronomic delights, and an ambiance that strikes the perfect balance between tranquility and adventure.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Capella Singapore: A Sanctuary of Serenity
Tucked away on Sentosa Island, Capella Singapore is the epitome of understated luxury. This exclusive resort, with its colonial architecture and modern sophistication, offers an intimate escape. From spacious villas to gourmet cuisine, every facet of Capella promises an indulgent experience where personalized service surpasses expectations.</p>
  </li>
  <li>JW Marriott Hotel Singapore South Beach: Urban Elegance in the Heart of the City
Situated in the bustling city center, JW Marriott Hotel Singapore South Beach stands as an architectural marvel, seamlessly blending historic charm with contemporary flair. This luxury establishment invites guests to partake in avant-garde design, innovative dining, and an ambiance crafted for an unparalleled urban experience.</li>
  <li>The Warehouse Hotel: A Stylish Blend of History and Modernity
Set against the backdrop of the Singapore River, The Warehouse Hotel resides in a meticulously restored heritage building. This boutique gem marries industrial-chic aesthetics with a commitment to sustainability, offering a unique journey into the city’s past. With thoughtfully curated spaces, it redefines boutique luxury for the modern traveler.</li>
</ul>

<p>Singapore’s hospitality landscape, adorned with these exceptional establishments, epitomizes the city’s commitment to providing unparalleled experiences. Whether seeking seaside tranquility, historical grandeur, or contemporary chic, these hotels promise an unforgettable sojourn in the Lion City. Indulge in the extraordinary, and let these remarkable establishments elevate your stay to new heights.</p>

<h4 id="how-to-snag-a-good-hotel-deal">How to snag a good hotel deal</h4>

<p>Snagging good hotel deals requires a bit of savvy and strategic planning. Here are some tips, including using corporate codes:
Comparison Sites: Use hotel comparison websites like Booking.com, Expedia, or Hotels.com to compare prices across various platforms.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Timing is Key: Book during off-peak seasons or last-minute for potential discounts. Hotels often drop prices to fill vacant rooms.</li>
  <li>Sign Up for Alerts: Subscribe to newsletters or set up price alerts on travel websites. They notify you when prices drop for your chosen hotels.</li>
  <li>Loyalty Programs: Join hotel loyalty programs. Members often get exclusive discounts, perks, or room upgrades.</li>
  <li>Corporate Codes: Perhaps the most important one. Some companies have corporate codes for hotel discounts. These can sometimes be found online through forums or by directly reaching out to the company’s HR department. Remember to read the terms and conditions carefully, and be cautious when using corporate codes to ensure compliance with hotel policies.
    <ul>
      <li>Bundle Deals: Consider booking flight and hotel together. Bundling can sometimes result in significant savings.</li>
      <li>Use Apps: Check hotel booking apps for exclusive mobile deals or app-only discounts.</li>
      <li>Flexible Dates: If your travel dates are flexible, use tools that show you the cheapest days to stay.</li>
      <li>Book Directly: Sometimes, hotels offer the best rates when you book directly through their websites. If other competitors are offering a cheaper price, call the hotel directly and ask for a price match or extra benefits. It always works</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>In Singapore, there’s an abundance of luxury hotels, and among them, the ones I’ve listed stand out as the finest. Whether it’s the sophisticated ambiance of W Hotel, the timeless elegance of Fullerton, the serene escape at Shangri-La Sentosa, the modern luxury of Capella, or the refined experience at JW Marriott and Warehouse Hotel, each offers a unique and exceptional stay. Good luck in your quest for the perfect hotel deal!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="hotels" /><category term="W" /><category term="Fullerton" /><category term="shangri-la" /><category term="Singapore" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the resplendent panorama of Singapore’s iconic skyline, a splendid tapestry of opulence and hospitality awaits the discerning traveler, promising an extraordinary sojourn like no other. Join us as we delve into the lap of luxury, exploring a curated selection of the city-state’s most exquisite hotels, each boasting its unique charm and allure. Oh, and learn more about how you can snag a great hotel deal.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/wroom.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/wroom.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">A Comprehensive Guide to Toast Box - Singapore’s breakfast heritage</title><link href="/singapore-breakfast-toastbox/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Comprehensive Guide to Toast Box - Singapore’s breakfast heritage" /><published>2023-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-breakfast-toastbox</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-breakfast-toastbox/"><![CDATA[<p>In the bustling food scene of Singapore, where the fusion of flavors and culinary diversity takes center stage, there’s a charming establishment that has been quietly preserving the essence of local breakfast culture since 2005 – Toast Box. Let’s take a delightful journey through the history and cultural impact of this beloved café, where tradition meets the aromatic allure of freshly brewed coffee. Then, I’ll reveal my go-to options at this establishment. Let’s get started.</p>

<h4 id="history-of-toast-box">History of toast box</h4>

<p>Conceived by the visionary minds at BreadTalk Group, Toast Box emerged with a mission to recreate the ambiance and flavors of the traditional kopitiams that were once the heartbeat of Singapore. Unlike Ya Kun / Yakun toast which started as a coffee stall in 1944, Toast Box is a more recent creation. The first Toast Box café opened its doors in 2005, breathing life into a concept that would soon become synonymous with nostalgic charm and authentic Singaporean breakfast. Well-played BreadTalk Group.
What sets Toast Box apart is its commitment to preserving the rich heritage of local coffee culture. Stepping into a Toast Box outlet is like stepping back in time, with its retro décor and the comforting aroma of freshly brewed coffee filling the air. The café’s design reflects the aesthetics of traditional kopitiams, creating a nostalgic haven for locals and a delightful discovery for tourists.</p>

<p>Fueled by the warmth of its kopi and the irresistible aroma of its toasts, Toast Box quickly gained popularity. Its success transcended the borders of Singapore, leading to international expansion. Today, Toast Box is not just a local gem but also an ambassador of Singaporean breakfast culture, with outlets in various international locations.
Toast Box has played a pivotal role in fostering an appreciation for Singapore’s coffee culture. It has become more than just a place to savor a cup of kopi; it’s a cultural touchstone where locals gather for a taste of tradition, and tourists seek an authentic experience.</p>

<p>While Toast Box remains deeply rooted in tradition, it has not shied away from evolution. The café has adapted to changing consumer preferences, introducing new menu items without compromising the authenticity that defines its identity. It strikes a delicate balance between preserving the past and embracing the present.</p>

<h4 id="lets-dive-into-some-of-toast-boxs-signatures">Let’s dive into some of Toast box’s signatures</h4>

<ol>
  <li>Kaya Toast: A Symphony of Simplicity
Let’s start our gastronomic expedition with the iconic Kaya Toast, a dish that embodies simplicity and flavor. The magic begins with perfectly toasted bread, generously layered with the heavenly combination of kaya (coconut and egg jam) and a velvety slab of butter. The result? A crispy, warm delight that hugs your senses and sets the perfect tone for the day.</li>
</ol>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/assets/images/kaya.jpg" alt="Kaya" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>Source - Classic Kaya business</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Laksa: A Bowlful of Singaporean Comfort
Venture into the realm of aromatic spices and rich coconut broth with Toast Box’s Laksa. This bowl of comfort features a harmonious blend of succulent prawns, flavorful noodles, and a broth that dances on your taste buds. It’s not just a dish; it’s an experience that transports you to the heart of Singaporean culinary warmth.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Nasi Lemak: An Ode to Local Flavors
For those craving a taste of local flair, the Nasi Lemak at Toast Box is a gastronomic masterpiece. Fragrant coconut rice, crispy anchovies, spicy sambal, and a perfectly fried egg – each element plays a role in creating a flavor symphony that celebrates the diverse and vibrant tapestry of Singaporean cuisine.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Teh Tarik: Liquid Gold for Your Palate
No visit to Toast Box is complete without indulging in Teh Tarik. This pulled milk tea, sweetened to perfection and adorned with frothy goodness, is liquid gold in a cup. It’s not just a beverage; it’s a comforting companion to your toasty adventures, providing a delightful balance to the array of flavors on your plate.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/assets/images/tt.jpg" alt="Teh" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>Source - Teh Tarik aka milk tea</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Curry Chicken with Rice:
Serving up a symphony of spices, Toast Box’s Curry Chicken with Rice is a culinary masterpiece that tantalizes the taste buds. This aromatic dish features tender chicken pieces bathed in a rich and flavorful curry sauce, served alongside fragrant jasmine rice. The robust blend of spices creates a delightful balance of heat and savory goodness, making it a comforting and hearty choice for those seeking a satisfying meal with a touch of spice.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Old School Hainanese Pork Chop:
Embark on a journey down memory lane with Toast Box’s Old School Hainanese Pork Chop. This classic dish pays homage to the culinary traditions of Hainanese cuisine, presenting succulent pork chops marinated to perfection and deep-fried to a golden crisp. Each bite is a delightful crunch of nostalgia, reminiscent of the beloved flavors from the past. Served with a side of fragrant rice, this dish is a testament to the enduring appeal of time-honored recipes.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Claypot Hokkien Prawn Mee:
For seafood enthusiasts, Toast Box introduces a delectable rendition of the iconic Claypot Hokkien Prawn Mee. This dish is a harmonious blend of thick yellow noodles, succulent prawns, and a rich, flavorful broth infused with the essence of the sea. Cooked to perfection in a claypot, the noodles absorb the savory goodness, creating a delightful medley of textures and tastes. With its hearty portions and tantalizing aroma, this dish is a celebration of Singapore’s culinary diversity and a must-try for those craving a seafood-infused delight.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/assets/images/prawn.jpg" alt="Claypot" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>Source - Hot in a pot</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>Toast box also serves desserts and Kopi (local Nanyang coffee). I’m not really into either so I can’t really comment on it. Whether you’re a seasoned foodie or a curious explorer, each dish at Toast Box tells a story, inviting you to be a part of the vibrant tapestry of Singaporean cuisine. Happy toasting, dear food connoisseurs! 🍞✨</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="food" /><category term="restaurants" /><category term="cuisine" /><category term="Singapore" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the bustling food scene of Singapore, where the fusion of flavors and culinary diversity takes center stage, there’s a charming establishment that has been quietly preserving the essence of local breakfast culture since 2005 – Toast Box. Let’s take a delightful journey through the history and cultural impact of this beloved café, where tradition meets the aromatic allure of freshly brewed coffee. Then, I’ll reveal my go-to options at this establishment. Let’s get started.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/tbtb.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/tbtb.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Top restaurants in Singapore by cuisine</title><link href="/singapore-top-restaurants-by-cuisine/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Top restaurants in Singapore by cuisine" /><published>2023-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-top-restaurants-by-cuisine</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-top-restaurants-by-cuisine/"><![CDATA[<p>Lately, I’ve been receiving numerous questions about the culinary scene in Singapore and my favorite go-to restaurants. I’ve always considered myself someone with a refined palate, and I’ve never quite found satisfaction in the recommendations from Google Maps, local Singaporeans, or local food blogs and YouTube channels. Therefore, I’ve made the decision to curate my own list for all you epicureans out there.</p>

<h4 id="some-ground-rules">Some ground rules</h4>

<p>As a reminder, this isn’t a fine dining list for 2 reasons - 1) it’s quite challenging to categorize the types of cuisine it covers, and 2) fine dining is never really a go-to option for food for anyone. I’ll share my list of fine dining recommendations at a later day. Additionally, we’ll exclude ‘Singaporean cuisine’ from this list as it deserves its own spotlight at another time. For certain cuisines, I don’t have a go-to choice as I don’t often have cravings for them. This includes Indian, Peranakan, Mala, etc., so they will also be omitted. These recommendations span across various price points. Keep in mind that this is my personal go-to list when I have specific cravings for a particular cuisine. If you have any recommendations, feel free to share them with me! I’d love to know your go-to places as well.</p>

<h5 id="western">Western</h5>

<p><u>Italian<u></u></u></p>

<p>Many italian restaurants are across the island. Most are tasty but way over price. Below are the ones that I find are value</p>

<ul>
  <li>No Menu ($$$): Experience authentic Italian cuisine complemented by excellent service and ambiance. True to its name, you can request dishes not listed on the menu. I personally recommend trying their seafood risotto and lobster ravioli.</li>
  <li>Publico ($$): A vibrant al fresco restaurant situated in the heart of Robertson Quay, perfect for brunch enthusiasts. I’m a fan of their shakshuka and pasta dishes. It’s an ideal spot for a mid-day drink.</li>
  <li>Pasta Bar ($$$): Indulge in high-quality, fresh pasta dishes in the heart of the city. This is my top choice for seafood pasta in Singapore, thanks to their exceptionally fresh ingredients and al dente pasta</li>
  <li>Ristorante Takada ($$$): Italian Japanese fusion. High value</li>
</ul>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/assets/images/pasta.jpg" alt="pasta" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>Ristorante Takada’s signature uni pasta - incredible umami</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p><u>Mediterranean<u></u></u></p>

<p>Mediterranean is not the most common in Singapore but for the establishments below, they execute on their respective dishes well.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Blu Kouzina ($$$): Renowned Mediterranean restaurant in Singapore known for its authentic dishes inspired by Greece, Turkey, and Lebanon. They emphasize high-quality ingredients sourced from Greece, offering a warm and inviting dining experience. I love their EVOO (extra virgin olive oil) - it’s pretty much on every dish. Order their baked halloumi cheese too - it’s divine</li>
  <li>Bakalaki Greek Taverna ($$$): Less of a vibe compared to Blu Kouzina, but serves up incredible gyros and souvlakis</li>
</ul>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/assets/images/greek.jpg" alt="greek" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>Feta salad with EVOO - an evergreen classic</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p><u>Spanish<u></u></u></p>

<p>Similar to Mediterranean cuisine, Spanish food isn’t common in Singapore. The two below are absolute standouts for me.</p>

<ul>
  <li>FOC ($$$): One’s in sentosa whilst the other’s near boat quay. Master of the Josper grill. Try their Iberian pork jowl and the Josper grilled spanish octopus. Their desserts are not to be discounted.</li>
  <li>Olivia ($$$): Known for their blue cheese basque cheesecake and croquettes. Intimate and straight to the point Spanish food that transports you back to Barcelona</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Burgers<u></u></u></p>

<p>There are plenty of burger places in Singapore including popular chains. Shake shack has to be a shout out here because it is decent.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Honbo ($$): Originally from Hong Kong and recently opened in Singapore. They serve up amazing smash patties with a fluffy potato milk bun, with their Double Gold American beef coming from Wisconsin</li>
  <li>Three buns ($$): As a part of the Potato Head Club, Three Buns is a popular burger joint known for its creative and delicious beef burgers. While it may not be the most budget-friendly option, the indulgent and delectable offerings make it a worthwhile culinary experience</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Steakhouse<u></u></u></p>

<p>Multiple restaurants serve steak in Singapore, but not a lot of them are steakhouses. I wouldn’t exactly call Burnt Ends a steakhouse given it does have a michelin star and is more relevated, but their steak is a definite highlight.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Burnt ends (\(\)): Famous for its wood-fired cooking techniques and innovative dishes. Their signature item, the Burnt Ends Sanger, is a must-try—a flavorful sandwich featuring smoked meats and homemade pickles, served on a potato roll. Order a steak even if it’s expensive. Don’t bother with their bakery</li>
  <li>Wolfgangs (\(\)): The best steakhouse I’ve been that’s not in South America. Incredibly pricey but their steaks are perfectly charred and grilled. Portions are extremely generous. A perfect pick for a marquee celebration</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Pizza<u></u></u></p>

<p>Singapore’s pizza scene is slowly growing, with a mix of American and Italian chains popping up.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Wild Child ($$): One of the best Neapolitan pizzas in Singapore. The dough is fluffy with a gorgeous amount of chewiness, complemented by quality ingredients. It’s known for its signature crack sauce that adds a burst of flavour to every pizza.</li>
  <li>Extra Virgin Pizza ($$): Less of a vibe than Wild Child, but there’s no doubt that their pizzas are divine. Their crusts are always beautifully charred and their innovative toppings amalgamate finely with the base</li>
</ul>

<h5 id="asian">Asian</h5>

<p><u>Taiwanese<u></u></u></p>

<p>There are quite a few Taiwanese-style restaurants, but not a lot of authentic Taiwanese food that is at the price point that it should be in.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Isshin Machi ($$): My go-to Taiwanese restaurant in Singapore is Isshin Machi, with multiple locations across the island. I particularly adore their pork chop fried rice (which gives Din Tai Fung a run for its money) and their refreshing winter melon tea (not to sweet, just mellow)</li>
  <li>Abundance ($$): My old neighbourhood haunt that is massively underrated. Their gua baos, dumplings and bacon cabbage make for a perfect late night meal</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Cantonese / Dim sum<u></u></u></p>

<p>Hailing from Hong Kong, there is a long list of restaurants / dining establishments I default to. One I have to shout out is Canton Paradise. Those chain stores are decent. More on specific dim sum options in <a href="https://fromhktosg.github.io/dimsum/">my previous article</a>.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Legendary HK ($$): My default cha chaan teng. Huge variety of options, authentic cantonese flavours and very affordable. Their congee is divine and fluffy unlike Singaporean / Taiwanese congee</li>
  <li>So good ($$): So good has a couple of chains across the island, and whilst I prefer Legendary as my #1 cantonese haunt, So Good comes in as a close second. I’m a sucker for their breakfast and afternoon tea</li>
  <li>Wah lok: ($$) Best dim sum in SG. They don’t skimp on the ingredients, so expect plump siu mais and shrimp dumplings. Great value for money given the restaurant is situated at the Carlton hotel</li>
  <li>Fook kin ($$): Best cantonese roast that’s not fine dining or a preppy cantonese restaurant. Not 100% authentic cantonese cha siu (more of a malaysian style instead) but does a terrific job in delivering charred, tender roast meat</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Japanese<u></u></u></p>

<p>This is a weird one. There are plenty of fantastic japanese restaurants in Singapore at all price points. Unlike other cuisines, I can’t bring myself to eat high end Japanese food in Singapore as they are too criminally priced. Hence, the below are some of my more comfortable options.</p>

<p>The sushi bar: My go-to for chirashi bowls. The Sushi bar serves up generous portions at a very respectable price point. Feel free to ask them to swap out specific cuts of fish if you prefer others - I always ask for more Salmon instead of swordfish
Omote: Similar to the Sushi Bar, Omote serves up comfort japanese food. They have a branch in City Hall now so if I’m near there versus Orchard where The Sushi Bar is, I’ll pop in for a meal
Sushiro: ‘Fun’ conveyor belt sushi. Don’t hate on my recommendation but Sushiro is delightfully pleasant, with a frequent rotating menu to highlight seasonal cuts
Brothers ramen: A dining hall for many Japanese expats in Singapore. I love how clean their broth is and their ramen has the perfect amount of spring in it</p>

<p><u>Korean<u></u></u></p>

<p>There are plenty of korean food places along the Tanjong Pagar stretch, and they are all of impressive qualities. To highlight a few -</p>

<ul>
  <li>Wang dae bak: Korean BBQ masterclass on top of a traditional grill. Book ahead of time as it always get filled</li>
  <li>SBCD tofu house: For hearty Sundubu jigae. Their tofu is made-in-house and is simple yet delicious</li>
  <li>Obba Jajang: MY go-to for jjajangmyeon and jjampong. Their banchan is average but I love their noodles (springy, chewy, slurpy)</li>
  <li>Magal: Versatile restaurant, with delicious BBQ options as well as jigaes (stew). Don’t skip out on their cockles rice and their gamjatang (pork bone stew)</li>
</ul>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/assets/images/korean.jpg" alt="obba" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>Obba Jajang’s signature Jjampong and jjangmyeon. Yum</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>Singapore’s a culinary haven with lots of options. I hope my go-tos help you narrow down on food establishments that are of the best value. Let me know what your go-tos are - I’d love to shore up my list.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="food" /><category term="restaurants" /><category term="cuisine" /><category term="Singapore" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lately, I’ve been receiving numerous questions about the culinary scene in Singapore and my favorite go-to restaurants. I’ve always considered myself someone with a refined palate, and I’ve never quite found satisfaction in the recommendations from Google Maps, local Singaporeans, or local food blogs and YouTube channels. Therefore, I’ve made the decision to curate my own list for all you epicureans out there.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/korean.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/korean.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Complete guide to the best online grocery shopping in Singapore</title><link href="/singapore-online-groceries/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Complete guide to the best online grocery shopping in Singapore" /><published>2023-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-online-groceries</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-online-groceries/"><![CDATA[<p>In my previous post, we delved into the world of Singapore’s finest grocery stores and supermarkets. But let’s face it, in this age of technological marvels, even the simplest tasks have evolved. Many of us have embraced the convenience of online grocery shopping, making our lives even more hassle-free. Let’s embark on a journey to uncover the top online grocery options that Singapore has to offer for all us lazy people.</p>

<h4 id="why-shop-for-groceries-online">Why shop for groceries online?</h4>

<p>TL;DR - we’re lazy. To expand -</p>
<ul>
  <li>Convenience: Shop from the comfort of your home, avoiding the need to travel to physical stores, stand in lines, or carry heavy bags. Many online grocery stores operate 24/7, providing the flexibility to shop whenever it’s most convenient for you, whether that’s early in the morning or late at night</li>
  <li>Time-saving: Quickly browse and select items, eliminating the need for a time-consuming trip to the store</li>
  <li>Price comparison: Compare prices easily across different brands and products, helping you find the best deals and discounts</li>
  <li>Subscription services: Schedule recurring deliveries for essential items, ensuring you never run out of household staples</li>
  <li>Detailed product information: Online platforms provide detailed product descriptions and customer reviews, helping you make informed decisions about the products you purchase</li>
  <li>Reduced Impulse Buying: Shopping online can help you stick to your shopping list and avoid impulse purchases, ultimately saving you money</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="are-prices-better-online">Are prices better online?</h4>

<p>Yes and no. It really depends on the quantity of goods you are purchasing. Online platforms usually have discount codes and incentivize bulk buying. However, you have to factor in whether delivery fees are high (if not waived at all).</p>

<h4 id="cons-of-online-grocery-shopping">Cons of online grocery shopping</h4>

<ul>
  <li>Grocery shopping is a lifestyle: To some, grocery shopping in stores is a borderline hobby. It is for me at least. I love visiting grocery stores to see what latest products are being featured. Shopping online just isn’t the same</li>
  <li>Delivery Fees: Many online grocery platforms charge delivery fees, which can vary based on factors like the order amount, delivery time, and location. You should factor in these fees when comparing prices.</li>
  <li>Minimum Order Requirements: Some online grocery stores may require a minimum order amount to qualify for free or reduced delivery fees. Be sure to check the terms and conditions.</li>
  <li>Quality and Freshness: Some individuals prefer to select their own fresh produce and items with a specific expiration date in physical stores to ensure quality. When shopping online, you are relying on the shopper’s judgment.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="what-are-the-delivery-options">What are the delivery options?</h4>

<p>Let’s take a look at the top 3 grocers in Singapore - Fairprice, Sheng Shiong and Cold Storage.</p>

<p><u>FairPrice Online<u></u></u></p>
<ul>
  <li>Same-Day Delivery: FairPrice Online offers same-day delivery for orders placed before a specified cutoff time. This allows you to receive your groceries on the same day you place your order</li>
  <li>Next-Day Delivery: Next-day delivery is also available, giving you the convenience of receiving your groceries the day after you place your order</li>
  <li>Scheduled Time Slots: FairPrice Online provides a range of delivery time slots throughout the day, allowing you to select a convenient time for your delivery</li>
  <li>Weekend and Evening Delivery: You can schedule weekend and evening deliveries to fit your schedule, making it ideal for those with busy weekday routines</li>
  <li>Subscription Services: FairPrice Online offers subscription options, allowing you to set up regular deliveries based on your preferred frequency, such as weekly or monthly</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Sheng Siong Online<u></u></u></p>
<ul>
  <li>Next-Day Delivery: Sheng Siong Online typically offers next-day delivery for orders placed before a specific cutoff time. This means you can place an order one day and receive it the following day</li>
  <li>Scheduled Time Slots: You can choose from various delivery time slots when placing your order, including morning, afternoon, and evening options</li>
  <li>Weekend Delivery: Sheng Siong Online provides weekend delivery slots, which can be convenient for those who prefer receiving groceries on Saturdays or Sundays</li>
  <li>Express Delivery: Sheng Siong also offers an express delivery option, allowing you to receive your groceries within a shorter time frame for an additional fee</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Cold Storage Online<u></u></u></p>
<ul>
  <li>Same-Day Delivery: Cold Storage Online offers same-day delivery for orders placed before a specified cutoff time, allowing you to receive your groceries on the same day</li>
  <li>Next-Day Delivery: Next-day delivery is available for orders placed in advance, ensuring your groceries arrive promptly the next day</li>
  <li>Scheduled Time Slots: You can select a preferred delivery time slot that suits your schedule, including options for mornings, afternoons, and evenings</li>
  <li>Weekend and Evening Delivery: Cold Storage Online provides weekend and evening delivery slots for added convenience</li>
  <li>Express Delivery: Cold Storage offers express delivery options for those who need groceries urgently, with faster delivery times</li>
</ul>

<p>Same same, but different</p>

<h4 id="top-online-grocers">Top online grocers</h4>

<p>As to nobody’s surprise, all the popular supermarkets and grocers in Singapore have an online presence.</p>

<h5 id="redmart-by-lazada">RedMart (by Lazada)</h5>
<ul>
  <li>Pioneer in Online Grocery: RedMart is a household name in Singapore, known for being one of the earliest players in the online grocery shopping scene</li>
  <li>Wide Selection: It boasts an extensive range of products, including fresh produce, pantry staples, household items, and more</li>
  <li>Convenience: RedMart’s user-friendly platform and reliable delivery service make it a convenient choice for busy individuals and families</li>
</ul>

<h5 id="fairprice-online">FairPrice Online</h5>
<ul>
  <li>Trusted Supermarket Brand: FairPrice is a well-established supermarket chain in Singapore</li>
  <li>One-Stop Shop: FairPrice Online allows customers to conveniently shop for groceries and household essentials</li>
  <li>Accessibility: The platform offers a familiar shopping experience for those who prefer a trusted brand</li>
</ul>

<h5 id="amazon-fresh-by-amazon">Amazon Fresh (by Amazon)</h5>
<ul>
  <li>Global E-commerce Giant: Amazon Fresh offers a variety of groceries and fresh produce for delivery in Singapore</li>
  <li>Amazon Prime Perks: Amazon Prime members can enjoy added convenience with access to this service</li>
  <li>Diverse Selection: Amazon’s vast product range ensures you can find just about anything you need</li>
</ul>

<h5 id="shopee-mart-by-shopee">Shopee Mart (by Shopee)</h5>
<ul>
  <li>E-commerce Convenience: Shopee Mart is the grocery arm of Shopee, one of Singapore’s popular e-commerce platforms</li>
  <li>Promotions and Discounts: Shopee Mart often runs promotions and discounts, making it an attractive choice for budget-conscious shoppers</li>
  <li>Variety: The platform provides a diverse selection of groceries to cater to various preferences</li>
</ul>

<h5 id="cold-storage-online">Cold Storage Online</h5>
<ul>
  <li>Premium Selection: Cold Storage is a premium supermarket chain in Singapore, and its online platform reflects its commitment to quality</li>
  <li>Imported and Specialty Products: It offers a wide range of imported and specialty items, making it perfect for those with specific tastes</li>
</ul>

<h5 id="giant-online">Giant Online</h5>
<ul>
  <li>Convenient Shopping: Giant is another well-known supermarket chain in Singapore</li>
  <li>Online Ease: Giant Online allows customers to shop for groceries and household items from the comfort of their homes</li>
  <li>Trustworthiness: Giant’s reputation for quality carries over to its online platform</li>
</ul>

<h5 id="opentaste">OpenTaste</h5>
<ul>
  <li>Farm-to-Table Experience: OpenTaste focuses on providing fresh produce and premium groceries directly from farms and suppliers</li>
  <li>Unique Offerings: It often features unique and hard-to-find items, making it a favorite for adventurous foodies</li>
</ul>

<h5 id="little-farms">Little Farms</h5>
<ul>
  <li>Quality and Freshness: Little Farms specializes in fresh, high-quality produce, dairy, meats, and other groceries</li>
  <li>Health-Conscious Choices: They cater to health-conscious consumers looking for wholesome options
Farm-to-Table Commitment: Little Farms offers a farm-to-table experience that many shoppers appreciate</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="what-about-chinese--japanese-grocers">What about Chinese / Japanese grocers?</h4>

<p>Here’s where things get interesting. There are plenty of boutique grocers that deliver! Some own their own delivery platforms / operations, whilst others rely on popular e-commerce sites in town.</p>

<p><u>Japanese<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>Don Don Don Ki
Don don don Ki doesn’t cater their own ecommerce site. However, they do have an official store presence on 3rd party e-commerce sites like Shopee</li>
</ul>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/assets/images/online.jpg" alt="DDDK" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>Source - Example Don Don Don Ki ecommerce store</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<ul>
  <li>Oishii Mart
Oishii Mart is a Japanese online grocery store that focuses on bringing authentic Japanese products to Singapore. They offer a variety of Japanese snacks, beverages, ingredients, and more</li>
  <li>Isetan Online
Isetan is a well-known Japanese department store in Singapore. They have an online platform that includes a selection of Japanese groceries and products for delivery</li>
  <li>Meidi-Ya
Meidi-Ya is another Japanese department store with a presence in Singapore. They offer Japanese groceries, fresh produce, snacks, and more through their online store</li>
  <li>Sakuraya: Sakuraya specializes in Japanese seafood and offers an online platform where you can order fresh Japanese seafood and related products</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Chinese<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Scarlett
Similar to Don Don Don Ki, Scarlett has an official store presence on 3rd party ecommerce sites.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Yue Hwa
Yue Hwa, a well-known Chinese department store in Singapore, primarily focuses on selling Chinese cultural and traditional products, including gifts, clothing, and home goods. They’ve now expanded their offerings to online delivery. All orders are delivered by Yue Hwa’s in-house delivery service team.  Delivery is available daily from 11am to 6pm, except Public Holidays.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Hao mart
​​Hao Mart: While not exclusively Chinese, Hao Mart is known for its extensive selection of Asian groceries, including Chinese items. They have both physical stores and an online platform for convenient shopping</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>Personally, I’ve tried delivery for all three and they work swell.</p>

<p>To wrap things up, online grocery shopping offers unmatched convenience and an extensive range of options, streamlining our busy lives. However, the in-store experience remains a unique and irreplaceable aspect of grocery shopping. It allows us to explore new products, relish the sensory pleasures of selecting fresh produce, and connect with food on a personal level. So, while we embrace the modern ease of online grocery shopping, let’s not forget the timeless joy of strolling through physical stores to bask in the beauty of our food shopping journey. Thanks for reading this post! Don’t forget to subscribe to see more content like this.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="online shopping" /><category term="shopping" /><category term="grocery" /><category term="Singapore" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In my previous post, we delved into the world of Singapore’s finest grocery stores and supermarkets. But let’s face it, in this age of technological marvels, even the simplest tasks have evolved. Many of us have embraced the convenience of online grocery shopping, making our lives even more hassle-free. Let’s embark on a journey to uncover the top online grocery options that Singapore has to offer for all us lazy people.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/butter.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/butter.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Wedding 101: How to avoid wedding photo scams</title><link href="/singapore-wedding-photos/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wedding 101: How to avoid wedding photo scams" /><published>2023-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-wedding-photos</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-wedding-photos/"><![CDATA[<p>In recent years, the institution of marriage has undergone significant changes in Singapore, reflecting shifting societal values, economic factors, and individual choices. While marriage remains a vital aspect of Singaporean culture, it’s worth examining the trends and factors that have shaped the current landscape. Heads-up, marriage is not for everyone. Some even think it’s a scam. This isn’t an article about why you should or should not get married. By all means, do whatever that works for you. However, we will discuss how marriage has been shifting in Singapore, as well as what you should look out for when taking your wedding photos. In that regard, we are here to make sure you don’t get scammed by pesky wedding photographers.</p>

<h4 id="lets-begin-with-the-shifts-in-the-marriage-landscape">Let’s begin with the shifts in the marriage landscape</h4>

<p>There has been a changing attitude towards marriage in Singapore, Marriage has traditionally been viewed as a significant life milestone in Singapore, often symbolizing stability and commitment. However, contemporary attitudes towards marriage have evolved. Many young Singaporeans are choosing to delay marriage to focus on their careers, personal growth, and financial stability. The emphasis is now on marrying for love and compatibility rather than societal expectations. Some beginning thoughts on what else is driving the shift and other phenomena that have arose from this -</p>

<ul>
  <li>Declining marriage rates: Singapore has witnessed a decline in marriage rates over the past decade. Factors such as increasing educational attainment, financial independence, and changing gender roles have contributed to this trend. People are prioritizing higher education and career advancement before considering marriage, resulting in later unions</li>
  <li>Cohabitation and unmarried parenthood: Cohabitation is becoming increasingly common in Singapore. Couples are choosing to live together and build their lives before formalizing their relationships through marriage. Additionally, the stigma surrounding unmarried parenthood has diminished, with more couples choosing to start families without traditional marriage</li>
  <li>Rising age at first marriage:The average age at which Singaporeans get married has risen steadily. Many are tying the knot in their late twenties or early thirties, compared to earlier generations who often married in their early twenties. This shift is driven by the pursuit of personal goals and financial stability before taking on the responsibilities of marriage</li>
  <li>Multicultural marriages: Singapore’s multicultural society has led to an increase in intercultural and cross-border marriages. Couples from different cultural backgrounds or nationalities are coming together, enriching the country’s cultural tapestry. These marriages often involve navigating unique challenges, such as cultural differences and immigration processes
Government initiatives: The Singaporean government has recognized the evolving dynamics of marriage and family life. Policies and initiatives, such as the Marriage and Parenthood Package, aim to support couples in building strong families. These initiatives include financial incentives, parental leave, and flexible work arrangements to encourage marriage and parenthood</li>
  <li>Embracing diversity: Singapore’s evolving attitudes towards marriage reflect a broader global trend of embracing diversity in relationships and family structures. While traditional marriages remain essential, the country’s openness to various relationship choices (although LGBT marriages are still not recognized) reflects a more inclusive and accepting society.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="should-i-have-a-wedding-or-should-i-just-rom">Should I have a wedding or should I just ROM?</h4>

<p>This is an increasingly common question amongst the younger generation. ROM stands for registration of marriage (aka signing  marriage papers). For those who have a wedding, most ROM during the wedding though some ROM prior the wedding itself. There are several reasons why an increasing number of people in Singapore are opting not to have traditional weddings and just opting for ROM:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Cost: Weddings are expensive. Many couples find that the cost of hosting a wedding, which includes venue rental, catering, decor, and other expenses, can be a significant financial burden. As a result, some couples choose to allocate their resources differently, perhaps for a house, travel, or other financial goals</li>
  <li>Lifestyle choices: Some couples prefer to embrace a simpler and more minimalist lifestyle. They may opt for smaller, more intimate gatherings or choose alternative ways to celebrate their union that align with their values. Smaller, intimate gatherings with close family and friends are becoming increasingly popular. Couples often find that these smaller events are more meaningful and allow for deeper connections with their loved ones.</li>
  <li>Parents have less say: Parents have less influence nowadays when it comes to weddings. Weddings have traditionally been an occasion for parents to showcase and brag about their children. However, with a gradual decline in parental control over their offspring and more relaxed expectations regarding filial piety, parents find themselves with diminishing authority in orchestrating elaborate weddings</li>
  <li>Time Constraints: Planning a traditional wedding can be a time-consuming endeavor. In today’s fast-paced world, with demanding work schedules and various commitments, couples often find themselves strapped for time when it comes to organizing and carrying out a wedding. This situation often prompts them to opt for simpler alternatives. I’ve heard from numerous friends who, in hindsight, express a desire for a smaller-scale wedding or even forgo the idea of a wedding altogether. The stress associated with wedding planning, they recount, detracted from their ability to fully enjoy their own special day</li>
  <li>Cultural Shifts: Changing cultural norms and values can influence marriage choices. As societal attitudes evolve, there is less pressure to conform to traditional wedding expectations, allowing couples more flexibility in how they choose to celebrate their union</li>
  <li>COVID-19 Pandemic: The COVID-19 pandemic has disrupted wedding plans for many couples. Restrictions on gatherings and health concerns have led some to postpone or downsize their weddings, while others have chosen to have small, intimate ceremonies. COVID officially showed the world that smaller weddings are ok!</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="whats-the-deal-with-destination-weddings">What’s the deal with destination weddings?</h4>

<p>Singaporeans often choose beautiful and picturesque destinations for their destination weddings. Here’s why you would do one:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Scenic and unique locations: Destination weddings allow couples to tie the knot in picturesque and unique settings. From beachfront ceremonies to historic castles or tropical islands, the choice of location can be stunning and unforgettable</li>
  <li>Intimate gatherings: Many couples prefer smaller, more intimate weddings with only close family and friends. Destination weddings naturally limit the guest list, creating a more personal and meaningful experience. Don’t like an aunt or uncle? A destination wedding helps resolve this</li>
  <li>Built-In Honeymoon: Destination weddings often double as a honeymoon. Couples can seamlessly transition from the wedding festivities to their honeymoon, saving both time and money</li>
  <li>Neutral location: If the couple comes from different cultural backgrounds or has family in different locations, a destination wedding can be a way to bring everyone together and celebrate in a neutral location</li>
  <li>Reduced Stress: Destination wedding packages offered by resorts and venues often include wedding planning services. This can significantly reduce the stress associated with planning a traditional wedding</li>
  <li>Cost-Effective: In some cases, destination weddings can be more cost-effective than traditional weddings, especially when considering guest numbers and all-inclusive packages</li>
  <li>Symbolic Locations: Sometimes, couples choose a destination with personal significance, such as where they met or a place they’ve always dreamed of visiting</li>
</ul>

<p>Here are some popular destination wedding locations favored by couples from Singapore:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Bali, Indonesia: Bali is a top choice for destination weddings due to its stunning beaches, lush landscapes, and vibrant culture. Couples can exchange vows overlooking the Indian Ocean or in lush tropical gardens. Bali offers a range of wedding venues, from luxury resorts to private villas</li>
  <li>Phuket, Thailand: Phuket’s pristine beaches, crystal-clear waters, and luxurious resorts make it a sought-after destination for  weddings. Couples can have a beachfront ceremony or choose from numerous scenic venues. Thailand’s warm hospitality and exotic charm add to the appeal</li>
  <li>Santorini, Greece: Santorini’s iconic white-washed buildings, dramatic cliffs, and breathtaking sunsets create a romantic backdrop for weddings. Many couples opt for intimate ceremonies overlooking the caldera or in charming chapels</li>
  <li>Maldives: The Maldives offers a dreamy setting for beachfront weddings. Overwater bungalows, turquoise waters, and coral reefs make it a paradise for couples seeking a romantic escape and a unique wedding experience. Of course, it’s extremely expensive too</li>
  <li>Da Nang, Vietnam: A top choice given its proximity to Singapore alongside a good value for money. You’ll get amazing food and beaches similar to Bali, at a better cost</li>
</ul>

<p>These destination wedding locations offer a blend of natural beauty, cultural richness, and romantic charm, making them popular choices for couples looking to create memorable and unique wedding experiences. Keep in mind that wedding planning for international destinations may involve additional logistical considerations, so it’s essential to plan ahead. I’ve been to weddings in Indonesia, Vietnam and Korea. They were all gorgeous in their own way.</p>

<h4 id="why-are-wedding-photos-so-expensive-in-singapore">Why are wedding photos so expensive in Singapore?</h4>

<p>Wedding photographs play an integral role in capturing the essence of the wedding experience. Different individuals opt for various approaches when it comes to photography. Some arrange pre-wedding photoshoots, while others focus on capturing moments on the wedding day itself. Some even choose to document their post-wedding moments. Moreover, there are options for both indoor and outdoor photoshoots, catering to individual preferences. Remarkably, the field of wedding photography has evolved into a thriving industry.</p>

<p>Wedding photography in Singapore can be relatively expensive for several reasons, and some couples opt to have their wedding photos taken abroad for cost savings and unique experiences. Let me tell you - this is the way to go. Here’s why wedding photography in Singapore can be costly and why couples consider overseas options:</p>
<ul>
  <li>High Cost of Living: Singapore is known for its high cost of living, which affects various services, including wedding photography. Photographers have to cover their living expenses, equipment costs, and other overheads, leading to higher rates. This is the main reason</li>
  <li>Demand and Competition: Singapore’s wedding industry is highly competitive, with many couples vying for the best services. High demand often leads to photographers charging premium rates for their services. I would say not all photographers are quality, but given the limited supply in Singapore, rates are boosted up</li>
  <li>Customization and Packages: Photographers often offer customizable packages to meet the unique needs of each couple. These packages may include engagement sessions, pre-wedding shoots, and various album options, adding to the overall cost. Guess what? Singaporeans are needy. From the photographers I have spoken with, many said that Singaporean couples ask for more customizations versus couples of other backgrounds</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="how-do-you-avoid-wedding-photo-traps">How do you avoid wedding photo traps?</h4>

<p>Wedding photography selection can be distressing and financially damaging. The industry is filled with red flags and predatory sales tactics. Here are some wedding photo scams to watch out for:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Bait-and-Switch: A photographer showcases impressive work online, but when hired, provides subpar quality photos. They may even send a different photographer to the wedding</li>
  <li>Payment Upfront: Scammers may insist on full payment or a significant deposit before the wedding day, then disappear or provide substandard services. Legitimate photographers typically require a deposit, but be cautious if the request seems excessive</li>
  <li>No Contract: A reputable photographer will always provide a detailed contract outlining services, pricing, and terms. Avoid photographers who refuse to provide or sign a contract</li>
  <li>Hidden Fees and Payment Methods: The biggest one to watch out for. Some dishonest photographers may lure clients with seemingly low upfront prices but later add hidden fees for services like editing, album creation, buying ampoules or extra hours. Be sure to clarify all potential additional costs upfront and include them in the contract to avoid surprises</li>
  <li>Payment Methods: Scammers might encourage cash payments to avoid leaving a financial trail. This can be risky because it makes it difficult to track and dispute payments if there are issues with the service. Always choose secure payment methods like credit cards, checks, or online transfers, which provide records and some level of protection against fraud</li>
  <li>Individual Photo Sales: Be cautious if the photographer insists on selling individual photos separately after the event. This can result in significantly higher costs than initially quoted. Ideally, your contract should include all agreed-upon services and the delivery of a complete set of edited photos</li>
  <li>Pressure Sales Tactics: Be wary of photographers who use high-pressure sales tactics or make unrealistic promises to secure your business</li>
  <li>Limited-Time Offers: Promising exclusive discounts or offers that are only available if you make an immediate decision</li>
</ul>

<p>Artiz Studio serves as a quintessential example of a questionable business practice. The studio lacks price transparency, often springing additional photo costs on unsuspecting customers. Their sales tactics can be aggressive, employing hard-sell techniques, and sometimes resorting to demeaning competitors. They heavily promote a supposed “Korean vibe” while concealing hidden costs that can catch customers off guard. They initially presented a price but later informed us of limited-time packages that required an immediate decision on that same day. While the photography displayed in this studio appeared beautiful, their aggressive sales tactics discouraged us from considering further transactions with them. It is advisable to steer clear of this establishment. It’s worth noting that several other photography studios employ similar practices, so it’s essential to be prepared for their direct approach.</p>

<p>To avoid falling victim to wedding photo scams:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Research photographers thoroughly, read reviews, and ask for references</li>
  <li>Meet with potential photographers in person or via video call to assess their professionalism</li>
  <li>Request a detailed contract that outlines all services, fees, and terms</li>
  <li>Pay using secure methods, such as credit cards, which offer some protection against fraud</li>
  <li>Trust your instincts. If something doesn’t feel right, consider other options. Cross-reference online in all review sites and social media platforms. People will speak up if they feel their experience was subpar</li>
</ul>

<p>It’s crucial to exercise caution and due diligence when hiring a wedding photographer to ensure that your special day is captured beautifully and without any unpleasant surprises.</p>

<p>And that’s a wrap! I hope you enjoyed this article. It means a lot to me to help you avoid falling into these wedding photo scams. Don’t forget to subscribe to see more content like this.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="wedding" /><category term="wedding photos" /><category term="marriage" /><category term="Singapore" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In recent years, the institution of marriage has undergone significant changes in Singapore, reflecting shifting societal values, economic factors, and individual choices. While marriage remains a vital aspect of Singaporean culture, it’s worth examining the trends and factors that have shaped the current landscape. Heads-up, marriage is not for everyone. Some even think it’s a scam. This isn’t an article about why you should or should not get married. By all means, do whatever that works for you. However, we will discuss how marriage has been shifting in Singapore, as well as what you should look out for when taking your wedding photos. In that regard, we are here to make sure you don’t get scammed by pesky wedding photographers.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/wedding.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/wedding.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>