<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2025-02-18T13:16:12+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">From HK to SG</title><entry><title type="html">Breathwork in Singapore: Boost Health &amp;amp; Focus with Proper Breathing</title><link href="/singapore-breathing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Breathwork in Singapore: Boost Health &amp;amp; Focus with Proper Breathing" /><published>2025-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-breathing</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-breathing/"><![CDATA[<p>Are we breathing properly in Singapore and should you practice breathwork?</p>

<p>Given the humid weather, air-conditioned offices, and occasional haze, you’d think we’d have mastered the art of inhaling and exhaling by now. But breathwork—yes, that’s a thing—goes beyond just surviving the MRT rush hour. Unlike meditation, which focuses on mindfulness, breathwork actively trains your lungs to work smarter, not harder. If ice baths aren’t your thing but you’re still looking for a way to boost energy and reduce stress, maybe it’s time to try controlling your breath instead. From relaxation to better focus, breathing might just be the wellness hack you didn’t know you needed—so let’s take a deep breath and explore.</p>

<h3 id="why-is-the-breath-so-important">Why is the breath so important?</h3>

<p>Breathing isn’t just about staying alive—it’s the key to better energy, mental clarity, and overall health. Science shows that deep diaphragmatic breathing activates the parasympathetic nervous system, reducing cortisol levels and lowering stress. On the flip side, shallow chest breathing—something many Singaporeans do unconsciously due to long hours at desks and high humidity—can trigger the body’s fight-or-flight response, increasing anxiety and fatigue. Proper breathwork improves oxygen exchange, enhances lung capacity, and even boosts athletic endurance by increasing CO2 tolerance. If you’re looking for an easy, science-backed way to feel better, optimizing your breath might be the best biohack yet.</p>

<h3 id="what-is-breathwork">What is breathwork?</h3>

<p>Breathwork is the practice of consciously controlling your breathing to improve physical, mental, and emotional well-being. Unlike the automatic, shallow breaths we take throughout the day, breathwork techniques focus on deep, intentional inhales and exhales to regulate the nervous system.</p>

<h3 id="how-is-breathwork-different-from-meditation">How is breathwork different from meditation?</h3>

<p>Breathwork involves actively controlling your breath to regulate the nervous system and achieve specific physical or mental benefits, while meditation focuses on quieting the mind and cultivating mindfulness. Essentially, breathwork is a dynamic practice, whereas meditation is more about stillness and mental presence.</p>

<h3 id="what-are-the-benefits-of-breathwork">What are the benefits of breathwork?</h3>

<p><u>Benefits of Breathwork<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>Reduces Stress and Anxiety: Breathwork activates the parasympathetic nervous system, lowering cortisol levels and promoting relaxation (backed by Western science on stress reduction).</li>
  <li>Improves Mental Clarity and Focus: Techniques like box breathing enhance concentration and cognitive performance by increasing oxygen flow to the brain.</li>
  <li>Boosts Energy and Endurance: The Wim Hof Method, for example, combines deep breathing with cold exposure to increase energy levels and physical endurance.</li>
  <li>Enhances Emotional Regulation: Breathwork helps release pent-up emotions and balance mood, contributing to better emotional health (supported by both Western psychology and Eastern practices like yoga).</li>
  <li>Improves Sleep Quality: Controlled breathing reduces overactive thinking, making it easier to fall asleep and stay asleep.</li>
  <li>Supports Immune Function: Breathwork can strengthen the immune system, with studies showing improved immune response through deep breathing techniques (Western and Asian wellness traditions support this).</li>
  <li>Promotes Better Respiratory Health: Deep breathing increases lung capacity and oxygenation, improving overall respiratory function, particularly in practices like pranayama in yoga.</li>
  <li>Helps in Pain Management: Breathwork can reduce the perception of pain by releasing endorphins, providing relief from chronic pain or discomfort.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="what-breathing-exercises-are-there">What breathing exercises are there?</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Diaphragmatic Breathing (Belly Breathing): Focuses on deep belly breaths to engage the diaphragm and promote relaxation.</li>
  <li>Box Breathing: Involves inhaling, holding, exhaling, and holding for equal counts (e.g., 4 seconds each), commonly used for stress reduction and focus.</li>
  <li>Wim Hof Method: Combines deep, controlled hyperventilation with cold exposure to increase oxygen levels and enhance endurance.</li>
  <li>4-7-8 Breathing: Inhale for 4 seconds, hold for 7 seconds, and exhale for 8 seconds to help reduce anxiety and improve sleep quality.</li>
  <li>Alternate Nostril Breathing (Nadi Shodhana): Involves inhaling and exhaling through one nostril at a time, used to balance the body’s energy and calm the mind (popular in yoga).</li>
</ul>

<p>Its a personal preference or which one to practice. I’m a big fan of the Wim Hof method and box breathing. A lot of these resources can be found on YouTube where you can practice for 20-30 minutes a day.</p>

<h3 id="when-should-you-practice-breathwork">When should you practice breathwork?</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Morning: Start your day with a session of diaphragmatic breathing or the Wim Hof Method to boost energy, focus, and mental clarity.</li>
  <li>During Stressful Moments: Use box breathing or 4-7-8 breathing when you’re feeling overwhelmed to calm your mind and regulate your emotions.</li>
  <li>Before Sleep: Practice 4-7-8 breathing or diaphragmatic breathing to relax your body and improve sleep quality.</li>
  <li>Throughout the Day: Integrate simple breathwork whenever you need a mental reset or emotional balance.</li>
</ul>

<p>A deep breath before you make decisions or if you are feeling reactive goes a long wayt!</p>

<p>The best time for breathwork is when you need it most—whether for relaxation, focus, energy, or emotional regulation, and practicing with a partner or having someone hold you accountable can make it easier to stick to your routine.</p>

<h3 id="books-about-better-breathing">Books about better breathing</h3>

<p>A few books on better breathing that provide in-depth knowledge and practical techniques:</p>

<ul>
  <li>“The Oxygen Advantage” by Patrick McKeown: Focuses on breathing exercises that improve athletic performance, reduce stress, and boost overall health through nasal breathing and breath control.</li>
  <li>“Breath: The New Science of a Lost Art” by James Nestor: Explores the science behind breathing, how modern humans have lost the art of proper breathing, and how we can reclaim it for improved health.</li>
  <li>“The Wim Hof Method” by Wim Hof: Details Wim Hof’s unique combination of breathing exercises and cold exposure, designed to enhance physical performance, mental clarity, and emotional resilience.</li>
  <li>“The Healing Power of the Breath” by Richard P. Brown and Patricia L. Gerbarg: Offers a comprehensive guide on using breathing techniques to treat anxiety, depression, and stress, backed by scientific research.</li>
  <li>“The Art of Breathing” by Danny Penman: A practical guide to mindfulness and breathwork, focusing on simple techniques to reduce stress and improve mental and physical health.</li>
</ul>

<p>I’m personally a big fan of breath. Wellness is always a continuous practice. Check out <a href="https://fromhktosg.github.io/singapore-stretching-muscle/">stretching</a> or <a href="https://fromhktosg.github.io/singapore-ice-bath/">ice bathing</a> as alternatives too. Good luck on your pursuits!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Singapore" /><category term="wellness" /><category term="health" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Are we breathing properly in Singapore and should you practice breathwork?]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/breath.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/breath.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ice Baths in Singapore: Benefits, Risks &amp;amp; Where to Try</title><link href="/singapore-ice-bath/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ice Baths in Singapore: Benefits, Risks &amp;amp; Where to Try" /><published>2025-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-ice-bath</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-ice-bath/"><![CDATA[<p>Ice baths in Singapore are becoming the latest wellness trend, with many seeking the supposed benefits of plunging into frigid waters.</p>

<p>While the idea of submerging yourself in near-freezing temperatures might sound like a form of self-torture, people claim it aids in muscle recovery, reduces inflammation, and boosts mental clarity. But before you rush to the nearest cold plunge, you’ll need to know how an ice bath is actually done, why people swear by it (and celebrities like Cristiano Ronaldo are all in), and whether it’s something you can safely do at home. Of course, as with any trend, there are risks to consider, and not everyone is ready to turn into an ice cube. Whether you’re wondering where to take the plunge in Singapore or need some cool alternatives, we’ve got you covered.</p>

<h3 id="what-is-an-ice-bath-and-why-do-people-do-it">What is an ice bath and why do people do it?</h3>

<p>An ice bath is a cold therapy practice where an individual immerses their body in ice-cold water for a period of time, typically 10 to 15 minutes, to help with muscle recovery and reduce inflammation. Popular among athletes and fitness enthusiasts, ice baths are believed to improve circulation, reduce muscle soreness, and speed up recovery after intense physical activity. The practice has gained significant attention in wellness circles and has even been embraced by celebrities, such as athletes and influencers, who tout its benefits for overall health and mental clarity. While the concept of ice bathing may sound extreme, it has become a trending recovery technique in Singapore, with locals seeking out cold plunge pools and specialized ice bath centers to reap the purported benefits. Whether you’re a weekend warrior or simply curious, exploring the world of ice baths could be the next step in your wellness journey.</p>

<h3 id="what-is-the-usual-process-of-an-ice-bath">What is the usual process of an ice bath?</h3>

<p>The usual process of an ice bath typically follows these steps:</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Prepare the Water: Fill a bathtub, plunge pool, or container with cold water, adding ice to lower the temperature to around 10-15°C (50-59°F).</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Set a Timer: It’s recommended to stay in the ice bath for about 10-15 minutes to avoid extreme cold exposure.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Enter Slowly: Ease into the cold water gradually to allow your body to adjust to the shock of the temperature.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Submerge Your Body: Ideally, the water should cover most of your body, up to your neck for maximum benefits.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Focus on Breathing: Maintain deep, controlled breathing to help manage the discomfort and focus on relaxation.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Exit Carefully: Once your time is up, slowly exit the bath to allow your body to warm up naturally, often by doing gentle movements or a warm shower.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Warm back up: Chant “hoo ha, hoo ha” while bending your knees and pushing your arms in opposite directions to help activate your body and warm up. It might sound odd, but it can aid in bringing back warmth and energy! Wim hof technique.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Always listen to your body and avoid staying in too long, as overexposure can lead to hypothermia or other risks.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<h3 id="how-do-i-decide-on-the-temperature-of-the-ice-bath">How do I decide on the temperature of the ice bath?</h3>

<p>Deciding on the temperature of your ice bath depends on your goals, tolerance, and experience level. Here’s a quick guide:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>For Beginners: Start with a warmer ice bath around 15°C (59°F). This will still provide some benefits without shocking your system too much. Gradually decrease the temperature as your body adjusts.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>For Muscle Recovery: The ideal temperature for muscle recovery is typically between 10-15°C (50-59°F). This range helps reduce muscle inflammation and soreness effectively without causing too much discomfort.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>For Advanced Users: If you’ve been practicing ice baths for a while, you can aim for a colder bath around 5-10°C (41-50°F) to intensify the recovery process. However, this can be challenging, so always listen to your body.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>For Mental Toughness: If you’re aiming to improve mental resilience, colder temperatures might be more beneficial, but it’s crucial to stay mindful of how your body is reacting.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Personal Tolerance: The best temperature ultimately depends on how your body responds. If you start feeling numb or excessively uncomfortable, it’s a sign to warm up or exit.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Start slow and adjust based on what feels right for you to avoid any risks of overexposure.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<h3 id="which-celebrities-practice-ice-bathing">Which celebrities practice ice bathing?</h3>

<p>Several celebrities swear by ice baths as part of their wellness routines, citing benefits like faster recovery and improved mental resilience. Some of the most notable names include:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Cristiano Ronaldo – The football legend is known for his intense recovery regimen, which includes regular ice baths to speed up muscle recovery after matches.</li>
  <li>LeBron James – The NBA star incorporates ice baths into his routine to help with muscle recovery and keep him in peak physical condition.</li>
  <li>David Beckham – The former footballer and fashion icon is often seen enjoying ice baths, a practice he has used to maintain his fitness levels throughout his career.</li>
  <li>Joe Rogan – The podcast host and comedian has shared his ice bath experiences on his show, often discussing the mental clarity and physical benefits he gets from regular cold plunges.</li>
  <li>Dwayne “The Rock” Johnson – Known for his intense workouts, The Rock has openly discussed how ice baths help him recover from the grueling demands of his training.</li>
  <li>Tony Robbins – The motivational speaker uses ice baths as part of his wellness routine, claiming they help with both physical recovery and mental fortitude.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="what-are-the-risks-of-doing-an-ice-bath">What are the risks of doing an ice bath?</h3>

<p>While ice baths offer benefits like muscle recovery and reduced inflammation, they also come with some risks, especially if done improperly or for too long. Here are the main risks to consider:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Hypothermia: Staying in an ice bath for too long can lower your body temperature to dangerous levels, leading to hypothermia. Symptoms include shivering, confusion, and fatigue.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Frostbite: Prolonged exposure to extreme cold can cause tissue damage, leading to frostbite, particularly in extremities like fingers, toes, and ears.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Shock to the System: The sudden cold can cause an abrupt shock to your body, potentially increasing your heart rate and blood pressure, which could be dangerous for those with heart conditions.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Numbness and Tingling: Ice baths can cause temporary numbness or tingling sensations, which can lead to discomfort or even injury if you’re not careful when exiting the bath.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Impaired Circulation: If you don’t warm up properly after an ice bath, it can disrupt blood flow and leave you feeling lightheaded or weak.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Risk for Pre-existing Conditions: People with certain conditions like Raynaud’s disease (poor circulation in fingers and toes), heart disease, or respiratory issues should avoid ice baths or consult a doctor before trying them.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>It’s crucial to monitor your time in the bath and ensure you’re in good health before engaging in this practice. Always warm up gradually afterward to avoid additional risks. If you’re a beginner, it’s best to have someone watch over you to ensure your safety.</p>

<h3 id="where-can-you-do-an-ice-bath-in-singapore">Where can you do an ice bath in Singapore?</h3>

<p>In Singapore, you can find several places to experience ice baths, either in specialized wellness centers or gyms offering cold therapy as part of their recovery services. Here are a few options:</p>

<ul>
  <li>The Cold Plunge Singapore – Specializing in cold therapy, this facility offers ice baths and cold plunge pools, ideal for muscle recovery and mental clarity.</li>
  <li>Physiotherapy &amp; Sports Injury Clinic – Some physiotherapy centers in Singapore provide cold plunge options as part of their sports recovery treatments.</li>
  <li>The Wellness Hub – A health and wellness center offering a range of therapies, including ice baths for recovery and improved circulation.</li>
  <li>True Fitness – Many of the True Fitness gyms in Singapore feature cold plunge pools, where members can access ice baths as part of their fitness recovery program.</li>
  <li>Cold Water Therapy at Sport Singapore – Occasionally, Sport Singapore offers cold water therapy sessions, including ice baths for athletes and fitness enthusiasts.</li>
  <li>Luxury Hotel Spas – Some high-end hotels like The Fullerton and Marina Bay Sands may offer ice baths as part of their spa or wellness services, especially for guests looking for elite recovery treatments.</li>
  <li>Ice bath clubs - For the hipsters!</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="can-you-have-an-ice-bath-at-home">Can you have an ice bath at home?</h3>

<p>Yes, and it’s easier than you might think. All you need is a bathtub, a large container, or even a small plunge pool. Here’s how you can do it:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Prepare the Ice and Water: Fill your bathtub or container with cold water, then add ice to bring the temperature down to 10-15°C (50-59°F) for an optimal recovery experience.</li>
  <li>Ice Bath Kits: You can purchase ice bath kits or cold plunge pools online in Singapore through platforms like Lazada or Shopee, which make it easier to create your own ice bath setup at home.</li>
  <li>Cold Plunge Pools: For a more permanent setup, some people in Singapore invest in portable cold plunge pools, which are perfect for regular ice baths and can fit into your home or balcony.</li>
  <li>Thermometer: Use a thermometer to check the water temperature and make sure it’s at the right level. This ensures you don’t end up with water that’s too cold or too warm for an effective ice bath.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="alternatives-to-ice-bathing-in-singapore-to-preserve-well-being">Alternatives to ice bathing in Singapore to preserve well-being</h3>

<p>If you’re not quite ready to dive into an ice bath, there are plenty of alternative wellness solutions available in Singapore to help with muscle recovery, relaxation, and overall well-being. Here are a few popular options:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Cryotherapy – This is a popular alternative to ice bathing, where your body is exposed to extremely cold air (around -100°C to -140°C) for a few minutes. Cryotherapy studios like CryoWorld Singapore offer full-body cryo chambers for recovery and rejuvenation.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Infrared Saunas – For a more relaxing recovery method, try infrared saunas. These saunas use infrared light to heat your body, promoting muscle relaxation, increased circulation, and detoxification. Breeze Sauna and The Sauna Room are great spots in Singapore.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Epsom Salt Baths – A more accessible alternative to ice baths, Epsom salt baths can help reduce muscle soreness, stress, and inflammation. You can easily recreate this wellness ritual at home with a few bags of Epsom salts from stores like Guardian or Watsons Singapore.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Foam Rolling – A go-to for athletes and fitness enthusiasts, foam rolling helps release tension in muscles, increase flexibility, and speed up recovery. Many gyms in Singapore, such as Fitness First and Virgin Active, provide foam rollers as part of their recovery zones.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Hydrotherapy Pools – These pools use water jets to massage and relieve pressure on your muscles. Many spas and wellness centers like ESPA at Resorts World Sentosa offer hydrotherapy pools as part of their treatment packages.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Massage Therapy – A traditional and highly effective method for muscle recovery, massage therapy helps reduce soreness and stress. Options include deep tissue massages, sports massages, and lymphatic drainage. Many spas in Singapore, such as Kahuna Spa and The Ritz-Carlton Spa, offer specialized services.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a href="https://fromhktosg.github.io/singapore-stretching-muscle/">Stretching</a> and Yoga – Practices like yoga and stretching can complement or even replace the benefits of ice baths by improving flexibility, blood flow, and overall recovery. Consider joining classes at Yoga Movement or Pure Yoga for guided sessions.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>Try it out!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Singapore" /><category term="wellness" /><category term="health" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ice baths in Singapore are becoming the latest wellness trend, with many seeking the supposed benefits of plunging into frigid waters.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/icebath.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/icebath.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Best Souvenirs in Singapore: Top Picks &amp;amp; Where to Shop</title><link href="/singapore-souvenirs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Best Souvenirs in Singapore: Top Picks &amp;amp; Where to Shop" /><published>2025-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-souvenirs</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-souvenirs/"><![CDATA[<p>Souvenirs in Singapore—those must-have keepsakes that supposedly capture the essence of your trip—are everywhere, but are they worth the buy?</p>

<p>In this city of contrasts, from modern skyscrapers to traditional hawker centers, finding the perfect souvenir is a task in itself. Whether it’s a Merlion souvenir, locally crafted jewelry, or Singaporean snacks like kaya jam, the options are endless and suited to every budget. But the real question is, are these items authentic representations of Singapore, or just another tourist trap? Let’s explore the best souvenirs to buy in Singapore, both edible and non-edible, and where to find them, including at Changi Airport.</p>

<h3 id="does-anyone-still-buy-souvenirs">Does anyone still buy souvenirs?</h3>

<p>Does anyone still buy souvenirs? Surprisingly, yes! Despite the rise of digital photos and online shopping, souvenirs continue to be a popular choice for travelers. According to a recent survey, nearly 60% of tourists still purchase souvenirs as a way to remember their trips or share their experiences with loved ones. In Singapore, where tourism is a major industry, souvenir sales remain strong, with many visitors keen on taking home a physical reminder of their visit to the Lion City. So, whether it’s a little keychain or a luxe local craft, it seems that souvenirs are far from becoming obsolete.</p>

<h3 id="why-should-you-buy-souvenirs-in-singapore">Why should you buy souvenirs in Singapore?</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Memory Keepsake: A unique souvenir to remember your trip to Singapore, from iconic Merlion statues to local handicrafts.</li>
  <li>Share the Experience: Perfect gifts like kaya jam or Singaporean jewelry for friends and family.</li>
  <li>Support Local Artisans: By purchasing items at places like Bugis Street or Chinatown, you support Singapore’s local artisans.</li>
  <li>Unique Finds: Discover one-of-a-kind souvenirs that represent Singapore’s culture, from traditional items to modern collectibles.</li>
  <li>Cultural Connection: Authentic Singapore souvenirs allow you to connect with the city’s rich cultural heritage and vibrant history.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="what-are-the-best-souvenirs-to-buy-in-singapore-that-are-not-food">What are the best souvenirs to buy in Singapore that are not food?</h3>

<p><u>Below 10 SGD / 7.5 USD:<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>Merlion Figurines – Iconic symbol of Singapore, perfect for a souvenir.</li>
  <li>Singapore Keychains – Practical and widely available at souvenir shops across the city.</li>
  <li>Orchid-Themed Gifts – Singapore’s national flower, featured on various souvenirs like pins, bags, and accessories.</li>
  <li>Miniature Singapore Landmarks – Small replicas of famous landmarks like Marina Bay Sands or Gardens by the Bay.</li>
  <li>Singapore Postcards – Featuring stunning images of Singapore’s skyline, landmarks, and culture.</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Below 25 SGD / 18 USD<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>Local Handicrafts – Beautifully crafted items from Chinatown or Kampong Glam, including batik art and traditional textiles.</li>
  <li>Batik Scarves – Colorful, hand-painted scarves that showcase Singapore’s cultural diversity.</li>
  <li>Peranakan Jewelry – Intricate designs inspired by Singapore’s Peranakan culture.</li>
  <li>Local Art Prints – Affordable prints by local artists, often showcasing scenes of Singapore’s history and vibrant neighborhoods.</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Below 50 SGD / 37 USD<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>Peranakan Pottery – Handcrafted porcelain or ceramic items, perfect for home decor and representing Singapore’s Peranakan heritage.</li>
  <li>Local Designer Accessories – Affordable yet stylish fashion accessories from local Singaporean designers.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="what-are-the-best-souvenirs-to-buy-in-singapore-that-are-edible-aka-food">What are the best souvenirs to buy in Singapore that are edible aka food?</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Bacha coffee - TwG tea - no explanations needed. The most iconic Singapore beverages</li>
  <li>Kaya Jam – A sweet, coconut and egg jam, perfect for spreading on toast or as a gift.</li>
  <li>Bak Kwa – A popular Chinese-style dried meat, sweet and savory, often enjoyed as a snack.</li>
  <li>Chilli Crab Sauce – A ready-to-use sauce that lets you recreate Singapore’s famous chilli crab at home.</li>
  <li>Pineapple Tarts – A delicious pastry filled with sweet pineapple jam, commonly enjoyed during festive seasons like Chinese New Year.</li>
  <li>Singapore Sling Mix – A cocktail mix that allows you to make the iconic Singapore Sling at home.</li>
  <li>Durian Products – Whether it’s durian candies, chips, or paste, this ‘king of fruits’ is a uniquely Singaporean flavor.</li>
  <li>Local Tea Blends – Unique Singaporean blends, such as the popular Singaporean milk tea or jasmine tea.</li>
  <li>Salted Egg Snacks – Chips or crackers coated with the flavorful salted egg yolk, a favorite local snack. Irvins is the classic</li>
  <li>Chocolates with Local Flavors – Chocolates infused with local flavors like pandan, kaya, or durian, for a taste of Singapore in every bite.</li>
  <li>Gula Melaka (Palm Sugar) – Sweet and rich, this sugar is commonly used in local desserts like Chendol.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="where-can-you-buy-souvenirs-in-singapore">Where can you buy souvenirs in Singapore?</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Chinatown – A hotspot for traditional crafts, local art, Peranakan items, and affordable souvenirs like keychains, ornaments, and tea sets.</li>
  <li>Bugis Street – Known for its bustling markets, you’ll find a wide variety of souvenirs, from clothing and accessories to Merlion figurines and local snacks.</li>
  <li>Haji Lane – A vibrant area filled with unique boutiques offering locally designed items, including art, jewelry, and custom-made accessories.</li>
  <li>VivoCity – A large shopping mall offering both luxury and affordable souvenirs, including local brands, art, and food products like kaya jam and Bak Kwa.</li>
  <li>Marina Bay Sands Shoppes – If you’re looking for high-end or unique luxury items, this is the place to shop for designer souvenirs and exclusive Singaporean goods.</li>
  <li>Little India – Explore traditional markets for Indian-inspired souvenirs, such as jewelry, fabrics, and ethnic handicrafts.</li>
  <li>Sentosa – Popular tourist attractions here offer a variety of fun, themed souvenirs, from Merlion merchandise to themed apparel and accessories.</li>
  <li>Singapore Changi Airport – A convenient spot for last-minute souvenir shopping, with stores offering everything from local snacks and sweets to Singapore-themed gifts.</li>
  <li>Raffles City Shopping Centre – A centrally located mall offering a mix of high-street and local brands, perfect for finding unique Singaporean gifts and souvenirs.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="can-you-buy-souvenirs-at-singapore-changi-airport">Can you buy souvenirs at Singapore Changi airport?</h3>

<p>You can definitely buy souvenirs at Singapore Changi Airport! In fact, it’s one of the most convenient places for last-minute shopping. The airport features a wide range of stores offering a variety of Singaporean souvenirs, including:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Local snacks like kaya jam, Bak Kwa, salted egg chips, and pineapple tarts.</li>
  <li>Singapore-themed gifts such as Merlion figurines, T-shirts, keychains, and bags.</li>
  <li>Luxury items and high-end local products from top Singaporean designers.</li>
  <li>Chocolates with local flavors like pandan and durian.</li>
  <li>Cultural items like Peranakan crafts, jade jewelry, and Singapore Sling mixes.</li>
</ul>

<p>They’re generally all overpriced though. To be honest, the souvenirs from Singapore versus that of other countries are tame. But there’s always something to love for everyone. Remember, you might be able to get a <a href="https://fromhktosg.github.io/singapore-tax-refunds/">tax refund</a> for your purchases!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Singapore" /><category term="travel" /><category term="tourists" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Souvenirs in Singapore—those must-have keepsakes that supposedly capture the essence of your trip—are everywhere, but are they worth the buy?]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/sou.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/sou.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Fill in Singapore Health Declaration &amp;amp; SG Arrival Card</title><link href="/singapore-arrival-card/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Fill in Singapore Health Declaration &amp;amp; SG Arrival Card" /><published>2025-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-arrival-card</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-arrival-card/"><![CDATA[<p>Planning a trip to Singapore? Well, don’t forget the famous SG Arrival Card (SGAC) with the Electronic Health Declaration.
This essential document is required for all travelers entering Singapore, ensuring you’ve provided all the necessary health and travel details for your stay. You’ll need to fill it out online before you even step foot in Singapore, as it’s part of their smooth (and highly regulated) arrival process. But don’t worry, it’s not as complicated as it sounds—just a few simple steps to get you through the immigration process without a hitch. In this guide, we’ll dive into why, who, where, and how to fill out your Singapore Arrival Card, so you can get on with your <a href="https://fromhktosg.github.io/singapore-travel-itinerary/">adventure</a> in this iconic city-state.</p>

<h3 id="what-forms-do-you-need-to-fill-in-when-you-arrive-in-singapore">What forms do you need to fill in when you arrive in Singapore?</h3>

<p>SG Arrival Card (SGAC). That’s it</p>

<h3 id="what-is-the-singapore-arrival-card">What is the Singapore arrival card?</h3>

<p>This form collects essential information about your health status, travel history, and recent contact with high-risk areas, helping Singapore maintain its strict border controls. All travelers—whether you’re visiting for tourism, business, or even a layover—must submit the SG Arrival Card online before arrival. Depending on your travel history and vaccination status, additional declarations might be required. The process is quick, but it’s crucial to complete it accurately to avoid delays at immigration.</p>

<h3 id="who-needs-to-fill-in-singapore-arrival-card">Who needs to fill in Singapore arrival card?</h3>

<p>Anyone entering Singapore needs to fill in the SG Arrival Card (SGAC), regardless of whether you’re a tourist, business traveler, or even just passing through on a layover. This includes Singapore citizens, permanent residents, and foreign visitors alike. The form is required for all travelers aged 6 years and above, ensuring that authorities have the necessary information about your health and travel history. If you’re planning to enter Singapore, don’t think you can skip this step—failing to submit the SG Arrival Card could lead to delays or complications at immigration.</p>

<h3 id="where-do-you-fill-in-singapore-arrival-card">Where do you fill in Singapore arrival card?</h3>

<p>You fill in the Singapore Arrival Card (SGAC) online through the official Immigration and Checkpoints Authority (ICA) website or their mobile app. This form is required for all travelers entering Singapore, including citizens, permanent residents, and foreign visitors, aged 6 years and above. You’ll need to provide personal details, travel information, and a health declaration to help the authorities maintain safety and health standards. It’s recommended to submit the form at least 3 days before your arrival to avoid last-minute issues. You can complete the form easily at https://www.ica.gov.sg/sg-arrival-card, ensuring a smooth entry into Singapore without unnecessary delays.</p>

<h3 id="how-do-you-fill-in-singapore-arrival-card">How do you fill in Singapore arrival card?</h3>

<p>Filling in the Singapore Arrival Card (SGAC) is a straightforward process. First, visit the official Immigration and Checkpoints Authority (ICA) website or use their mobile app. You’ll need to provide personal details such as your passport information, flight details, and your travel history, including any recent trips to high-risk areas. You’ll also complete the Electronic Health Declaration, answering questions about your health status and any symptoms you may have. Once you’ve filled in all the required fields, review your information and submit the form. Straightforward and simple. You’ll receive a notification in your email inbox when done.</p>

<p>Happy travels!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Singapore" /><category term="travel" /><category term="tourists" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Planning a trip to Singapore? Well, don’t forget the famous SG Arrival Card (SGAC) with the Electronic Health Declaration. This essential document is required for all travelers entering Singapore, ensuring you’ve provided all the necessary health and travel details for your stay. You’ll need to fill it out online before you even step foot in Singapore, as it’s part of their smooth (and highly regulated) arrival process. But don’t worry, it’s not as complicated as it sounds—just a few simple steps to get you through the immigration process without a hitch. In this guide, we’ll dive into why, who, where, and how to fill out your Singapore Arrival Card, so you can get on with your adventure in this iconic city-state.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/arrival.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/arrival.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Stretching in Singapore: Best Tips &amp;amp; Stretches for Muscle Relief</title><link href="/singapore-stretching-muscle/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stretching in Singapore: Best Tips &amp;amp; Stretches for Muscle Relief" /><published>2025-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-stretching-muscle</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-stretching-muscle/"><![CDATA[<p>Ever feel like your body is permanently stuck in “office chair mode”? You need to stretch.</p>

<p>If you’re in Singapore, where long hours at a desk (or hunched over a phone) are the norm, muscle tightness is practically a national condition. But why does your body feel like it’s turning into a stiff board, and can stretching actually help? From the best home stretches to whether you should trust stretching services like Dr Stretch, we’ll break down everything you need to know. Plus, we’ll tackle the age-old question: Can a gym workout or a good massage really replace proper stretching?</p>

<h3 id="why-does-the-body-get-tight">Why does the body get tight?</h3>

<p>Muscle tightness happens when your body stays in the same position for too long or undergoes repetitive stress without proper movement. In Singapore, where long office hours, high stress, and a sedentary lifestyle are common, issues like tight hamstrings, stiff shoulders, and lower back pain are almost guaranteed. Poor office workers. Poor posture, lack of mobility, and even dehydration can make muscles contract and feel tense, reducing flexibility over time. Without regular stretching, this tightness can lead to discomfort, limited range of motion, and even chronic pain. Understanding why muscles get tight is the first step to improving flexibility, preventing injury, and keeping your body moving pain-free.</p>

<h3 id="what-is-stretching-and-the-science-behind-it">What is stretching and the science behind it?</h3>

<p>Stretching is the act of lengthening muscles and connective tissues to improve flexibility, mobility, and blood circulation. Scientifically, it helps reduce muscle stiffness by increasing blood flow, delivering oxygen and nutrients to tissues while removing waste products. Stretching also triggers the nervous system to relax tight muscles, reducing muscle tension, improving range of motion, and helping to reduce back pain. Over time, consistent stretching exercises can enhance muscle elasticity, prevent injuries, and even improve posture—something especially useful for office workers in Singapore who sit all day. Whether it’s static stretching, dynamic stretching, or assisted stretching, the key is to do it regularly to maintain flexibility and prevent stiffness.</p>

<h3 id="why-is-it-important-to-stretch">Why is it important to stretch?</h3>

<p>Stretching is essential for maintaining flexibility, mobility, and overall physical health at any age. Here’s why it matters for different age groups:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Children &amp; Teens: Helps with growth, posture, and athletic performance, reducing the risk of injuries from sports or daily activities.</li>
  <li>Young Adults (20s-30s): Counters muscle tightness from long work hours, improves posture, and prevents workout-related injuries.</li>
  <li>Middle-Aged Adults (40s-50s): Keeps joints mobile, reduces the risk of chronic pain, and helps with lower back pain, a common issue in Singapore’s office culture.</li>
  <li>Seniors (60+): Maintains balance, flexibility, and independence, reducing the risk of falls and mobility issues as the body naturally stiffens with age.</li>
</ul>

<p>No matter your age, regular stretching can prevent stiffness, improve circulation, and enhance overall well-being.</p>

<h3 id="can-massages-replace-stretching">Can massages replace stretching?</h3>

<p>Massages can relieve muscle tension, but they don’t improve flexibility or range of motion like stretching does.</p>

<h3 id="can-working-out-at-the-gym-replace-stretching">Can working out at the gym replace stretching?</h3>

<p>Working out strengthens muscles, but without stretching, you risk stiffness, reduced flexibility, and a higher chance of injury.</p>

<h3 id="can-you-trust-stretching-services-like-dr-stretch">Can you trust stretching services like Dr Stretch?</h3>

<p>Stretching services like Dr Stretch claim to improve flexibility, mobility, and muscle recovery, but trust depends on factors like trainer expertise, technique, and personal experience. While assisted stretching can help deeply stretch tight muscles—especially for office workers, athletes, and those with chronic stiffness—it’s not a magic fix. Some people find it effective, while others prefer self-stretching or physiotherapy for more controlled results. Always check reviews, credentials, and pricing before committing, and remember: no service can replace regular, consistent stretching on your own.</p>

<h3 id="popular-stretches-you-can-do-at-home">Popular stretches you can do at home</h3>

<p>Please note - I’m not a doctor or physio but these are some I do frequently!</p>

<p><u>Neck Stretches<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>Neck Tilts: Gently tilt your head towards each shoulder, holding for 20-30 seconds.</li>
  <li>Neck Rotations: Slowly rotate your neck in a full circle, then switch directions.</li>
  <li>Forward Neck Stretch: Drop your chin to your chest and hold for 20-30 seconds.</li>
  <li>Neck Side Stretch: Tilt your head to one side and use your hand to gently deepen the stretch.</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Lower Back Stretches<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>Child’s Pose: Sit on your knees and stretch your arms forward while lowering your chest to the floor.</li>
  <li>Cat-Cow Stretch: Start on all fours, arch your back upwards (Cat), then dip it downward (Cow), repeating for 10-15 reps.</li>
  <li>Knee-to-Chest Stretch: Lie on your back and pull one knee towards your chest, holding for 20-30 seconds.</li>
  <li>Seated Forward Bend: Sit with your legs straight and gently reach forward to touch your toes.</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Hip Stretches<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>Lunge Stretch: Step one foot forward into a deep lunge, holding for 20-30 seconds on each side.</li>
  <li>Pigeon Pose: From a tabletop position, bring one leg forward and bend it while extending the other leg back.</li>
  <li>Butterfly Stretch: Sit with your feet together and gently press your knees toward the floor.</li>
  <li>Hip Flexor Stretch: Step one foot forward into a lunge and push your hips forward to feel a stretch in the hip flexor.</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Quad Stretches<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>Standing Quad Stretch: Stand on one leg and pull the opposite foot towards your glutes, holding for 20-30 seconds.</li>
  <li>Lying Quad Stretch: Lie on your side, grab your ankle, and pull it towards your glutes.</li>
  <li>Kneeling Quad Stretch: Kneel on one knee, and gently push your hips forward while pulling your opposite foot towards your glutes.</li>
  <li>Bridge with Quad Stretch: Lie on your back, lift your hips into a bridge, and stretch one leg at a time.</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Calf Stretches<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>Standing Calf Stretch: Place your hands on a wall and step one foot back, pressing your heel into the floor.</li>
  <li>Downward Dog: In a plank position, lift your hips and push your heels towards the floor to stretch the calves.</li>
  <li>Seated Calf Stretch: Sit with your legs extended and use a towel around your feet to pull your toes towards you.</li>
  <li>Wall Calf Stretch: Stand facing a wall and step one foot back, keeping your heel down as you lean forward.</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Hamstring Stretches<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>Standing Hamstring Stretch: Stand tall, hinge at the hips, and reach for your toes, holding for 20-30 seconds.</li>
  <li>Seated Hamstring Stretch: Sit with one leg extended and gently reach forward to touch your toes, keeping your leg straight.</li>
  <li>Lying Hamstring Stretch: Lie on your back and use a belt or towel around your foot to gently pull your leg up.</li>
  <li>Leg Swings: Stand on one leg and swing the other leg forward and backward to loosen up the hamstrings.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="what-to-watch-out-for-when-stretching">What to watch out for when stretching?</h3>

<p>When stretching, it’s important to be mindful to avoid injury and maximize effectiveness. Here are key things to watch out for:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Overstretching: Pushing your muscles too far can cause strains or sprains. Always stretch to a point where you feel tension, not pain.</li>
  <li>Bouncing: Ballistic stretching (bouncing) can increase the risk of muscle tears. Opt for static stretching or dynamic stretching instead.</li>
  <li>Holding Stretches Too Long: Holding stretches for too long can lead to muscle fatigue. Aim for 20-30 seconds per stretch for best results.</li>
  <li>Poor Technique: Incorrect form can cause muscle imbalances or strain. Focus on proper alignment to ensure safe and effective stretching.</li>
  <li>Ignoring Warm-Up: Stretching cold muscles can lead to injury. Always do a brief warm-up before stretching, such as light jogging or walking.</li>
  <li>Not Listening to Your Body: If you feel sharp pain or discomfort, stop immediately. Stretching should be gentle and progressive, not forced.</li>
</ul>

<p>By avoiding these common mistakes, you can improve flexibility, prevent injury, and ensure your stretching routine is effective and safe.</p>

<h3 id="what-equipment-can-help-you-with-stretching">What equipment can help you with stretching?</h3>

<p>Several pieces of equipment can enhance your stretching routine and help you improve flexibility, mobility, and muscle recovery. Here’s a list of useful tools:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Foam Roller: A foam roller helps with self-myofascial release, targeting tight muscles and fascia to relieve stiffness and improve range of motion.</li>
  <li>Resistance Bands: These bands can assist in deeper stretches by providing gentle resistance, especially for hamstring stretches or shoulder stretches.</li>
  <li>Stretching Strap: A stretching strap helps you deepen your stretches safely by allowing you to hold positions longer, especially for hamstrings or calf stretches.</li>
  <li>Yoga Blocks: Yoga blocks are great for supporting your body during hip stretches or seated stretches, allowing you to focus on flexibility without straining.</li>
  <li>Massage Ball: A massage ball targets trigger points and knots in the body, enhancing the effect of your stretches and helping to release muscle tension.</li>
  <li>Yoga Wheel: This tool is helpful for opening up the chest, back, and hip flexors by gently stretching and increasing your range of motion.</li>
  <li>Stretching Bench or Chair: These tools provide stability and support for stretches, especially when targeting areas like the lower back or hips, and are useful for people with limited flexibility.</li>
</ul>

<p>If stretching doesn’t help with easing your pain, see a <a href="https://fromhktosg.github.io/best-doctor-singapore/">doctor</a> or physio for a professional opinion!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Singapore" /><category term="health" /><category term="wellness" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ever feel like your body is permanently stuck in “office chair mode”? You need to stretch.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/stretch.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/stretch.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Bubble Tea in Singapore: Must-Try Milk Teas You’re Missing Out On</title><link href="/singapore-milk-tea-bubble-tea/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bubble Tea in Singapore: Must-Try Milk Teas You’re Missing Out On" /><published>2025-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-milk-tea-bubble-tea</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-milk-tea-bubble-tea/"><![CDATA[<p>Bubble tea or milk tea in Singapore is more than just a drink—it’s practically a lifestyle.</p>

<p>From classic milk tea with chewy tapioca pearls to extravagant cheese foam-topped creations, Singaporeans can’t seem to get enough of their favorite boba fix. But how did this obsession even begin, and is it really called “bubble tea” or “boba”? With so many tea bases, toppings, and sugar levels to choose from, navigating the bubble tea world can feel overwhelming, especially with new brands like Chagee gaining cult followings. Whether you’re just here for the pearls or secretly wondering if opening your own bubble tea shop is a good investment, this guide will cover everything you need to know about Singapore’s unshakable love for bubble tea.</p>

<h3 id="why-do-singaporeans-like-bubble-tea">Why do Singaporeans like bubble tea?</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Convenience: Bubble tea is easily accessible with numerous outlets in <a href="https://fromhktosg.github.io/shopping-in-singapore/">shopping malls</a>, along MRT stations, and even on food delivery apps.</li>
  <li>Customizable: With endless options for tea bases, sugar levels, and toppings (like pearls, coconut jelly, or red bean), there’s something for everyone.</li>
  <li>Social Media Appeal: Instagram-worthy drinks and quirky flavors make bubble tea a fun part of Singapore’s social media culture.</li>
  <li>Chewy Pearls: The satisfying texture of the chewy tapioca pearls adds a unique experience that sets bubble tea apart from regular beverages.</li>
  <li>Trendy and Youthful: It’s seen as a trendy, youthful drink, and often associated with socializing or hanging out with friends.</li>
  <li>Cultural Influence: Having originated in Taiwan, bubble tea has become a beloved part of the Singaporean food scene due to its influence across Asia.</li>
  <li>Sweet Escape: A sugary, refreshing treat that offers a quick break from the daily grind, satisfying cravings for something indulgent.</li>
  <li>Affordable luxury: Not the cheapest, not essential either</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="how-did-the-bubble-tea-craze-start">How did the bubble tea craze start?</h3>

<p>The bubble tea craze began in Taiwan during the 1980s, with the invention of the now-famous drink made from tea, milk, and chewy tapioca pearls. Legend has it that Lin Hsiu Hui, the owner of a small tea shop, decided to add tapioca pearls to her iced tea, creating a unique combination that quickly gained popularity. By the 1990s, bubble tea made its way to other parts of Asia, including Singapore, where it rapidly became a hit. The trend was fueled by its novelty, customizable nature, and the fun of slurping up chewy pearls with every sip. Over time, social media amplified the craze, making bubble tea a global sensation that continues to thrive today.</p>

<p>Bubble tea made its way into Singapore in the early 1990s, shortly after it gained popularity in Taiwan. The first shops offering the trendy drink started popping up, initially catering to the younger crowd who were curious about the novelty of combining tea with chewy tapioca pearls. Singapore’s food scene, already known for embracing new trends, quickly embraced bubble tea, with local adaptations of flavors and toppings. The growing influence of Taiwanese pop culture, along with the rise of malls and food courts, created the perfect environment for bubble tea chains to expand rapidly. Soon, it wasn’t just a passing fad but a lasting part of Singapore’s daily life, with local and international brands competing for the top spot in a fiercely popular market. Allegedly, Koi came first to SG.</p>

<h3 id="is-it-boba-or-bubble-tea">Is it boba or bubble tea?</h3>

<p>Whether it’s called boba or bubble tea often depends on where you’re from, but both terms refer to the same popular drink. Bubble tea is the more common name in places like Singapore and the U.S., highlighting the tea base and the chewy “bubbles” or pearls that sit at the bottom of the drink. On the other hand, boba is the term used primarily in Taiwan, where the drink originated, and it’s often used interchangeably to describe the drink and the tapioca pearls themselves. So, if you’re craving that sweet, chewy, Instagram-worthy drink, you can call it whatever you like—whether you’re enjoying a boba milk tea or a bubble tea with pearls, you’re in for a treat.</p>

<h3 id="what-are-the-pearls-or-bubbles-made-of-for-bubble-tea">What are the pearls or bubbles made of for bubble tea?</h3>

<p>The pearls or bubbles in bubble tea are typically made from tapioca starch, water, and sugar, which are cooked to create chewy, translucent balls. Some variations may use other ingredients like agar or fruit juices for different textures and flavors.</p>

<h3 id="is-bubble-tea-healthy">Is bubble tea healthy?</h3>

<p>Bubble tea can be high in sugar and calories, especially with added toppings like tapioca pearls or cheese foam. While it provides some antioxidants from the tea, regular consumption may not be the healthiest choice due to its sugar content. Opting for lower sugar versions or healthier toppings can make it a more balanced treat.</p>

<h3 id="what-types-of-tea-are-there-for-bubble-tea">What types of tea are there for bubble tea?</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Green Tea / Sencha: A lighter, more refreshing option, often used in healthier bubble tea variations.</li>
  <li>Oolong Tea: A semi-fermented tea that provides a unique, floral flavor profile.</li>
  <li>Jasmine Tea: A fragrant, floral tea that pairs well with sweet toppings like tapioca pearls.</li>
  <li>Taro Tea: A sweet, creamy tea made with taro root, popular in bubble tea for its smooth texture and unique flavor.</li>
  <li>Matcha Tea: A powdered green tea used for a richer, more earthy taste in bubble tea.</li>
  <li>Ceylon Tea: A bold, robust tea from Sri Lanka that adds a rich flavor to bubble tea.</li>
  <li>Tie Guan Yin: A premium variety of oolong tea with floral and fruity notes, often used in high-end bubble tea.</li>
  <li>Osmanthus Tea: A fragrant tea with a sweet, floral aroma, adding a delicate touch to bubble tea blends.</li>
  <li>Da Hong Pao: A famous oolong tea from China, known for its complex flavor profile and smooth texture.</li>
  <li>Pu-erh Tea: A fermented tea with earthy, deep flavors that can offer a unique twist to bubble tea.</li>
</ul>

<p>Of course, all of these can come with milk or without. In some instances, they can be with fruits as well.</p>

<h3 id="what-type-of-toppings-are-there-for-bubble-tea">What type of toppings are there for bubble tea?</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Tapioca Pearls: The classic, chewy topping that defines bubble tea, offering a satisfying texture in every sip.</li>
  <li>Popping Boba: Small, juice-filled bubbles that burst with flavor, adding a fun, colorful twist to your drink.</li>
  <li>Coconut Jelly: A chewy, slightly sweet topping made from coconut, offering a refreshing alternative to tapioca pearls.</li>
  <li>Aloe Vera: Light and refreshing, this topping provides a healthy, cool texture that complements fruit teas.</li>
  <li>Cheese Foam: A creamy, salty foam topping that’s become a fancy trend in bubble tea, creating a savory-sweet experience.</li>
  <li>Whipped Cream: A luxurious topping that adds a rich, creamy texture and can be customized with flavor syrups or sprinkles.</li>
  <li>Grass Jelly: A popular topping with a mildly bitter flavor, offering a unique contrast to the sweetness of bubble tea.</li>
  <li>Red Bean: A classic Asian topping that adds a sweet and slightly earthy flavor to your bubble tea.</li>
  <li>Taro Balls: Made from taro root, these chewy balls are a fancy alternative that pairs perfectly with taro-flavored drinks.</li>
  <li>Lychee Jelly: A sweet, fruity topping that adds an extra burst of flavor, perfect for fruit-infused bubble teas.</li>
</ul>

<p>These days, bubble tea has gotten even fancier with endless possibilities for customization. Whether you’re choosing from a variety of exotic toppings or adjusting your sugar level, it’s easy to personalize your drink to fit your cravings.</p>

<h3 id="whats-the-ideal-bubble-tea-customization-ask">What’s the ideal bubble tea customization ask?</h3>

<p>Keep things simple. 1. bubbles, 2. 25% sugar / sweetness, 3. less / no ice (ice takes up too much space)</p>

<h3 id="popular-bubble-tea-chains-in-singapore-and-their-signature-items">Popular bubble tea chains in Singapore and their signature items</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Koi Cafe: Known for its signature Golden Pearls, Koi Cafe offers a rich and creamy milk tea that’s a crowd favorite. Their customizable drinks, like the Koi milk tea with brown sugar pearls, are perfect for tea lovers looking for a sweet treat.</li>
  <li>ChiCha SanChen: Famous for their Brown Sugar Bubble Tea, ChiCha SanChen brings Taiwanese tea culture to life with their freshly brewed teas and chewy pearls. Their Taro Milk Tea and Signature Brown Sugar Milk Tea are highly recommended.</li>
  <li>Chagee: Chagee specializes in refreshing fruit teas, with their Peach Oolong Tea and Passionfruit Green Tea standing out. Their chilled fruit infusions with pearls or coconut jelly are perfect for a lighter, fruity bubble tea experience.</li>
  <li>Kebuke: Known for their Matcha Milk Tea, Kebuke also stands out with its honeycomb pearls, offering a unique twist to the typical bubble tea. Their Honey Milk Tea with pearls is a top pick for a sweet and smooth drink.</li>
  <li>LiHo: A local favorite, LiHo’s Brown Sugar Fresh Milk and Cheese Tea are fan favorites. Their Signature Brown Sugar Boba Milk is a must-try for those who crave a rich and indulgent bubble tea.</li>
  <li>Playmade: Playmade is famous for their handmade tapioca pearls, offering a fresh, chewy experience. Their Playmade Brown Sugar Pearl Milk and Taro Milk Tea are popular choices for those seeking an authentic bubble tea experience.</li>
  <li>Silk Tea: A chain that specializes in smooth and creamy drinks, Silk Tea’s Silk Matcha Latte and Silk Taro Milk Tea are top recommendations for those looking for a rich, velvety bubble tea.</li>
  <li>Beautea: Known for its trendy matcha drinks and fruit tea blends, Beautea’s Matcha Latte and Lychee Fruit Tea are perfect for those who want to enjoy both creamy and fruity bubble tea options.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="why-do-people-like-chagee">Why do people like Chagee?</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Unique Fruit Teas: Chagee’s refreshing fruit-infused teas like Passionfruit Green Tea and Peach Oolong Tea stand out with bold, natural flavors that are a perfect alternative to traditional milk teas.</li>
  <li>Customization: The ability to customize drinks with toppings like coconut jelly and tapioca pearls makes every Chagee experience personal and fun.</li>
  <li>Quality Ingredients: Chagee uses premium teas and freshly brewed bases, ensuring that each drink is flavorful and of high quality.</li>
  <li>Instagram-Worthy Drinks: With vibrant colors and beautifully crafted drinks, Chagee has earned a loyal following, especially among younger crowds who love to share their drinks on social media. The bag your tea sits in is so cute too!</li>
  <li>Affordable Pricing: Compared to other bubble tea chains, Chagee offers great value for the quality and customization options, making it accessible for everyone.</li>
</ul>

<p>The combination of fresh ingredients, innovative flavors, and a fun, customizable experience is what drives the hype around Chagee.</p>

<h3 id="can-you-make-bubble-tea-at-home">Can you make bubble tea at home?</h3>

<p>Yes, here’s how:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Tea Base: Brew your favorite tea (green, black, oolong, etc.). For a more authentic taste, use loose leaf tea or tea bags.</li>
  <li>Tapioca Pearls: You can either buy pre-made tapioca pearls from stores or make your own from scratch (though that’s a more time-consuming process). Simply cook them according to the package instructions.</li>
  <li>Sweetener: Add your preferred sweetener—sugar syrup, honey, or brown sugar syrup—depending on your taste.</li>
  <li>Milk or Alternatives: Add regular milk, condensed milk, or dairy-free alternatives like almond milk or oat milk for a creamy texture.</li>
  <li>Ice: Add ice cubes to chill your bubble tea.</li>
  <li>Toppings: If you like extra toppings like coconut jelly, popping boba, or red bean, you can easily add them in!</li>
</ul>

<p>Let me save you some time though - it’s not worth the time unless for a fun date idea.</p>

<p>I’m not crazy about milk tea or bubble tea. It’s really not that healthy and dents your wallet like a daily coffee does. Let me know your thoughts.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Singapore" /><category term="food" /><category term="restaurants" /><category term="tea" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bubble tea or milk tea in Singapore is more than just a drink—it’s practically a lifestyle.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/tea.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/tea.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Guide to Ice Cream in Singapore: Best Secret Shops &amp;amp; Brands</title><link href="/singapore-ice-cream/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Guide to Ice Cream in Singapore: Best Secret Shops &amp;amp; Brands" /><published>2025-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-ice-cream</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-ice-cream/"><![CDATA[<p>Ah, ice cream in Singapore—a delightful treat that somehow manages to be both a cooling respite from the relentless tropical heat and a source of endless debate among dessert enthusiasts.</p>

<p>In Singapore, where the weather practically begs for a scoop (or three) of ice cream, the frozen dessert options seem endless—gelato, sorbet, and the ever-popular ice cream, all competing for your attention. Whether you’re questioning why some ice cream brands use milk powder instead of regular milk or you’re curious about which local ice cream stores are worth braving the sweltering heat for, this guide will answer all the burning questions you never thought to ask. From top ice cream shops in Singapore to the best ice cream brands at your local grocery store, the variety is mind-boggling—if not slightly overwhelming. Oh, and for those who believe there’s no place like home, yes, you can make your own ice cream, though you might need to shell out some cash for an ice cream machine. And if you’re trying to master the art of scooping ice cream out of a carton like a pro, stick around for some tips that’ll make you seem almost professional—almost.</p>

<h3 id="what-is-the-difference-between-ice-cream-and-gelato-and-sorbet">What is the difference between ice cream and gelato and sorbet</h3>

<p>Ice cream, gelato, and sorbet may seem similar, but they each have distinct characteristics that set them apart.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Ice cream is made with cream, milk, sugar, and often eggs, giving it a rich and creamy texture. It typically has a higher fat content (at least 10%) and is churned faster, which incorporates more air and results in a lighter texture.</li>
  <li>Gelato, the Italian cousin of ice cream, uses more milk and less cream, and it’s churned at a slower speed, creating a denser, smoother texture. It also has a lower fat content than traditional ice cream, which allows its flavors to shine more intensely.</li>
  <li>Sorbet, on the other hand, is completely dairy-free, made with fruit puree, sugar, and water. It’s lighter and fruitier, with a refreshing texture that’s often a perfect choice for those avoiding dairy or looking for a more refreshing treat.</li>
</ul>

<p>So while ice cream is creamy and rich, gelato is dense and flavorful, and sorbet is all about vibrant fruit and lightness—each perfect for different moods, climates, and dietary choices.</p>

<h3 id="if-ice-cream-has-no-milk-is-it-still-ice-cream">If ice cream has no milk, is it still ice cream?</h3>

<p>If ice cream uses milk powder instead of fresh milk, it can still technically be considered ice cream. The key factor in traditional ice cream is the use of dairy in some form, and milk powder is simply a dehydrated form of milk. In fact, many commercial ice cream brands use milk powder as a more stable and convenient ingredient to create that creamy texture and rich flavor we all crave. It tastes much worse though</p>

<h3 id="top-ice-cream-brands-in-grocery-stores">Top ice cream brands in grocery stores</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Häagen-Dazs – Known for its premium, rich flavors and creamy texture, Häagen-Dazs is a popular choice for those looking for indulgence in every bite.</li>
  <li>Mövenpick – Offering high-quality, Swiss-made ice cream with natural ingredients, Mövenpick is well-loved for its smooth and flavorful varieties.</li>
  <li>Magnolia – A local favorite, Magnolia offers a variety of classic flavors at more affordable prices, including both regular and low-fat options.</li>
  <li>Breyers – Known for its more natural, simple ingredients, Breyers offers ice cream made with fresh cream and real fruit, appealing to those seeking a less indulgent treat.</li>
  <li>Wall’s – A popular and widely available brand, Wall’s offers affordable and classic ice cream options, including beloved treats like Cornetto and Magnum.</li>
  <li>Nestlé – Offering a range of affordable ice cream options, Nestlé’s ice cream includes both traditional flavors and fun novelties like Drumsticks.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="what-dairy-free-alternative-ice-cream-are-there">What dairy free alternative ice cream are there?</h3>

<p>Dairy-Free Ice Cream Brands in <a href="https://fromhktosg.github.io/grocery/">Grocery Stores</a>:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Ben &amp; Jerry’s Non-Dairy – Offers flavors like Peanut Butter Cup and Chocolate Fudge Brownie made with almond milk.</li>
  <li>Häagen-Dazs Non-Dairy – Features coconut milk-based options such as Chocolate Salted Fudge Truffle and Coconut Almond Fudge.</li>
  <li>Magnolia Lactose-Free – Lactose-free options suitable for those with lactose intolerance.</li>
  <li>Coconut Collab – Coconut milk-based, with flavors like Salted Caramel and Mango &amp; Passionfruit.</li>
  <li>So Delicious – Uses coconut and almond milk for flavors like Cookie Dough and Chocolate Peanut Butter.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="dairy-free-ice-cream-stores-in-singapore">Dairy-Free Ice Cream Stores in Singapore:</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Kind Kones – Offers a variety of plant-based ice cream made from coconut milk, cashew milk, and other plant-based ingredients.</li>
  <li>Creamier – Features both dairy and dairy-free options made with coconut milk, so there’s something for everyone. Creamier’s waffles are divine too! One of my favourite ice cream stores overall</li>
  <li>Oat and about - In the heart of Maxwell</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="best-ice-cream-stores-in-singapore">Best ice cream stores in Singapore</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Birds of Paradise – Famous for its floral-inspired ice cream, Birds of Paradise offers unique flavors like Lychee Raspberry Rose and Saffron &amp; Maple that stand out for their delicate, aromatic profiles.</li>
  <li>Apiary – Known for its rich, smooth ice cream and creative flavors, Apiary serves up a variety of delicious choices like Earl Grey Lavender and Salted Caramel.</li>
  <li>Salted Caramel – Known for its rich, salted caramel flavor and other indulgent options, this shop is a must-visit for ice cream lovers.</li>
  <li>Tom’s Palette – This artisanal ice cream shop is known for its quirky and experimental flavors, such as Chilli Chocolate and Durian, which push the boundaries of traditional ice cream.</li>
  <li>Udders – A local favorite that offers a range of rich and creamy ice cream flavors, including adventurous choices like Whiskey Coffee and Durian.</li>
  <li>Dopa Dopa – Offering premium gelato made with the finest ingredients, Dopa Dopa ice cream delivery brings their creamy flavors like Matcha and Pistachio straight to your door for a delightful treat.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="what-about-the-ice-cream-breads-in-singapore-on-the-street-side">What about the ice cream breads in Singapore on the street side?</h3>

<p>Singapore’s iconic ice cream sandwiches! These are the street-side treats sold by old-school ice cream uncles—a nostalgic part of Singaporean culture.</p>

<h3 id="what-is-singapores-ice-cream-bread">What is Singapore’s Ice Cream Bread?</h3>

<p>It’s a thick slab of ice cream wrapped in colorful bread, often rainbow-hued. Instead of a cone or cup, you get your ice cream nestled inside a slice of soft, fluffy bread—or sandwiched between crispy wafer biscuits if you prefer.</p>

<p><u>Where to Find Street Ice Cream in Singapore?<u></u></u></p>

<p>These ice cream carts are usually found in high-footfall areas like:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Orchard Road (near Takashimaya or Ion)</li>
  <li>Bugis Street</li>
  <li>Chinatown</li>
  <li>Esplanade &amp; Marina Bay</li>
  <li>Outside MRT stations (random pop-ups)</li>
</ul>

<p><u>What Flavors Are There?<u></u></u></p>

<p>The classics include:
✅ Durian – The king of fruits in ice cream form.
✅ Chocolate – Always a safe and creamy choice.
✅ Mint Chocolate Chip – Refreshing and minty.
✅ Sweet Corn – A unique Singaporean favorite.
✅ Red Bean – Old-school, slightly earthy sweetness.
✅ Yam (Taro) – A smooth, mildly sweet purple delight.
✅ Rippled Raspberry, Blueberry, or Strawberry – Swirls of fruity goodness.</p>

<p><u>How Much Does It Cost?<u></u></u></p>

<p>A standard ice cream sandwich from these carts usually costs 2.50 to $3, making it one of the most affordable (and delicious) desserts in Singapore.</p>

<p><u>Why Do People Love It?<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>Cheap and nostalgic – Many Singaporeans grew up eating this as a childhood treat.</li>
  <li>Soft, chewy bread with cold, creamy ice cream – The texture contrast is chef’s kiss.</li>
  <li>A simple pleasure in the Singapore heat – The perfect way to cool down.</li>
</ul>

<p>If you haven’t tried one yet, go grab an ice cream sandwich the next time you see an ice cream uncle!</p>

<h3 id="can-you-make-your-own-ice-cream-at-home">Can you make your own ice cream at home?</h3>

<p>Whether you’re craving a classic vanilla or want to experiment with unique flavors, homemade ice cream can be customized to your liking. The best part? You can make it without an ice cream machine, though having one can make the process quicker and smoother. To get started, you’ll need basic ingredients like cream, milk, sugar, and flavorings such as vanilla extract or fresh fruit. For a smoother texture, consider using heavy cream and condensed milk, which help achieve that rich, creamy consistency.</p>

<p>To make your homemade ice cream even better, you can experiment with unique flavors, mix-ins, or even try a dairy-free ice cream recipe using alternatives like coconut milk or almond milk. You can also try different methods, such as making no-churn ice cream that doesn’t require an ice cream machine.</p>

<p>A simple Google search for easy homemade ice cream recipes will guide you to countless variations. Also, if you’re wondering about the price, ice cream machine costs typically range from $150 to a few hundred dollars, depending on the brand and features. Don’t buy an ice cream machine. It’s too much effort.</p>

<h3 id="how-to-scoop-ice-cream-out-of-a-carton-with-ease">How to scoop ice cream out of a carton with ease?</h3>

<p>Scooping ice cream out of a carton shouldn’t feel like a workout, yet we’ve all been there, battling a rock-hard block of frozen goodness. The best trick? Heat your ice cream scoop over a flame—just a few seconds over a gas stove or with hot water will do the trick. The warmth helps the scoop glide through the ice cream effortlessly, giving you that perfect, round scoop without bending your spoon in the process. If you don’t have a flame, running the scoop under hot water or dipping it in a mug of warm water works just as well. And if patience isn’t your thing, let the carton sit at room temperature for 5–10 minutes—just enough to soften the edges without turning it into a melty mess.</p>

<p>Ice cream’s always a treat! Enjoy.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Singapore" /><category term="food" /><category term="restaurants" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ah, ice cream in Singapore—a delightful treat that somehow manages to be both a cooling respite from the relentless tropical heat and a source of endless debate among dessert enthusiasts.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/ice.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/ice.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Universal Studios Singapore: Best Rides, Tickets &amp;amp; Tips for an Epic Day</title><link href="/singapore-universal-studios/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Universal Studios Singapore: Best Rides, Tickets &amp;amp; Tips for an Epic Day" /><published>2025-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-universal-studios</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-universal-studios/"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to the magical world of Universal Studios Singapore, where thrill-seekers and fans of blockbuster movies can find adventure at every corner.</p>

<p>Opened in 2011, this is the first Universal Studios theme park in Southeast Asia, and if you’re wondering, yes, it’s as exciting as it sounds, with rides, food, and photogenic spots to make your Instagram pop. But how do you get there, what zones will you explore, and most importantly—what are the must-ride attractions? Let’s dive into the best experiences at Universal Studios Singapore, from the jaw-dropping rides to the hidden gems for family fun. So, grab your tickets (we’ll let you know where to find those) and start planning your ultimate day at this cinematic wonderland.</p>

<h3 id="what-is-universal-studios">What is Universal Studios?</h3>

<p>Universal Studios is a globally recognized theme park brand, known for bringing the magic of movies to life with thrilling rides, shows, and immersive experiences. Located in various cities around the world, Universal Studios offers visitors the chance to step into iconic films and TV shows, featuring attractions based on blockbuster franchises like Jurassic Park, Transformers, and Minions. Universal Studios theme parks are designed for all ages, making them perfect for family vacations, adrenaline junkies, and film buffs alike. With its unique combination of cutting-edge technology and beloved movie magic, Universal Studios stands out as a must-visit destination for those seeking excitement and fun. Whether you’re in Universal Studios Singapore, Hollywood, or Orlando, you can expect the same high-energy experience and unforgettable moments.</p>

<h3 id="number-of-universal-studios-around-the-world">Number of Universal Studios around the world</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Universal Studios Hollywood (USA) – The original park, located in California.</li>
  <li>Universal Studios Florida (USA) – Located in Orlando, Florida, it opened in 1990.</li>
  <li>Universal’s Islands of Adventure (USA) – Also in Orlando, this park features more thrill rides and is part of the larger Universal Orlando Resort.</li>
  <li>Universal Studios Singapore (Singapore) – Located on Sentosa Island, it opened in 2011 and is the first in Southeast Asia.</li>
  <li>Universal Studios Japan (Japan) – Located in Osaka, it opened in 2001 and is one of the most popular in Asia.</li>
  <li>Universal Studios Beijing (China) – The newest addition, opening in 2021, offering a mix of familiar and new attractions tailored for the Chinese market.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="when-did-universal-studios-singapore-come-about">When did Universal Studios Singapore come about?</h3>

<p>Universal Studios Singapore officially opened its doors on March 18, 2011, making it the first Universal Studios theme park in Southeast Asia. Located on the popular Sentosa Island, this theme park quickly became one of the top tourist attractions in Singapore, offering a blend of thrilling rides, immersive movie experiences, and family-friendly fun. With its world-class attractions based on famous Universal films like Transformers, Shrek, and Jurassic Park, Universal Studios Singapore has since solidified its place as a must-visit destination for both locals and international visitors. Whether you’re seeking adventure, photo ops, or a day of entertainment, Universal Studios Singapore delivers on all fronts.</p>

<h3 id="how-do-you-get-to-universal-studios-singapore">How do you get to Universal Studios Singapore?</h3>

<p>To get to Universal Studios Singapore, you have a few convenient options:</p>

<ul>
  <li>By MRT: Take the North East Line (NEL) to HarbourFront MRT Station, then transfer to the Sentosa Express at the <a href="https://fromhktosg.github.io/shopping-in-singapore/">VivoCity</a> shopping mall (Level 3).</li>
  <li>By Bus: Public buses such as RWS8 run directly to Sentosa, where Universal Studios Singapore is located.</li>
  <li>By Taxi/Private Car: Simply tell the driver “Universal Studios Singapore” or “Resorts World Sentosa” for a direct drop-off.</li>
  <li>By Walking: If you’re nearby, you can walk via the Sentosa Boardwalk from VivoCity, a scenic 10-minute stroll.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="where-can-you-buy-tickets-to-universal-studios-singapore">Where can you buy tickets to Universal Studios Singapore?</h3>

<p>Finding the best USS ticket price? You can buy tickets to Universal Studios Singapore through several convenient options:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Official Universal Studios Singapore Website: Purchase directly from their site for the latest offers and discounts.</li>
  <li>Resorts World Sentosa Website: Tickets are available here, often with bundled packages for other attractions.</li>
  <li>Authorized Resellers: Popular platforms like Klook, Trip.com, and KKday often offer discounted tickets.</li>
  <li>On-Site: You can also buy tickets at the park entrance, but expect longer queues, especially during peak periods.</li>
  <li>Hotels in Sentosa: Some Sentosa hotels offer ticket sales or exclusive packages for guests.</li>
  <li>Booking online in advance is often the best way to save time and money! Always check the authorized resellers for the best Universal Studios Singapore deals.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="what-are-the-opening-hours-for-universal-studios-singapore">What are the opening hours for Universal Studios Singapore?</h3>

<p>Universal Studios Singapore typically operates with the following hours:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Opening Time: 10:00 AM</li>
  <li>Closing Time: 6:00 PM to 7:00 PM (varies depending on the day or special events)</li>
</ul>

<p>However, these hours can change depending on the time of year, public holidays, or special events like Halloween Horror Nights. It’s always a good idea to check the official Universal Studios Singapore website or Resorts World Sentosa for the most up-to-date schedule before your visit!</p>

<h3 id="what-are-the-current-zones-in-universal-studios-singapore">What are the current zones in Universal Studios Singapore?</h3>

<p>Universal Studios Singapore is divided into several exciting themed zones, each offering unique attractions, dining, and experiences. The current zones in the park include:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Hollywood – The iconic entrance, featuring a replica of the famous Hollywood Walk of Fame and the Universal Globe.</li>
  <li>New York – Step into the bustling streets of New York with attractions like Revenge of the Mummy and Sesame Street Spaghetti Space Chase.</li>
  <li>Sci-Fi City – Home to the thrilling Transformers The Ride: The Ultimate 3D Battle and Battlestar Galactica: HUMAN vs. CYLON roller coasters.</li>
  <li>Ancient Egypt – Journey through ancient times with the Mummy Returns ride and explore Egyptian-themed shopping and dining.</li>
  <li>The Lost World – Featuring Jurassic Park Rapids Adventure and WaterWorld, where you can immerse yourself in prehistoric adventure.</li>
  <li>Far Far Away – Enter the fairy tale kingdom of Shrek, with rides like Shrek 4-D Adventure and Kingdom of Far Far Away.</li>
  <li>Minion Land – The latest addition to the park, where you can meet the mischievous Minions in Despicable Me Minion Mayhem and enjoy other Minion-themed attractions and food.</li>
</ul>

<p>Note: Madagascar is closed in place for Minion Land. These zones create a world of adventure that brings your favorite movies to life, with new updates like Minion Land continuing to keep the experience fresh and exciting!</p>

<h3 id="what-are-the-best-rides-at-universal-studios-singapore">What are the best rides at Universal Studios Singapore?</h3>

<p>Universal Studios Singapore offers a thrilling lineup of rides for all types of adventure seekers. Here are some of the best ones you shouldn’t miss:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Transformers The Ride: The Ultimate 3D Battle – A heart-pounding 3D ride that throws you into an epic battle between Autobots and Decepticons. This is one of the park’s most popular attractions.</li>
  <li>Battlestar Galactica: HUMAN vs. CYLON – An adrenaline-packed, dueling roller coaster with two distinct ride experiences, the HUMAN (seated) and the CYLON (inverted). Spoiler - this one loops</li>
  <li>Revenge of the Mummy – A high-speed indoor roller coaster that takes you on a thrilling journey through ancient Egypt, complete with twists, turns, and surprises. Spoiler - this one goes backwards</li>
  <li>Jurassic Park Rapids Adventure – A water-based ride that immerses you in the world of Jurassic Park, featuring thrilling rapids and a dramatic T. rex finale.</li>
  <li>Shrek 4-D Adventure – A fun and family-friendly 4D movie experience with Shrek and friends, combining thrilling visuals with motion seats.</li>
  <li>Despicable Me Minion Mayhem – A hilarious, family-friendly 3D simulator ride where you become a Minion for an unforgettable adventure.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="is-universal-studios-singapore-kid-friendly">Is Universal Studios Singapore kid friendly?</h3>

<p>Universal Studios Singapore is definitely kid-friendly, offering a wide range of attractions suitable for children of all ages. While there are thrilling rides for adrenaline junkies, many attractions cater specifically to younger audiences. Here are some kid-friendly options, along with their height requirements:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Shrek 4-D Adventure – A family-friendly 4D movie experience. (No height requirement).</li>
  <li>Despicable Me Minion Mayhem – A fun 3D simulator ride, perfect for kids. Minimum height: 102 cm.</li>
  <li>Sesame Street Spaghetti Space Chase – A gentle ride with fun, themed around Sesame Street. Minimum height: 92 cm.</li>
  <li>Jurassic Park Rapids Adventure – While thrilling, it’s family-friendly, though it might be a little intense for very young kids. Minimum height: 107 cm.</li>
</ul>

<p>While the park offers a lot for younger visitors, there are also plenty of rides and experiences designed for older kids and adults. Plus, with its colorful zones and character meet-and-greets, there’s never a dull moment!</p>

<h3 id="where-can-you-get-the-best-photos-in-universal-studios-singapore">Where can you get the best photos in Universal Studios Singapore?</h3>

<p>Here are some of the top spots to capture memorable moments:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Universal Globe – The iconic spinning globe right at the entrance is a must for any visitor. Get a shot with the globe in the background, but don’t forget to wear a fun headband for extra flair!</li>
  <li>Hollywood Boulevard – The famous Walk of Fame with its star-studded sidewalks provides the perfect backdrop for a glamorous photo op.</li>
  <li>Minion Land – With its vibrant yellow theme and mischievous Minions, this zone is a fun spot for lively and playful photos. Grab a Minion-themed headband to match!</li>
  <li>New York Street – Snap a picture in front of the Sesame Street or Revenge of the Mummy settings. The New York streetscapes are perfect for that city vibe.</li>
  <li>Jurassic Park – The towering gates of Jurassic Park and the life-sized dinosaurs make for thrilling photo moments. Maybe wear a dinosaur-themed headband to go with it!</li>
  <li>Far Far Away Castle – With the fairy-tale castle as the backdrop, you can channel your inner princess (or ogre) for a photo. A whimsical headband would complete the look!</li>
  <li>Transformer’s Headquarters – Strike a powerful pose in front of Optimus Prime or the Decepticons. A cool headband or even a Transformer-themed one adds to the fun.</li>
</ul>

<p>Don’t forget to pick up one of those fun headbands from the gift shops around the park! They’ll not only add to your look but make your photos extra memorable. They’re not cheap though ($7 to $15).</p>

<h3 id="what-is-there-to-eat-in-universal-studios-singapore">What is there to eat in Universal Studios Singapore?</h3>

<p>Universal Studios Singapore offers a wide variety of dining options to suit all tastes, from quick bites to themed restaurants. Here are some of the highlights:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Mel’s Drive-In (Hollywood) – Enjoy classic American diner fare like burgers, fries, and milkshakes in a 50s-themed setting.</li>
  <li>Loui’s Pizza (New York) – If you’re craving Italian, this spot serves up delicious pizzas and pastas.</li>
  <li>KT’s Grill (New York) – Savor hearty meals such as steaks, grilled fish, and BBQ dishes in a cozy, rustic setting.</li>
  <li>Jurassic Park Food Court (The Lost World) – For some prehistoric bites, try local favorites like chicken rice, satay, and laksa in a jungle-themed food court.</li>
  <li>Gloria’s Snack Shack (Sci-Fi City) – Grab a quick snack like fried chicken or hot dogs while enjoying the futuristic ambiance.</li>
  <li>Fried Chicken &amp; Co. (Sci-Fi City) – Perfect for fried chicken lovers, this spot offers crispy, golden chicken served with sides.</li>
  <li>Despicable Me Minion Mayhem (Minion Land) – A family-friendly spot serving kid-approved meals like chicken nuggets, fries, and pizzas.</li>
</ul>

<p>For snacks and sweet treats, don’t miss the ice cream stalls scattered throughout the park. I’d remember to pack water and some snacks though! Things are expensive within the grounds ($5 a bottle of water??)</p>

<h3 id="how-long-should-you-spend-at-universal-studios-singapore">How long should you spend at Universal Studios Singapore?</h3>

<p>The ideal time to spend at Universal Studios Singapore depends on your interests, but generally, a full day (6-8 hours) is recommended to make the most of the park.</p>

<p>Whether it’s worth getting a Fast Pass (or Express Pass) at Universal Studios Singapore depends on a few factors, but generally, it can be a great investment for a more stress-free experience:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Long Lines for Popular Rides: Rides like Transformers, Battlestar Galactica, and Jurassic Park Rapids Adventure can have long wait times, especially during peak hours or weekends. The Fast Pass allows you to skip these lines, saving you up to 1-2 hours in some cases.</li>
  <li>Limited Time: If you’re on a time crunch or visiting during busy seasons (public holidays, weekends), a Fast Pass can ensure you get to enjoy more of the park without spending too much time in queues.</li>
  <li>Peak Seasons: During holidays like Chinese New Year, school vacations, or weekends, the park tends to get crowded. In these times, a Fast Pass is well worth it, especially if you want to experience the best rides.</li>
  <li>Budget Considerations: While the Fast Pass does cost extra, it’s worth it if you’re planning to maximize your day and minimize time spent waiting in lines. It’s a good option for families or groups with young kids, or those who want to fit more into their day.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="alternatives-of-universal-studios-singapore-for-those-in-singapore">Alternatives of Universal Studios Singapore for those in Singapore</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Tokyo Disneyland &amp; DisneySea (Japan) – Experience classic Disney magic and exclusive attractions.</li>
  <li>Universal Studios Japan (Osaka) – Enjoy exciting rides, including Harry Potter World and Jurassic Park.</li>
  <li>Legoland Malaysia Resort (Johor Bahru) – Ideal for families with younger kids, featuring Lego-themed fun and a water park.</li>
  <li>Genting SkyWorlds (Malaysia) – A theme park with a mix of thrilling rides and immersive experiences in the cool hilltop setting of Genting Highlands.</li>
  <li>Everland (South Korea) – A large theme park offering a variety of rides, shows, and a safari experience for all ages.</li>
</ul>

<p>I personally think USS is worth visiting once during the day and once at night during Halloween Horrors night.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Singapore" /><category term="fun" /><category term="society" /><category term="things to do" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to the magical world of Universal Studios Singapore, where thrill-seekers and fans of blockbuster movies can find adventure at every corner.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/uss.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/uss.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Guide to Singapore’s Disappearing Dialects: Teochew, Hokkien &amp;amp; Cantonesee</title><link href="/singapore-dialects/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Guide to Singapore’s Disappearing Dialects: Teochew, Hokkien &amp;amp; Cantonesee" /><published>2025-02-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-dialects</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-dialects/"><![CDATA[<p>Once a staple of everyday conversation, dialects in Singapore are now teetering on the edge of extinction.</p>

<p>Because who needs Teochew, Hokkien, or Cantonese when we have perfectly good English and Mandarin, right? According to the latest government surveys, less than 10% of young Singaporeans speak a Chinese dialect at home, a sharp decline from previous generations. With the rise of standardized Mandarin and the convenience of English, dialects are disappearing faster than your Wi-Fi connection in an MRT tunnel. But beyond nostalgia, these languages hold cultural stories, unique expressions, and a deep sense of identity that textbooks simply can’t replicate. Thankfully, initiatives like dialect classes, digital resources, and even social media influencers are making an effort to keep these linguistic treasures alive—so if you’ve ever wanted to impress your grandparents or speak to <a href="https://fromhktosg.github.io/hk-versus-sg-food/">hawker center</a> aunties in the most authentic way possible, now’s your chance.</p>

<h3 id="what-are-dialects">What are dialects?</h3>

<p>Dialects are regional or social variations of a language, shaped by history, geography, and culture, often carrying unique pronunciation, vocabulary, and grammar. Unlike standard languages, dialects evolve organically within communities, reflecting generations of tradition, identity, and heritage. In today’s world of globalization and digital communication, many dialects are at risk of fading, as dominant languages take over daily conversations, education, and media. However, the rise of AI translation, language learning apps, and cultural preservation movements has sparked renewed interest in reviving endangered dialects. With trending searches on “language diversity,” “heritage languages,” and “multilingual learning,” it’s clear that people are recognizing the importance of preserving dialects before they vanish completely.</p>

<h3 id="what-dialects-are-there-in-singapore">What dialects are there in Singapore?</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Hokkien (福建话) – A Southern Min dialect originating from Fujian, China, Hokkien was historically the most widely spoken Chinese dialect in Singapore, especially among early Chinese immigrants.</li>
  <li>Cantonese (广东话) – Hailing from Guangdong and Hong Kong, Cantonese was commonly spoken among the Chinese community in Singapore, particularly in business and entertainment circles.</li>
  <li>Teochew (潮州话) – Another variant of the Southern Min dialect, Teochew comes from the Chaoshan region of Guangdong and was the dominant dialect among many early Chinese settlers.</li>
  <li>Hakka (客家话) – With roots in China’s Hakka-speaking regions, this dialect was traditionally spoken by the Hakka community, known for their resilience and migratory history.</li>
  <li>Hainanese (海南话) – Originating from Hainan Island, this dialect was once commonly heard among Hainanese immigrants, particularly in the food and beverage industry (think chicken rice hawkers).</li>
  <li>Malay Dialects – While Standard Malay is the national language, regional Malay dialects like Javanese and Boyanese (Baweanese) are still spoken by some within Singapore’s Malay community.</li>
  <li>Indian Dialects – Aside from Tamil, which is an official language, dialects such as Hokkien-influenced Peranakan Tamil and Malayalees’ Malayalam can still be heard within certain communities.</li>
</ul>

<p>Despite their historical significance, many of these dialects are now fading due to the emphasis on English and Mandarin in education and media.</p>

<h3 id="are-dialects-disappearing">Are dialects disappearing?</h3>

<p>Yes, dialects are disappearing, and Singapore is no exception. According to the Singapore Census 2020, only 7.8% of Chinese households reported using dialects as their main language at home, a steep drop from 18.2% in 2000. This decline is largely due to language policies promoting English and Mandarin, leaving dialects struggling to stay relevant in everyday life. With fewer young Singaporeans speaking Hokkien, Teochew, or Cantonese, dialects are fading from public spaces, traditional media, and even family conversations. As globalization, digital communication, and language homogenization take over, the urgency to preserve heritage languages, linguistic diversity, and cultural identity has never been greater. Be nice to your hawker center aunties!</p>

<h3 id="why-is-it-important-to-preserve-dialects">Why is it important to preserve dialects?</h3>

<p>Preserving dialects is crucial for maintaining cultural identity, heritage, and intergenerational connections. These languages carry unique expressions, oral traditions, and historical context that standardized languages like Mandarin or English often cannot fully capture. In Singapore, where dialects are rapidly fading, losing them means losing a key part of the nation’s multilingual diversity and rich immigrant history. Studies show that bilingual or multilingual individuals often have better cognitive flexibility, meaning that keeping dialects alive isn’t just about culture—it’s also about enhancing brain function and communication skills. As interest in heritage language preservation grows, safeguarding dialects ensures that future generations can still access their roots, understand traditional customs, and keep family bonds strong.</p>

<h3 id="initiatives-in-singapore-happening-to-preserve-dialect">Initiatives in Singapore happening to preserve dialect</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Speak Mandarin Campaign – While primarily promoting Mandarin, this initiative also encourages the preservation of dialects in Singapore by raising awareness about cultural heritage and encouraging older generations to pass on their dialects.</li>
  <li>Dialects in Schools – Some schools have started incorporating dialect classes or cultural heritage programs into their curriculum to teach younger generations about dialects and their importance in multicultural Singapore.</li>
  <li>Media and Entertainment – Local TV programs and radio stations, such as Mediacorp’s “Kopi Talk,” feature dialect content to keep dialects alive in the media and make them accessible to younger audiences, promoting language diversity.</li>
  <li>Public Awareness Campaigns – Organizations like the Singapore Hokkien Huay Kuan have launched campaigns to preserve dialects through workshops, events, and online content, fostering a renewed appreciation for Singapore’s linguistic heritage.</li>
  <li>Community and Cultural Events – Cultural institutions, such as the Chinese Heritage Centre, host events and exhibitions that highlight the history and importance of dialects in Singapore’s development, encouraging their use among visitors and participants.</li>
  <li>Language Apps and Resources – Digital initiatives, including language learning apps and online platforms, are being developed to teach and preserve dialects by providing interactive learning experiences for all ages, making dialect education more accessible.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="where-else-can-you-learn-dialects-in-singapore">Where else can you learn dialects in Singapore?</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Singapore Hokkien Huay Kuan – Offers dialect classes and cultural programs to preserve and teach Hokkien and other Chinese dialects.</li>
  <li>The Chinese Heritage Centre – Hosts workshops and events on dialects, with opportunities to learn through immersive cultural experiences.</li>
  <li>Community Centres – Various community centres across Singapore offer dialect classes, especially for older generations wanting to pass on their language skills.</li>
  <li>Dialect Clubs and Associations – Organizations like the Teochew Poit Ip Huay Kuan provide educational resources and community-driven dialect learning programs.</li>
  <li>Online Platforms – Websites and apps such as DialectHub provide interactive lessons and resources for learning dialects at your own pace.</li>
</ul>

<p>I expect dialects to disappear in a generation’s time. Unfortunate.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Singapore" /><category term="society" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Once a staple of everyday conversation, dialects in Singapore are now teetering on the edge of extinction.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/dialects.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/dialects.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Flu in Singapore: Symptoms, Prevention &amp;amp; Flu Shot Guide</title><link href="/singapore-flu-cold-sick/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Flu in Singapore: Symptoms, Prevention &amp;amp; Flu Shot Guide" /><published>2025-02-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-flu-cold-sick</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-flu-cold-sick/"><![CDATA[<p>The flu in Singapore isn’t just a minor inconvenience—it’s an annual uninvited guest that spreads faster than a lunchtime queue at a hawker centre.</p>

<p>It’s been nasty lately. Caused by the influenza virus, this highly contagious illness is known for symptoms like fever, chills, sore throat, and the sudden realization that you should have gotten your flu shot. The flu spreads easily through respiratory droplets (aka coughs and sneezes) and contaminated surfaces, making crowded MRT trains and office spaces prime flu-sharing hotspots. The best way to avoid spending a week in bed regretting your choices? Get vaccinated regularly, because flu shots aren’t just for the elderly or hypochondriacs—they’re for anyone who prefers to stay healthy and avoid infecting everyone around them. Flu vaccination in Singapore is essential not just for prevention but also for minimizing the risk of complications, so it’s crucial to know how often you need to get a flu jab and what other vaccines are recommended for adults and children alike.</p>

<h3 id="what-is-the-flu">What is the flu?</h3>

<p>The flu, or influenza, is a viral infection that affects the respiratory system, causing symptoms like fever, cough, sore throat, body aches, and fatigue. In Singapore, the flu season typically peaks during the rainy months, making it more important than ever to stay vigilant.</p>

<h3 id="how-does-the-flu-spread">How does the flu spread?</h3>

<p>Caused by the influenza virus, the flu spreads easily through droplets from coughs and sneezes, making crowded public spaces like malls, offices, and schools high-risk zones for infection. While the flu can sometimes be mild, it can also lead to serious complications, especially for vulnerable groups such as the elderly, young children, and those with weakened immune systems. Protecting yourself with a flu vaccine is one of the most effective ways to prevent the flu, ensuring you don’t become a part of the annual Singapore flu outbreak.</p>

<h3 id="how-to-prevent-the-flu">How to prevent the flu?</h3>

<p>Preventing the flu in Singapore requires a combination of good hygiene practices, lifestyle choices, and getting vaccinated. Here are some key methods:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Get a Flu Vaccine: Annual flu shots are the best way to protect yourself from getting the flu and its complications.</li>
  <li>Wash Hands Regularly: Proper hand hygiene, especially after touching common surfaces, helps reduce the risk of spreading the virus.</li>
  <li>Practice Respiratory Hygiene: Cover your mouth and nose with a tissue or your elbow when coughing or sneezing to avoid spreading germs.</li>
  <li>Stay Home When Sick: If you’re feeling unwell, it’s best to stay home and avoid infecting others in crowded places.</li>
  <li>Boost Your Immune System: Maintain a healthy diet, exercise regularly, and get plenty of sleep to keep your immune system strong.</li>
</ul>

<p>By following these simple yet effective measures, you can significantly lower your chances of catching and spreading the flu in Singapore.</p>

<h3 id="why-should-you-vaccinate">Why should you vaccinate?</h3>

<p>Vaccinating against the flu in Singapore is essential to protect not just yourself but also those around you. The flu vaccine helps reduce the risk of severe illness, hospitalisation, and even death, especially among vulnerable groups like the elderly, young children, and individuals with underlying health conditions. With flu season peaking during the rainy months in Singapore, getting vaccinated is a simple yet highly effective way to avoid being part of the yearly flu outbreaks that impact schools, offices, and crowded public spaces. Flu vaccination also helps prevent the spread of the virus, reducing the overall burden on Singapore’s healthcare system during peak flu periods. Whether you’re planning to travel, want to safeguard your family, or simply prefer to avoid the discomfort of the flu, getting your annual flu shot is a proactive step towards staying healthy in Singapore.</p>

<h3 id="how-often-do-you-need-to-get-a-flu-jab">How often do you need to get a flu jab?</h3>

<p>In Singapore, it’s recommended to get a flu jab annually, as the influenza virus strains can change each year.</p>

<h3 id="where-can-you-get-the-flu-jab">Where can you get the flu jab?</h3>

<p>You can get the flu jab at several convenient locations in Singapore:</p>

<ul>
  <li>General Practitioners (GPs): Many GP / doctor clinics across Singapore offer flu vaccinations throughout the year.</li>
  <li>Polyclinics: Singapore’s public healthcare network provides flu shots at affordable rates, especially for eligible groups.</li>
  <li>Hospitals: Private and public hospitals in Singapore also offer flu vaccinations, often with added health check-ups.</li>
  <li>Pharmacies: Some large pharmacies, like Guardian and Watsons, provide flu vaccination services at selected locations.</li>
  <li>Workplace Clinics: Many companies in Singapore arrange flu vaccination drives for employees to reduce workplace illness.</li>
</ul>

<p>These options ensure that flu vaccines are easily accessible for everyone in Singapore.</p>

<h3 id="how-do-i-know-what-vaccines-i-need">How do I know what vaccines I need?</h3>

<p>To know which vaccines you need in Singapore, consult your healthcare provider who can assess your age, health status, lifestyle, and travel plans. They will recommend essential vaccinations such as the flu vaccine, COVID-19 vaccine, and others specific to your needs, like MMR (measles, mumps, rubella) or travel vaccines. You can also refer to Singapore’s Ministry of Health vaccination guidelines for up-to-date information on recommended vaccines. Ensuring you’re up-to-date on essential vaccinations helps protect you and those around you from preventable diseases.</p>

<p>Remember it is socially responsible to stay home if you are sick!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Singapore" /><category term="medicine" /><category term="doctor" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The flu in Singapore isn’t just a minor inconvenience—it’s an annual uninvited guest that spreads faster than a lunchtime queue at a hawker centre.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/flu.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/flu.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>