<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2023-10-01T09:59:20+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">From HK to SG | Expat Living Guide in Singapore</title><entry><title type="html">Should I join a Singapore country clubs?</title><link href="/singapore-country-clubs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Should I join a Singapore country clubs?" /><published>2023-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-country-clubs</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-country-clubs/"><![CDATA[<p>I played tennis at the Capella a couple weeks back. Whilst it isn’t a country club, the establishment in its grandeur and luxury sure felt like one. Having personally experienced the allure of country clubs while being part of one in Hong Kong, I was naturally drawn to explore what Singapore’s country clubs have to offer. Today, we’ll unpack a little about country clubs, including the verdant landscapes and luxurious amenities and weighing the question on everyone’s mind: Are they worth it? Join me as we unravel the world of Singaporean country clubs and discover whether these exclusive enclaves truly live up to their reputation.</p>

<h4 id="what-are-the-5-cs-that-all-singaporeans-revere">What are the 5 C’s that all Singaporeans revere?</h4>

<p>In the realm of Singaporean culture and lifestyle, the “5 Cs” have long held a special place. Historically symbolizing cash, car, credit card, condominium and country club, these markers of affluence have shaped aspirations and defined success for generations of Singaporeans. These five Cs are:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Cash: Refers to the pursuit of wealth and financial success</li>
  <li>Car: Singapore’s car prices are among the highest in the world due to significant taxes and fees, making car ownership a status symbol</li>
  <li>Credit Card: Self-explanatory, although getting a credit card was much more difficult a generation back</li>
  <li>Condo: Owned private real estate versus government housing (HDBs) is much more valuable (and comfortable)</li>
  <li>Country Club: Joining an exclusive country club is considered a symbol of prestige</li>
</ul>

<p>While the concept of the five C’s is often taken lightly, many Singaporeans adhere to its philosophy and aspire to ‘collect them all.’</p>

<h4 id="how-did-country-clubs-come-about-in-singapore">How did country clubs come about in Singapore?</h4>

<p>The roots of country clubs can be traced back to a time when colonial influences and British traditions shaped Singapore’s landscape. These clubs emerged as enclaves where colonial expatriates gathered to escape the tropical heat, indulge in recreational activities, and foster a sense of community. Over the decades, these exclusive retreats have evolved to become more diverse, catering to the changing demographics and interests of Singapore’s populace. However, this is also the reason why many country clubs are named after particular countries i.e. The American Club.</p>

<h4 id="why-should-you-join-a-country-club">Why should you join a country club?</h4>

<p>During my membership at a country club in Hong Kong, I dedicated the majority of my time to utilizing their tennis facilities, spending six days a week there for training. In fact, the country club became my third most frequently visited location, following my school and home. A good amount of my friends hung out there too. Looking back, I loved being part of that community. Here’s why there’s merit in joining a country club -</p>

<ul>
  <li>Sanctuary lifestyle: At their core, country clubs in Singapore serve as sanctuaries, offering members an escape from the hustle and bustle of urban living. They are nestled amidst lush greenery, providing an oasis of tranquility where one can reconnect with nature, unwind, and recharge. It’s a place where time seems to slow down, and the stresses of daily life fade into the background</li>
  <li>Facilities: One of the defining features of country clubs is their extensive range of recreational facilities. While golf courses remain a hallmark, these clubs have diversified to include tennis courts, swimming pools, gyms, and even equestrian facilities. This diversity ensures that members of all ages can find activities that cater to their interests and fitness levels</li>
  <li>Fine dining: From casual poolside snacks to elegant fine dining experiences, these clubs boast a variety of dining options. Members can savor an array of cuisines and delight in gastronomic adventures, often accompanied by scenic views of the club’s sprawling grounds</li>
  <li>Networking: Beyond leisure and sports, country clubs play a pivotal role as social hubs. They provide a platform for networking and building relationships among individuals from diverse backgrounds. Memberships often span generations, creating a sense of community and continuity that extends beyond the club’s facilities</li>
  <li>Family activities: Many country clubs recognize the importance of family bonding. They offer family-friendly amenities, including children’s play areas, kid-focused activities, and even educational programs. These clubs become places where generations come together to create lasting memories</li>
  <li>Exclusive Events and Entertainment: Country clubs often host exclusive events, including gala dinners, themed parties, and cultural celebrations. These gatherings provide members with opportunities to socialize and enjoy unique entertainment experiences</li>
  <li>Prestige and Status: Joining a prestigious country club can enhance one’s social status and reputation, as these clubs are often associated with affluence and success</li>
  <li>Legacy and Tradition: Some members value the sense of tradition and heritage associated with country clubs. Membership often spans generations, creating a sense of continuity and belonging</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="top-country-clubs-in-singapore">Top country clubs in Singapore</h4>

<p>So if you’re a little more convinced in joining one, here are some of the top country clubs in Singapore:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Singapore Island Country Club (SICC): SICC is one of the oldest and most renowned country clubs in Singapore. It has multiple locations, including Bukit and Island locations. SICC offers members access to golf courses, tennis courts, swimming pools, fine dining, and social events</li>
  <li>The Tanglin Club: Established in 1865, The Tanglin Club is one of Singapore’s oldest and most prestigious clubs. It provides members with dining options, sports facilities, spa services, and a variety of social events</li>
  <li>Sentosa Golf Club: Known for its stunning golf courses with panoramic views of the sea, Sentosa Golf Club offers a world-class golfing experience. It has hosted prestigious golf tournaments and is recognized for its challenging courses</li>
  <li>Keppel Club: Keppel Club offers a range of sports facilities, including golf, tennis, and swimming. Members can also enjoy dining options and a relaxed atmosphere within the club’s premises</li>
  <li>Warren Golf &amp; Country Club: Situated in the lush Warren Golf Course, this country club offers golfing, dining, and social activities. It’s known for its scenic golf course and serene environment</li>
  <li>Seletar Country Club: Located near Seletar Airport, this club offers a golf course, swimming pool, tennis courts, and dining options. It has a family-friendly atmosphere and organizes various events for members</li>
  <li>Orchid Country Club: Orchid Country Club is known for its beautiful landscapes and golf courses. It offers a wide range of amenities, including bowling, swimming, and dining. The club has a resort-like ambiance.</li>
  <li>Raffles Country Club: Raffles Country Club has two locations, Lake Course and Palm Course. It provides golfing, dining, and event facilities. Note that part of the Palm Course was acquired for development, and the club will cease operations there.</li>
  <li>Marina Bay Golf Course: While not a traditional country club, Marina Bay Golf Course is known for its stunning location with city skyline views. It offers an 18-hole golf course and dining facilities.</li>
  <li>The American club: Better membership deal if you’re American. Really good location near Orchard / Tanglin. A good amount of my friends are a part of this one</li>
  <li>The British Club: Near the Swiss Club in Bukit Timah. Has an amazing spa center and pool complex</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="what-are-memberships-like">What are memberships like?</h4>

<p>On to the elephant in the room - how do memberships work?</p>

<p>Country clubs in Singapore typically offer various types of memberships to cater to the diverse preferences and needs of individuals and families. These memberships often include:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Ordinary or Full Membership: This is the most comprehensive and prestigious membership category, providing access to all club facilities and amenities, including golf courses, sports facilities, dining, and social events. Full members often have voting rights and may be required to pay an initiation fee and monthly dues. Some memberships are transferable - obviously, a transferable one is more expensive</li>
  <li>Associate Membership: Associate members enjoy most of the privileges of full membership but may have restrictions, such as limited access to certain facilities or no voting rights. Associate memberships are often available to family members of full members or individuals who do not meet the criteria for full membership.</li>
  <li>Social or Non-Golfing Membership: Social members typically have access to the club’s dining, social events, and some recreational facilities but do not have golfing privileges. This membership category is suitable for individuals or families who are primarily interested in the club’s social aspects.</li>
  <li>Corporate Membership: Corporate memberships are often offered to businesses and organizations. They provide access to club facilities for employees and clients. Corporate members may also use the club for business events and meetings.</li>
  <li>Term Membership: Term memberships are typically offered for a specific duration, such as one or two years. They are suitable for individuals who may want to experience the club for a limited time without a long-term commitment.</li>
  <li>Family Membership: Family memberships extend privileges to the member, their spouse, and dependent children. It provides a family-friendly environment with access to family-oriented amenities</li>
  <li>Sport membership: Primary access to sports facilities; often without voting rights</li>
</ul>

<p>To grossly summarize how much a country club membership costs -</p>

<ul>
  <li>Entry-level country clubs might have initiation fees ranging from SGD 5,000 to SGD 10,000, with annual subscription fees of around SGD 1,000 to SGD 3,000</li>
  <li>Mid-tier country clubs may require initiation fees of SGD 15,000 to SGD 30,000 or more, with annual subscription fees ranging from SGD 2,000 to SGD 5,000 or higher</li>
  <li>Premium and prestigious country clubs can have initiation fees exceeding SGD 50,000, and annual subscription fees can be in the range of SGD 5,000 to SGD 10,000 or more</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="so-are-country-clubs-worth-it">So are country clubs worth it?</h4>

<p>It depends. Ultimately, it’s often more about status, but if you spend a significant amount of time there and a country club offers a place for your children to socialize, it can be justifiable.</p>

<h4 id="what-alternatives-to-country-clubs-are-there">What alternatives to country clubs are there?</h4>

<p>Aka where do those more money conscious or less wealthy go to.</p>

<p><u>Hometeam NS<u>
Hometeam NS operates clubhouses across Singapore, providing a range of facilities for recreational and social activities. These clubhouses are designed to cater to NSmen (National Servicemen), their families, and NS supporters. You can find amenities such as swimming pools for leisure and fitness, well-equipped gyms, sports courts for various activities like badminton and basketball, and dining options where you can enjoy meals with family and friends. Hometeam NS offers affordable memberships that grant access to these facilities, making it a popular choice for those seeking an inclusive and community-oriented environment</u></u></p>

<p><u>Condo Clubhouses:<u>
Private Condo Facilities: Many condominiums in Singapore offer exclusive clubhouses and amenities within their complexes. These condo clubhouses are typically reserved for residents and their guests, providing a convenient and private space for leisure and social gatherings. Depending on the condominium, you may find features like swimming pools for residents to relax and cool off, fully equipped fitness centers for workouts, BBQ pits for outdoor gatherings, and function rooms suitable for events and celebrations. Residents can enjoy these facilities within the comfort of their condo community, fostering a sense of belonging and convenience</u></u></p>

<p><u>Shopping Malls:<u>
Singapore boasts a plethora of world-class shopping malls that offer more than just shopping opportunities. These malls are vibrant hubs where people gather to indulge in various forms of entertainment, dining, and recreation. Inside these malls, you can find entertainment zones with arcade games, cinemas screening the latest films, food courts serving diverse cuisines, and indoor playgrounds designed for children's enjoyment. Popular malls like Orchard Central, VivoCity, and Jewel Changi Airport provide a wide range of recreational activities, ensuring that visitors can have a full day of fun and relaxation.</u></u></p>

<p><u>Community Centers (CCs) and Community Clubs<u>
Singapore's network of Community Centers (CCs) and Residents' Committees (RCs) plays a vital role in fostering community engagement and organizing a diverse array of activities. These centers serve as focal points for residents to participate in social, cultural, and recreational events. CCs and RCs offer programs such as fitness classes, art workshops, sports events, and cultural performances. Some of these centers also feature sports facilities like tennis courts and basketball courts, providing opportunities for physical activities and bonding with neighbors. Membership options are often available, allowing residents to access these facilities and programs at reasonable rates, enhancing community spirit and cohesion.</u></u></p>

<p>Honestly, the options above sound pretty sound lame compared to a country club, but there’s nothing wrong with being more frugal and responsible. Ultimately, a country club provides its own merits and it’s understandable that Singaporeans want to strive to be part of one. I know I will. As usual, don’t forget to subscribe so you don’t miss out on more content!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="country clubs" /><category term="luxury" /><category term="Singapore" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I played tennis at the Capella a couple weeks back. Whilst it isn’t a country club, the establishment in its grandeur and luxury sure felt like one. Having personally experienced the allure of country clubs while being part of one in Hong Kong, I was naturally drawn to explore what Singapore’s country clubs have to offer. Today, we’ll unpack a little about country clubs, including the verdant landscapes and luxurious amenities and weighing the question on everyone’s mind: Are they worth it? Join me as we unravel the world of Singaporean country clubs and discover whether these exclusive enclaves truly live up to their reputation.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/club.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/club.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Why do Singaporean adults still live with their parents?</title><link href="/singapore-living-with-parents/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why do Singaporean adults still live with their parents?" /><published>2023-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-living-with-parents</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-living-with-parents/"><![CDATA[<p>I left my parents’ home at the age of 18 when I moved to the States for college. Interestingly, most of my peers in Hong Kong, as well as my friends in Singapore, continue to live in their family homes if they remained in the same country post college graduation. Even in the case of marriage, a significant percentage of them choose to reside with their families unless they have accumulated enough resources to afford their own place. This trend is notably common in these two Asian countries, in contrast to the United States. Today, we’ll delve into the phenomenon of adults living with their parents and explore its advantages and disadvantages.</p>

<h4 id="why-do-singaporeans-live-with-their-parents">Why do Singaporeans live with their parents?</h4>

<p>An estimated 97% of unmarried individuals between the ages of 15 and 34 lived with their parents in 2013. Whilst this number is from ten years ago, it’s still unfathomable for me to comprehend why someone would loiter at home for such a lengthy time frame. It’s a fascinating aspect of Singapore culture that often raises eyebrows among our international friends. Let’s unpack the reasons behind this unique lifestyle choice.</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Cost of living
Let’s not sugarcoat it; living in Singapore can burn a hole in your pocket. With sky-high property prices and rent that can make your eyes water, it’s no wonder that many young adults opt to bunk with mum and dad. This financial strategy lets us save our hard-earned cash for other life goals, like furthering our education, kick-starting our careers, or exploring the world. This is the reason I hear the most from my local friends. It makes sense but also strips away from an independent lifestyle that can be priceless. We’ll touch on this later on.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Filial piety and family values
Now, here’s where it gets heartwarming. Rooted in Confucian values, it’s all about respecting and caring for our parents, especially as they grow older. Living under the same roof is seen as a tangible way to show love and respect. It’s like a warm, perpetual family hug that keeps family bonds strong. However, I see staying at home as a poor reason for filial piety, especially amongst the younger generation. You can still be taking care of your parents without living with them.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>A built-in support system
Who doesn’t love a solid support system? Living with family means you’ve got a tribe to rely on—be it for sage advice, a hand with chores, or simply some good old-fashioned company. In fact, many of us owe our sanity to this network of support. Grandparents often join in on the fun, pitching in with childcare duties and adding extra layers of love to the mix.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Practicality and convenience
Living at home is the epitome of convenience. No more worries about grocery shopping, cooking, or laundry—parents often take the reins. This means more time and energy to dedicate to careers and personal growth. Plus, parents are usually more than happy to lend a helping hand—whether it’s whipping up breakfast or offering a ride to work. I hate this reason personally given it just sounds like freeloading.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Lack of pressure to move out
Unlike in some Western cultures, where moving out is the badge of adulthood, Singaporeans face zero societal pressure to vacate the family nest. In fact, it’s perfectly normal, widely accepted, and definitely no reason to raise an eyebrow. This is something that is changing in Singapore’s societal fabric, and something I want all Singaporeans to challenge.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>And there you have it, folks! Living with parents in Singapore is about more than just saving a few bucks; it’s a reflection of our rich cultural values of filial piety, strong family bonds, and unwavering support. Whether it’s for financial stability, emotional connection, or the sheer joy of sharing life’s moments with loved ones, bunking with Mom and Dad is a lifestyle choice that’s here to stay.</p>

<h4 id="whats-the-deal-with-multi-generational-living">What’s the deal with multi-generational living?</h4>

<p>In many Singaporean families, it’s common for several generations to reside under one roof, even when parents are old and have children of their own. In fact, the number of resident households increased from 1,145,900 households in 2010 to 1,372,600 households in 2020. Not to go too much into this topic, but root causes of filial piety, economic considerations and practical benefits contribute to such phenomenon.</p>

<h4 id="the-flip-side-and-the-challenges-that-come-with-staying-at-home">The flip side and the challenges that come with staying at home</h4>

<p>Between 1990 and 2020 the number of those under 35 who lived alone or with non-family members grew from 33,400 to 51,300 (The economist). Additionally, local real estate portal PropertyGuru showed seven in 10 respondents between the ages of 22 and 39 were considering moving out. This shows the growing trend of Singaporeans leaving home. Let’s unpack the reasons why.</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Space Squeeze
Singapore is a tiny red dot on the map, and boy, my friends feel it when they’re all cozying up in the same apartment. With property prices soaring higher than our aspirations, limited living space can be a real buzzkill. Forget personal space; it’s more like “Can I please have any space?”</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Independence
Living with your parents well into adulthood can make it tough to carve out your own identity. While other twenty- and thirty-somethings around the world are out there solo-traveling, building their empires, or even just decorating their own pads, we might feel like we’re in a bit of a holding pattern. I feel maximum 25 years old is the age where one should move out. This way, it feels like you can structure life to your own accord.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Dating dilemmas
Let’s talk about the elephant in the room: dating. In a city where the dating game is already challenging, explaining that you live with Mom and Dad can add an extra layer of complexity. It’s like a rite of passage—eventually, we all hope to have a place to call our own for those romantic rendezvous. We covered dating in a previous article - it’s much better to have your own abode.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Parental power
Ah, the classic “When are you getting married?” and “Why aren’t you home yet?” questions that can drive us up the wall. Living under the same roof might mean dealing with a bit more parental pester power than you’d like. They mean well, but sometimes, you just need your own space to breathe. Leaving home equates to being in control of your own life. No monetary ties, no decisions influenced by parents if you don’t want their opinions.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>The boomerang effect
It’s all fun and games until you decide it’s time to spread your wings and fly. But what if you’ve been under your parents’ roof for so long that you’ve forgotten how to adult on your own? The boomerang effect—a return to the nest after an attempt at independence—can be a humbling experience, to say the least. Leaving your parent’s roof doesn’t mean you won’t come back or won’t take care of them either.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<h4 id="additional-pull-factors-of-leaving-home">Additional pull factors of leaving home</h4>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Increasing number of co-living spaces
Co-living spaces have gained popularity worldwide, offering an affordable, community-oriented housing solution. Singapore could promote the development of such spaces designed for young adults. These environments foster independence while providing essential amenities and a built-in support system. Think Hmlet in Singapore.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Career opportunities beyond Singapore
Sometimes, the best way to encourage independence is to expand horizons. Singaporean companies and the government can promote overseas work opportunities, internships, or exchange programs. These experiences not only help young adults gain independence but also broaden their perspectives. Singapore is a huge bubble, hence I always encourage locals here to go abroad if their means can afford it.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Changing mindsets
There is a shifting societal norm and a growing emphasis on independence, which will lead to a healthier peer pressure to move out of one’s parental home.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>Living with your parents as an adult in Singapore can be a double-edged sword. While it offers financial stability, emotional closeness, and an unwavering support system, it also comes with space constraints, identity challenges, and a few extra dating hurdles. But hey, there’s no one-size-fits-all answer here. Whether you’re nesting with Mom and Dad or spreading your wings into the unknown, the important thing is finding what works for you.</p>

<h4 id="where-is-the-new-generation-moving-to">Where is the new generation moving to?</h4>

<p>Young married Singaporeans often seek neighborhoods that provide a balance between convenience, affordability, and a family-friendly environment. Here are some popular neighborhoods where you can find young married couples in Singapore:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Bishan
Bishan is a mature and well-established residential area in central Singapore. It offers excellent connectivity with the North-South Line and Circle Line MRT stations. The neighborhood has numerous parks, good schools, and a range of amenities, making it attractive to young families.</li>
  <li>Punggol
Punggol, a waterfront town in the northeastern part of Singapore, has seen rapid development in recent years. It offers a tranquil living environment with scenic waterfront views. Young couples are drawn to Punggol for its affordability and the promise of a growing community.</li>
  <li>Sengkang
Sengkang, located adjacent to Punggol, is another family-friendly neighborhood. It features spacious public housing (HDB) flats and various recreational amenities like parks, sports complexes, and malls. The LRT and MRT lines connect Sengkang to other parts of the island.</li>
  <li>Woodlands
Woodlands, situated in the northern region of Singapore, has become increasingly popular among young couples due to its affordability and improving amenities. The upcoming Woodlands Regional Center promises to bring more job opportunities and recreational options to the area.</li>
  <li>Tampines
Tampines is one of Singapore’s largest residential towns, known for its well-planned HDB estates. It offers a wide range of amenities, including shopping malls, parks, and schools. The convenient access to public transport and major expressways makes it an attractive choice for young families.</li>
  <li>Jurong West
Jurong West, located in the western part of Singapore, is known for its affordability and proximity to Jurong Lake District, a rapidly developing commercial and leisure hub. It’s an ideal choice for couples looking for a mix of urban and suburban living.</li>
  <li>Bedok
Bedok, in the eastern part of Singapore, offers a coastal living experience. The neighborhood has a strong sense of community and boasts numerous dining options, parks, and schools. It is well-connected via the East-West Line.</li>
  <li>Bukit Panjang
Bukit Panjang is situated in the northwestern part of Singapore and is known for its lush greenery and proximity to nature reserves. Young couples looking for a more tranquil setting may find this neighborhood appealing.</li>
  <li>Clementi
Clementi, located in the western part of the island, is a mature estate with good schools and accessibility. It’s a popular choice for young families due to its well-rounded amenities.</li>
  <li>Hougang
Hougang, in the northeastern region, is known for its affordability and numerous parks. The upcoming Cross Island Line will further enhance its connectivity.</li>
</ol>

<p>These neighborhoods offer various housing options, amenities, and a sense of community, making them attractive choices for young married couples in Singapore. The ideal choice depends on factors like budget, lifestyle preferences, and proximity to workplaces and family. As you can see, none of these locations are central or sexy. But hey, they’re practical and works for young families.</p>

<p>Have you considered moving out or already moved out? Let me know. Don’t forget to subscribe to see more content like this.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="living" /><category term="housing" /><category term="parents" /><category term="Singapore" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I left my parents’ home at the age of 18 when I moved to the States for college. Interestingly, most of my peers in Hong Kong, as well as my friends in Singapore, continue to live in their family homes if they remained in the same country post college graduation. Even in the case of marriage, a significant percentage of them choose to reside with their families unless they have accumulated enough resources to afford their own place. This trend is notably common in these two Asian countries, in contrast to the United States. Today, we’ll delve into the phenomenon of adults living with their parents and explore its advantages and disadvantages.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/apartment.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/apartment.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Unlocking Opportunities: job searching guide in Singapore</title><link href="/singapore-job-landscape/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Unlocking Opportunities: job searching guide in Singapore" /><published>2023-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-job-landscape</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-job-landscape/"><![CDATA[<p>In the current economic climate, job searching can be quite challenging. Both the tech and banking sectors are experiencing layoffs, and start-ups are not as actively hiring, leading to an abundance of talent in the market competing for a limited number of job openings. Singapore’s job search landscape is in this sticky state. However if we looked a couple years back, Singapore attracted a plethora of international talent given its robust economy, diverse industries, and business-friendly atmosphere. In our guide today, we’ll take a deep dive into the key industries, top companies, sought-after roles, and vital employment regulations you must navigate while pursuing your career aspirations in Singapore. I’ll also share some insights from my own job hunt experience here, along with strategies you can employ to carve your path to success.</p>

<h4 id="the-appeal-of-singapore-why-work-here">The appeal of Singapore: Why work here?</h4>
<ul>
  <li>Economic prosperity and business friendliness: Singapore’s unwavering economic stability and flourishing industries make it a magnet for businesses. The city-state’s pro-business policies, minimal taxes, and robust infrastructure create an ideal environment for local and international enterprises alike.</li>
  <li>Strategic geographic hub: Nestled at the crossroads of Asia, Singapore acts as a pivotal gateway to the entire region. Its strategic location facilitates seamless trade and business opportunities with neighboring nations</li>
  <li>Global financial powerhouse: Singapore shines as a global epicenter of financial services. Hosting a plethora of international banks, investment firms, family offices, and financial institutions, it presents unparalleled prospects in finance, banking, and wealth management</li>
  <li>English as a universal language: The widespread use and understanding of English in Singapore foster an environment where expatriates and professionals easily communicate and assimilate into both local society and the workplace</li>
  <li>A universe of career possibilities: Singapore’s dynamic economy offers an extensive array of job prospects spanning diverse industries, from finance and technology to healthcare and hospitality. More on this later</li>
  <li>Exposure to talent from around the world: Singapore provides professionals with the opportunity to build global networks and collaborate with kindred spirits</li>
  <li>Conducive business environment: Singapore’s streamlined bureaucracy, efficient legal framework, and straightforward business procedures contribute to a fertile ground for establishing and nurturing enterprises</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="what-are-the-top-industries-in-singapore">What are the top industries in Singapore?</h4>

<p>Singapore’s economy thrives on a diverse range of industries, offering a wide array of career options. Some of the top industries that contribute significantly to the country’s GDP and job market include:</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Finance: With its reputation as a global financial hub, Singapore is home to numerous multinational banks, asset management firms, and insurance companies. Opportunities in finance, accounting, risk management, and compliance abound in this sector. Singapore’s local banks, such as DBS Bank, OCBC Bank, and United Overseas Bank (UOB), offer diverse career paths. International banks like Citibank, Standard Chartered, and J.P. Morgan have established a strong presence in Singapore. I’d say Finance is still stronger in HK and Shanghai versus Singapore, but the gap is closing</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Tech: Singapore places a strong emphasis on digital transformation, making its IT sector a dynamic and rapidly growing industry. Job opportunities exist in software development, cybersecurity, data analytics, and artificial intelligence. Global tech giants like Google, Microsoft, and Facebook have set up regional headquarters in Singapore, attracting talent from around the world. Additionally, local tech companies like Grab and Sea Limited have gained prominence, although they are evidently struggling at the moment</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Bio-med / pharma: Singapore has established itself as a prominent player in the biomedical field. It houses renowned research institutes, pharmaceutical companies, and biotech firms. Job prospects in biomedical research, clinical trials, medical device manufacturing, and pharmaceutical sales are aplenty. Renowned pharmaceutical companies like GlaxoSmithKline (GSK), Novartis, and Pfizer have a significant presence in Singapore. Local healthcare institutions such as Singapore General Hospital (SGH) and National University Hospital (NUH) offer rewarding careers in the healthcare sector too and has decent compensation</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Engineering and Manufacturing: Singapore boasts a strong manufacturing base, encompassing precision engineering, electronics, aerospace, and chemical industries. Job seekers with engineering expertise are in demand, especially in areas such as semiconductor manufacturing, industrial automation, and renewable energy. Companies like Singapore Technologies Engineering (ST Engineering), Flex, and Micron Technology contribute significantly to Singapore’s thriving manufacturing sector.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Hospitality and Tourism: As a popular tourist destination, Singapore offers a vibrant hospitality sector with numerous opportunities in hotels, restaurants, and attractions. Well-known hospitality brands such as Marina Bay Sands, Resorts World Sentosa, and Shangri-La Hotels and Resorts provide diverse job opportunities in the hospitality and tourism industry</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Venture Capital: Singapore has become a prominent hub for venture capital, attracting investments and fostering the growth of startups. VC firms offer opportunities in investment analysis, deal sourcing, and portfolio management. Peak XV (ex- Sequoia Capital), Golden Gate Ventures, Vertex Ventures, and Monk’s Hill Ventures are among the top venture capital firms with a presence in Singapore</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Crypto / Blockchain: As cryptocurrencies gain mainstream acceptance, Singapore has positioned itself as a cryptocurrency and blockchain hub. Roles in this sector include blockchain developers, cryptocurrency analysts, and compliance specialists. Companies like Binance, CoinGecko, Huobi, and Zilliqa have established themselves as key players in Singapore’s cryptocurrency and blockchain ecosystem. Too bad this industry is in shits right now</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<h4 id="what-roles-are-in-top-demand">What roles are in top demand?</h4>

<p>To excel in your job search, it is essential to understand the roles that are currently in high demand in Singapore’s competitive job market. Some of the top roles sought after by employers include:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Technology and digital transformation: Software engineers, data scientists, cybersecurity specialists, and UX/UI designers are highly sought after in Singapore’s tech-driven economy. Trust me - you want to be in tech given it’s the industry with the highest bang for your buck</li>
  <li>Finance and accounting: Finance professionals with expertise in risk management, financial analysis and regulatory compliance</li>
  <li>Healthcare and bio-med: Medical professionals, research scientists, and pharmaceutical sales representatives</li>
  <li>Engineering: Skilled engineers specializing in fields such as electrical, mechanical, and civil engineering</li>
  <li>Sales and Marketing: With Singapore’s focus on international trade and business development, professionals with sales and marketing expertise are highly sought after to drive growth and expansion.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="whats-the-state-of-the-job-market-right-now">What’s the state of the job market right now?</h4>

<p>I echoed this in the introduction, but times are tough for the unemployed, as evident from a recent Strait Times report stating that Singapore’s labor demand is cooling due to economic uncertainty and global headwinds. This trend is prevalent worldwide. Singapore’s rising cost of living and the increasing challenge of obtaining an employment pass sponsorship could lead to a short-term decline in foreign talent. However, I anticipate a robust and opportunistic Singapore job market in the long term. Share your experiences with the Singapore job search market in the comments or via email.</p>

<p>Thank you for reading my article - subscribe for more content like this.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="employment" /><category term="job searching" /><category term="opportunities" /><category term="Singapore" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the current economic climate, job searching can be quite challenging. Both the tech and banking sectors are experiencing layoffs, and start-ups are not as actively hiring, leading to an abundance of talent in the market competing for a limited number of job openings. Singapore’s job search landscape is in this sticky state. However if we looked a couple years back, Singapore attracted a plethora of international talent given its robust economy, diverse industries, and business-friendly atmosphere. In our guide today, we’ll take a deep dive into the key industries, top companies, sought-after roles, and vital employment regulations you must navigate while pursuing your career aspirations in Singapore. I’ll also share some insights from my own job hunt experience here, along with strategies you can employ to carve your path to success.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/jobsearch.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/jobsearch.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Singapore McDonald’s - an unexpected dining option</title><link href="/singapore-mcdonalds/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Singapore McDonald’s - an unexpected dining option" /><published>2023-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-mcdonalds</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-mcdonalds/"><![CDATA[<p>I have a friend who visits their local McDonalds whenever he travels abroad. He’s not poor, but let’s just say he’s a little obnoxious and insistent. When he visited Singapore a few weeks back, he could not shut up about how high quality the McDonalds is here. With a localized menu and somewhat well-executed food items, McDonalds is seen as a medium-end eatery in SIngapore given hawker center food is cheaper (sometimes up to 50% cheaper). Today, we’ll unpack McDonalds in Singapore, why it’s such a beloved institution and how to order from McDonalds Singapore so you won’t miss out on the goodness.</p>

<p>McDonald’s made its entry into Singapore in 1979. The first McDonald’s restaurant in Singapore was opened on March 8, 1979, at Liat Towers along Orchard Road, one of the city-state’s main shopping districts. The introduction of McDonald’s in Singapore marked the beginning of the fast-food industry’s development in the country and brought about significant changes in the local dining scene. Since then, McDonald’s has expanded its presence in Singapore, opening numerous locations across the country, including standalone restaurants, outlets in shopping malls, and drive-thru locations. Today, McDonald’s is a well-established and widely recognized fast-food chain in Singapore, serving a variety of menu items tailored to local tastes alongside their global offerings.</p>

<h4 id="why-is-mcdonalds-so-loved-in-singapore">Why is McDonalds so loved in Singapore?</h4>

<p>A Taste of Familiarity and Consistency: McDonald’s brings a sense of familiarity to Singaporeans’ palates. The taste, quality, and service consistency offered by McDonald’s worldwide is a major draw. Whether it’s the iconic Big Mac or the addictive Chicken McNuggets, there’s something undeniably comforting about indulging in these well-known flavors that we’ve grown up with.
Convenience, Convenience, Convenience: One word that perfectly describes McDonald’s in Singapore is “convenience.” With its widespread presence across the island, you’re never too far away from a McDonald’s outlet. Whether you’re in the mood for a quick bite, a takeaway meal, or even a late-night munchie, McDonald’s has you covered. The accessibility and round-the-clock operation of select locations make it a go-to choice for time-pressed individuals and hungry souls alike.
Catering to Local Tastes: McDonald’s understands the importance of catering to Singaporeans’ diverse palates. They have cleverly adapted their menu to include localized items that hit all the right spots. From the fiery McSpicy to the beloved McChicken, McDonald’s has perfected the art of creating dishes that resonate with our local flavors. These adaptations demonstrate their commitment to staying relevant and meeting the cravings of their Singaporean customers.
Somewhat Value-for-Money Meals: Living in a city known for its higher cost of living, finding an affordable dining option can be a challenge. McDonald’s, however, comes to the rescue with its value-for-money meals and pocket-friendly promotions. The combination of affordable pricing and satisfying portions makes it an appealing choice for budget-conscious individuals, families, and students looking to enjoy a satisfying meal without breaking the bank.
A Gathering Place for All: Step inside any McDonald’s outlet in Singapore, and you’ll find it buzzing with activity. From friends catching up over a meal to families enjoying a weekend outing, McDonald’s acts as a social hub for the community. With comfortable seating arrangements and a welcoming atmosphere, it provides a casual setting where people can connect, share stories, and create memories.
Embracing Innovation: In a rapidly evolving digital age, McDonald’s Singapore has embraced innovation to enhance the dining experience. Self-ordering kiosks, mobile ordering, and efficient delivery services have become the norm. These technological advancements cater to the preferences of tech-savvy customers, ensuring a seamless and convenient experience for those on the go.</p>

<h4 id="why-are-mcdonald-prices-higher-in-singapore">Why are McDonald prices higher in Singapore?</h4>

<p>Several factors contribute to the relatively higher prices of McDonald’s in Singapore compared to some other countries. Here are a few reasons:
Operating Costs: Singapore has a high cost of living and a relatively high standard of wages and labor costs. The cost of labor, rent, utilities, and other operational expenses for businesses, including McDonald’s, is generally higher in Singapore compared to many other countries. These higher operating costs can result in higher prices for products and services.
Import Costs: Singapore relies heavily on imports for its food supply. McDonald’s ingredients, such as beef, chicken, and certain produce, may need to be imported from other countries. Importing these items can involve additional transportation, handling, and custom duties, which can increase the overall cost of sourcing ingredients and impact the final pricing of the menu items.
Premium Locations: McDonald’s restaurants in Singapore are often strategically located in prime areas, such as shopping malls, busy city centers, or tourist destinations. These prime locations come with higher rental costs, which can be a significant factor in the overall pricing of the products.
Local Taxes and Regulations: Singapore has various taxes and regulations that businesses must comply with. These include goods and services tax (GST), import duties, and other levies that may affect the overall cost structure of McDonald’s operations and subsequently impact the pricing of their products.
Menu Customization: McDonald’s in Singapore often offers menu items customized to suit local tastes and preferences. The additional effort and costs associated with developing and producing these customized items can contribute to higher prices compared to standard menu items in other countries.</p>

<h4 id="must-orders">Must orders</h4>

<p>From most important to least important:</p>

<p><u>McSpicy<u>
This iconic burger is a favorite among spice enthusiasts. It features a crispy chicken patty with a kick of heat from the specially blended spicy sauce, topped with lettuce and mayonnaise, all sandwiched between sesame seed buns.</u></u></p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/assets/images/mcspicy.jpg" alt="McSpicy" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>McSpicy - Singapore’s iconic</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p><u>Filet-O-Fish<u>
With its crispy and golden exterior, tender and flaky fish fillet, harmonious blend of tangy tartar sauce and melted cheese, and a soft bun that completes the symphony of flavors, Singapore’s Filet-o-Fish is a class above that of it’s US counterpart’s</u></u></p>

<p><u>Chicken McCrispy<u>
McWing batter on a KFC drumstick. Chicken McCrispy has a fiery aftertaste and is extremely crunchy. Now comes with honey soy flavour too to mix things up</u></u></p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/assets/images/mccrispy.jpg" alt="McCrispy" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>McCrispy - succulent drumsticks</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p><u>McGriddle (limited edition)<u>
Indulge in the mouthwatering delight of the McGriddle at McDonald's! This breakfast innovation combines fluffy pancakes infused with maple syrup, enveloping a savory combination of bacon, sausage, or egg. With a perfect balance of sweet and savory flavors, the McGriddle satisfies your cravings while providing convenient breakfast enjoyment. Start your day with a smile and savor the heavenly goodness of the McGriddle.</u></u></p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/assets/images/mcgriddle.jpg" alt="McGriddle" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>McGriddle</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p><u>McFizz<u>
Elevate your beverage game with the refreshing McFizz at McDonald's! This fizzy carbonated drink offers a range of flavors to excite your taste buds. From classic cola to unique limited-time options, each sip delivers a burst of effervescence and flavor. Whether enjoyed on its own or paired with a McDonald's meal, the McFizz is the perfect thirst-quencher for those seeking a fizzy and satisfying beverage. Treat yourself to the sparkling goodness of the McFizz and elevate your McDonald's experience. Comes with different flavours (currently it’s Grapefruit)</u></u></p>

<p><u>Shake shake Fries<u>
Experience flavor-packed fries with McDonald's Shaker Fries! These golden and crispy delights allow you to shake them up in your choice of seasoning for an exciting taste experience. From classic Salted to spicy Hot &amp; Spicy, these interactive fries take your McDonald's meal to the next level. Shake, savor, and enjoy the burst of flavor with McDonald's Shaker Fries—a must-try for fry enthusiasts.</u></u></p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/assets/images/shakeshake.jpg" alt="ShakeShakeFries" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>Shake shake, shake shake, shake it</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>Surprise your taste buds with the delightful offerings at Singapore McDonald’s! For more tasty adventures, remember to subscribe and stay tuned.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="food" /><category term="dining" /><category term="McDonalds" /><category term="Singapore" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I have a friend who visits their local McDonalds whenever he travels abroad. He’s not poor, but let’s just say he’s a little obnoxious and insistent. When he visited Singapore a few weeks back, he could not shut up about how high quality the McDonalds is here. With a localized menu and somewhat well-executed food items, McDonalds is seen as a medium-end eatery in SIngapore given hawker center food is cheaper (sometimes up to 50% cheaper). Today, we’ll unpack McDonalds in Singapore, why it’s such a beloved institution and how to order from McDonalds Singapore so you won’t miss out on the goodness.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/Mcd.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/Mcd.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Best Singapore travel itinerary for tourists</title><link href="/singapore-travel-itinerary/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Best Singapore travel itinerary for tourists" /><published>2023-09-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-09-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-travel-itinerary</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-travel-itinerary/"><![CDATA[<p>Apologies for the gaps in posts - things have been hectic over the last month, and with the introduction of our Chinese language posts, I simply haven’t had the time to post new content. However, we are now back!</p>

<p>A few of my friends have been visiting Singapore and have asked me to create an itinerary for them. Many ask whether there are things to do in Singapore. The answer is yes and no. Singapore is a small but mighty city-state that offers a world of experiences within its compact borders. Despite its size, this dynamic metropolis is packed with iconic landmarks, cultural enclaves, stunning gardens, delectable cuisine, and much more. Overall, I recommend 3 days as the optimal amount of time to spend in Singapore. Anything more and you’ll be struggling to find things to do. Here’s the itinerary below. Note - we’ll save a more in-depth restaurant / bars guide for another time.</p>

<h4 id="day-1">Day 1:</h4>

<p><u>Morning<u></u></u></p>
<ul>
  <li>Breakfast at Ya Kun: Start your Singapore adventure with a hearty breakfast at Ya Kun Kaya Toast, a local favorite known for its traditional Singaporean breakfast. Indulge in crispy toast slathered with kaya (coconut jam) and paired with soft-boiled eggs and a cup of aromatic kopi (local coffee). Ya Kun’s are everywhere so it’s not hard to find. Alternatively, visiting Toast Box is ok too.</li>
  <li>Chinatown: After breakfast, make your way to Chinatown, a vibrant district teeming with colorful shophouses, bustling markets, and rich cultural heritage. Take a leisurely stroll along the vibrant streets, visit the historic Sri Mariamman Temple, and savor delicious local street food at the Chinatown Food Street.</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Afternoon<u></u></u></p>
<ul>
  <li>Tiong Bahru: Afterward, make your way to Tiong Bahru, a hip neighborhood known for its trendy cafes and charming heritage buildings. Enjoy a leisurely dinner at one of the local eateries, and explore the neighborhood’s unique boutiques and art galleries. Alternatively, check out the large Tiong Bahru Hawker center market for a local lunch, including Char Kway Teow, Chicken rice and Bak Chor Mee</li>
  <li>Artscience museum: Head to the ArtScience Museum, located within the iconic Marina Bay Sands complex. Explore the museum’s interactive exhibits that blend art, science, and technology, offering a unique and immersive experience.</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Evening<u></u></u></p>
<ul>
  <li>Gardens by the Bay / MBS: As the sun sets, head to Marina Bay Sands (MBS) to witness the spectacular light and sound show at the Marina Bay Sands SkyPark. Enjoy panoramic views of the city skyline and the dazzling light show that illuminates the night sky. At night, head to Gardens by the Bay, a stunning nature park that boasts iconic Supertrees and beautiful flower domes. Explore the various themed gardens and check out the free Garden Rhapsody performance.</li>
  <li>Dinner recommendations - Makansutra Gluttons Bay, Lau Pa Sat hawker center, Bread Street Kitchen by Gordon Ramsay, Extra Virgin Pizza. Plenty to eat around that area</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="day-2">Day 2:</h4>

<p><u>Morning / Afternoon<u></u></u></p>
<ul>
  <li>Sentosa: Head to Sentosa Island, a popular resort island with a myriad of attractions. Spend the afternoon enjoying the sandy beaches, visiting Universal Studios Singapore for thrilling rides and entertainment, or exploring the S.E.A. Aquarium for an underwater adventure. On the way out of Sentosa, check out Vivo City. Plenty to shop at that mall</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Evening<u></u></u></p>
<ul>
  <li>Clarke Quay: Take the MRT from Harborfront (Vivo City) to Clarke Quay. Enjoy a leisurely dinner at one of the many riverside restaurants offering a variety of cuisines. My recommendation is the Song Fa Ba Ku Teh there, a restaurant renowned for its flavorful pork rib soup. If you’re a party person, plenty of clubs / bars here, including the infamous Zouk</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="day-3">Day 3:</h4>

<p><u>Morning:<u></u></u></p>
<ul>
  <li>Little India: Start your day with a visit to Little India, a vibrant cultural enclave filled with colorful shops, aromatic spice stalls, and traditional Indian eateries. Immerse yourself in the vibrant atmosphere, visit Sri Veeramakaliamman Temple, and savor authentic Indian cuisine for breakfast. MTR is a great restaurant here</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Afternoon<u></u></u></p>
<ul>
  <li>Orchard: Explore Orchard Road, Singapore’s premier shopping belt. Stroll along this bustling street lined with luxurious malls, fashion boutiques, and international brands. Shop to your heart’s content or simply soak in the vibrant atmosphere.</li>
  <li>Dempsey: If shopping is not your thing, head to Dempsey Hill, Dempsey Hill offers a unique blend of history, dining, and shopping experiences. Explore the charming colonial-era buildings, indulge in a diverse range of cuisines at the various restaurants (Jumbo, Red Sparrow, Burnt Ends), and browse through the boutique shops and galleries for a delightful day out. FWIW, there’s a Dover Street Market there too</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Evening<u></u></u></p>
<ul>
  <li>Night Safari: Spend the evening at the Singapore Zoo, a world-class wildlife park known for its immersive and naturalistic enclosures. Discover a wide variety of animals and enjoy entertaining animal shows. Experience the unique Night Safari, where you can observe nocturnal animals in their natural habitats</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="some-other-experience-to-consider">Some other experience to consider</h4>
<ul>
  <li>East coast Park: Explore the scenic East Coast Park and enjoy activities like cycling, rollerblading, or simply relaxing on the beach.</li>
  <li>Joo Chiat: Immerse yourself in the colorful heritage of Joo Chiat, known for its Peranakan architecture, vibrant murals, and delicious local food.</li>
  <li>Jewel Airport: Visit Jewel Changi Airport, an architectural marvel that offers a wide range of shopping, dining, and entertainment options, including the stunning indoor waterfall, Canopy Park, and the Sky Nets.</li>
  <li>MacRitchie Reservoir: Embark on a nature adventure at MacRitchie Reservoir, where you can hike along the treetop walk, explore the nature trails, and spot wildlife such as monkeys and birds.</li>
  <li>Sungei Buloh: Discover the beauty of Sungei Buloh Wetland Reserve, a nature reserve teeming with diverse flora and fauna, including migratory birds, reptiles, and mudskippers. This is one of my personal favourites</li>
  <li>Fort Canning Park: Step back in time at Fort Canning Park, a historic landmark with lush greenery, ancient artifacts, and historical significance. Explore the park’s archaeological dig site, visit the Battle Box museum, and enjoy scenic views of the city.</li>
</ul>

<p>With this carefully curated three-day itinerary, you’ll have the opportunity to experience the best of Singapore’s iconic landmarks, vibrant neighborhoods, delicious cuisine, and unique attractions. Get ready for an unforgettable adventure in the Lion City.</p>

<h4 id="recommended-hotels-to-stay-in">Recommended hotels to stay in</h4>

<p>Singapore offers a wide range of hotel options to suit various preferences and budgets. From luxurious 5-star hotels that exude opulence and offer world-class amenities to trendy boutique hotels with unique designs and personalized service, there is something for every traveler. Additionally, budget-friendly accommodations such as hostels and budget hotels provide affordable options without compromising on comfort. Whether you seek a lavish retreat, a charming boutique experience, or a wallet-friendly stay, Singapore has an extensive selection of hotels to cater to diverse needs and enhance your overall travel experience. My personal recs -</p>

<p><u>5 stars<u></u></u></p>

<p>Luxury</p>
<ul>
  <li>Marina Bay Sands</li>
  <li>The Ritz-Carlton, Millenia Singapore</li>
  <li>The Fullerton Bay Hotel</li>
  <li>Mandarin Oriental, Singapore</li>
  <li>Raffles Hotel Singapore</li>
</ul>

<p>Business-y</p>
<ul>
  <li>JW Marriott</li>
  <li>Shangri-La Hotel, Singapore</li>
</ul>

<p>Getaway</p>
<ul>
  <li>W Hotel Sentosa (if Sentosa isn’t too far for you)</li>
  <li>Shangri-La Rasa Sentosa</li>
</ul>

<p><u>4 stars<u></u></u></p>
<ul>
  <li>Hotel Jen Tanglin / Orchard</li>
  <li>Studio M</li>
  <li>Holiday Inn Singapore Atrium</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="things-to-look-out-for">Things to look out for</h4>

<ul>
  <li>Strict Laws: Singapore is known for its strict laws, so it’s important to be mindful of local regulations. Avoid littering, spitting, or engaging in any form of vandalism. Also, remember that chewing gum is not allowed in public.</li>
  <li>Respect for Customs and Culture: Singapore is a multicultural country with diverse customs and traditions. Show respect for local customs, traditions, and religions. Dress modestly when visiting religious sites, and be mindful of local practices and sensitivities.</li>
  <li>Efficient Public Transportation: Singapore has an excellent public transportation system, including buses and trains. Familiarize yourself with the various modes of transportation and their respective routes. Be sure to tap your transport card (EZ-Link or Singapore Tourist Pass) when boarding buses and trains.</li>
  <li>Cleanliness and Hygiene: Singapore prides itself on cleanliness, and littering is heavily frowned upon. Dispose of trash in designated bins, and keep public spaces clean. Be mindful of personal hygiene, especially during the current COVID-19 pandemic. Follow health and safety guidelines, such as wearing masks in public and maintaining social distancing.</li>
  <li>Tipping Culture: Tipping is not a common practice in Singapore, as a service charge is usually included in bills at hotels, restaurants, and cafes.</li>
</ul>

<p>And here it is! I hope you like my Singapore 3-day itinerary and can put it to good use. Let me know if there are other recommendations that you think should be on this list! Comment in your thoughts. Subscribe now to see more content like this.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="expat" /><category term="tourists" /><category term="itinerary" /><category term="Singapore" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Apologies for the gaps in posts - things have been hectic over the last month, and with the introduction of our Chinese language posts, I simply haven’t had the time to post new content. However, we are now back!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/travel.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/travel.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Singapore expat resources now in Chinese</title><link href="/singapore-expats-blog-in-chinese-copy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Singapore expat resources now in Chinese" /><published>2023-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-expats-blog-in-chinese%20copy</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-expats-blog-in-chinese-copy/"><![CDATA[<p>We haven’t posted for two weeks, but there’s a good reason for it. We’re excited to announce the official launch of Chinese translations for our cherished posts! Given the numerous requests from our users for content in Chinese alongside English, we’re delighted to oblige. To access this feature, simply go to our homepage, locate the language selection option at the top, and choose 中文 (Chinese). It’s that simple! Enjoy.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="expat" /><category term="Chinese" /><category term="move" /><category term="relocation" /><category term="Singapore" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We haven’t posted for two weeks, but there’s a good reason for it. We’re excited to announce the official launch of Chinese translations for our cherished posts! Given the numerous requests from our users for content in Chinese alongside English, we’re delighted to oblige. To access this feature, simply go to our homepage, locate the language selection option at the top, and choose 中文 (Chinese). It’s that simple! Enjoy.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/chinese.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/chinese.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">10 reasons to move to Singapore</title><link href="/move-to-singapore/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="10 reasons to move to Singapore" /><published>2023-07-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/move-to-singapore</id><content type="html" xml:base="/move-to-singapore/"><![CDATA[<p>I have been asked many times what the main reasons are for moving to Singapore. I discussed my personal reasons in an earlier post, but that was based on my pre-move conception of the country. Now, after residing here for 5 years and witnessing the experiences of expats in Singapore, as well as interacting with locals, I can confidently state that there are clear-cut reasons for choosing to move to Singapore. With that in mind, I present to you my top ten reasons for living in Singapore.</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Strong Economy: Singapore’s robust and thriving economy is one of the key reasons why many people choose to move here. As a global financial hub, the city-state provides abundant job opportunities in sectors such as finance, technology, healthcare, and logistics. Its business-friendly environment and supportive infrastructure make it an attractive destination for professionals seeking career growth. Singapore is also a stable nation that many value. The job opportunity I’ve had here parallels that of the US and is stronger than that of Hong Kong.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Safety and Security: No country is safer than Singapore. No one will deny this. Singapore consistently ranks among the safest countries in the world, with low crime rates and efficient law enforcement. You can enjoy peace of mind and a secure environment for yourself and your family. Worried about going home at 3am? That’s not a concern in Singapore. Worried about getting pickpocketed on the train? That’s not a concern in Singapore. Worried about your kids being kidnapped from a park? That’s not a concern in Singapore. This is the biggest reason of why expats want to move to Singapore</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Excellent Infrastructure: Singapore boasts world-class infrastructure, which is essential for a comfortable and convenient lifestyle. From a well-connected public transportation system to efficient public services, you’ll find that everything runs smoothly in this city-state. The MRT (subway) connects all over the island and is still expanding its presence with new train lines being built. Well-maintained roads, advanced healthcare facilities, and modern amenities contribute to a high standard of living. I</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Cultural Diversity: One of Singapore’s greatest assets is its cultural diversity. With a mix of Chinese, Malay, Indian, and Western influences, the city-state embraces a multicultural society. This diversity is evident in its vibrant festivals, mouthwatering cuisine, and traditional customs. Living in Singapore means being part of a rich tapestry of cultures and enjoying a truly global experience. Is there racism? Yes. But that’s in any country, especially if you are an expat there. Are there clashes because of cultures and race? Yes. But that’s in any country as well. If anything, Singapore does a great job in maintaining racial harmony.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Education System: If you have children or are pursuing higher education, Singapore’s renowned education system will be of great interest. The city-state is home to top-ranking universities (NUS broke into the top 10 in the world this year I believe), international schools, and well-structured academic programs. The emphasis on quality education ensures that students receive a solid foundation for their future success. For expats, Singapore international schools are some of the top notch in the world (see more about education here). The local education system is intense, but that’s why you send your child to private or international school if you can afford it. The same applies to other countries</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Clean: Despite being a bustling urban center, Singapore is committed to maintaining a clean and green environment. The government’s strict environmental policies have resulted in well-managed parks, gardens, and nature reserves. You can enjoy green spaces, pristine streets, and a city that takes pride in its cleanliness. Now, it’s almost hysterical to complain about this but all the cleanliness takes away from the grunge that any country should have. However, this is about reasons to live in Singapore, and cleanliness is apparent</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Healthcare Excellence: Singapore’s healthcare system is world-class, with state-of-the-art medical facilities and highly skilled healthcare professionals. The country consistently ranks among the best in terms of healthcare outcomes and accessibility. You can have peace of mind knowing that quality healthcare services are readily available when you need them. Private and public healthcare is both amazing too. The country is tiny so a hospital is always at arms reach. Doctors are all quality (even the GPs though they look miserable) and it’s a luxury locals and expats in Singapore always forget</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Food and Dining: Prepare your taste buds for an unforgettable culinary adventure in Singapore. The city-state is renowned for its diverse food scene, offering a wide range of cuisines to satisfy every palate. From affordable street food at hawker centers to Michelin-starred restaurants, you’ll discover a gastronomic paradise where culinary delights await at every turn. I love that you can eat cheap if you want and then eat expensive the next day if that’s what you desire. Moving here for the food isn’t something people usually think about but it’s an unassuming luxury too. The issue with Singapore right now is that there are too many medium-priced food establishments that are not worth, but it takes time to really find what restaurants should be on your blacklist.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Travel Opportunities: Singapore’s strategic location in Southeast Asia makes it an ideal base for exploring the region. With excellent connectivity and transportation links, you can easily travel to neighboring countries and immerse yourself in diverse cultures, stunning landscapes, and unique experiences. Satiate your wanderlust and embark on exciting adventures just a short distance away. You’ll be able to get some great flight deals from this SEA hub too. I averaged 15-20 trips prior to COVID and now 5-7 trips post COVID. All from the heart of Singapore.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Quality of Life: Ultimately, moving to Singapore promises a high quality of life. With efficient public services, good infrastructure, a safe environment, and various amenities, you can enjoy a comfortable and prosperous lifestyle. Singapore consistently ranks well in global quality of life indexes, reflecting its commitment to providing a thriving and inclusive community for residents. Yes, the cost of living is high but taxes are low. You have the choice to live lavishly or not.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>If you’re seeking a dynamic and cosmopolitan city that offers tremendous opportunities, a diverse culture, and an excellent standard of living, Singapore could be the perfect destination for you. From its strong economy to its safe environment, world-class healthcare, and culinary delights, Singapore has much to offer. Consider these 10 compelling reasons as you contemplate your next chapter in life. I’ve talked about Singapore’s weaknesses. It’s time to talk about Singapore’s strengths too. Don’t forget to subscribe to follow more content like this.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Immigration" /><category term="move" /><category term="relocation" /><category term="Singapore" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I have been asked many times what the main reasons are for moving to Singapore. I discussed my personal reasons in an earlier post, but that was based on my pre-move conception of the country. Now, after residing here for 5 years and witnessing the experiences of expats in Singapore, as well as interacting with locals, I can confidently state that there are clear-cut reasons for choosing to move to Singapore. With that in mind, I present to you my top ten reasons for living in Singapore.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/movetosg.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/movetosg.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Best doctors, clinics and hospitals in Singapore</title><link href="/best-doctor-singapore/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Best doctors, clinics and hospitals in Singapore" /><published>2023-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/best-doctor-singapore</id><content type="html" xml:base="/best-doctor-singapore/"><![CDATA[<p>In an <a href="https://fromhktosg.github.io/singapore-healthcare-copy/">earlier article</a>, I talked about the healthcare system in Singapore and how robust it is, be it in the public or private sector. Since then, a few readers have asked me to recommend my go-to doctors so here’s my curated list of the best doctors, hospitals and clinics in Singapore.</p>

<p>In general, I’m a big fan of Raffles Hospital but have slowly begun seeing more doctors in Gleneagles as I think the nurses at Raffles aren’t that great. P.S. - yes, I have a lot of health problems so I’ve seen a lot of doctors.</p>

<h4 id="preferred-hospitals-in-singapore">Preferred hospitals in Singapore</h4>

<p>Gleneagles, Mount Elizabeth, Raffles Hospital. These are the best.</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/assets/images/glen.jpg" alt="Mte" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>Mount Elizabeth Novena Hospital Lobby</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<h4 id="preferred-health-checks-in-singapore">Preferred health checks in Singapore</h4>

<p>All of the ones I went to are subpar but Raffles hospital is the best of the lot. If anyone has a better option, please message me.</p>

<h4 id="preferred-doctors--clinics-in-singapore-western-medicine">Preferred doctors / clinics in Singapore (Western Medicine)</h4>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>General Practitioner (GP)  - <a href="https://www.healthcare.com.sg/item/dr-steven-ang-anesthetic-family-clinic/">Dr Steven Ang</a> (Dr Steven Ang Aesthetic &amp; Family Clinic)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Ophthalmologist (eye) - <a href="https://www.rafflesmedicalgroup.com/doctor/a-prof-johnson-tan-choon-hwai/">A/Prof Johnson Tan Choon Hwai</a> (Raffles Hospital)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>ENT (ear, throat, nose) - <a href="https://www.rafflesmedicalgroup.com/doctor/dr-chan-siew-chee/">Dr Chan Siew Chee</a> (Raffles Hospital), <a href="https://www.drjeeve.com/">Dr Jeeve Kanagalingam</a> (The ENT Clinic Gleneagles)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Rheumatologist (allergies) - <a href="https://www.rafflesmedicalgroup.com/doctor/dr-chong-yong-yeow/">Dr Chong Yong Yeow</a> (Raffles Hospital)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Dermatologist (skin) - <a href="https://www.rafflesmedicalgroup.com/doctor/dr-tan-siew-kiang/">Dr Tan Siew Kiang</a> (Raffles Hospital), <a href="https://www.dermatologyandco.sg/">Dr Tan Wei Sheng</a> (Dermatology and co)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Counseling (mental health) - <a href="https://www.rafflesmedicalgroup.com/doctor/ms-saras-atre/">Ms Saras Atre</a> (Raffles Hospital)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Surgery / Colorectal - <a href="https://www.rafflesmedicalgroup.com/doctor/dr-wong-kutt-sing/">Dr Wong Kutt Sing</a> (Raffles hospital)</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>This roster of doctors is absolutely A-grade. N/A - Oncologist, OBGYN, pediatrician.</p>

<h4 id="preferred-traditional-chinese-medicine-tcm">Preferred traditional Chinese medicine (TCM)</h4>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Tui Na - <a href="https://sinkangtcm.com.sg/?gad=1">Sin Kang TCM</a></p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Bo Jin - <a href="https://www.yongkangtcm.com/refresh-tcm-wellness">Refresh TCM</a></p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>Don’t have too much experience on this one so please let me know what the best TCM places are out there.</p>

<h4 id="preferred-physiotherapy-and-functional-training">Preferred physiotherapy and functional training</h4>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://www.coreconcepts.com.sg/">Core concepts</a> - most of the physiotherapists there are fantastic and caring.</li>
</ul>

<p>I have not found a podiatrist with whom I am satisfied, so please let me know if you have any suggestions for one. A short post today but I hope this helps in finding your ideal doctor in Singapore. Subscribe now to see more content like this.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Healthcare" /><category term="hospitals" /><category term="doctors" /><category term="clinics" /><category term="Singapore" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In an earlier article, I talked about the healthcare system in Singapore and how robust it is, be it in the public or private sector. Since then, a few readers have asked me to recommend my go-to doctors so here’s my curated list of the best doctors, hospitals and clinics in Singapore.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/penthouse.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/penthouse.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Tuition addiction: Unpacking tuition in Singapore</title><link href="/singapore-tuition/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tuition addiction: Unpacking tuition in Singapore" /><published>2023-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-tuition</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-tuition/"><![CDATA[<p>During a casual lunch with a friend, I was taken aback when he revealed that he spends a staggering $1000 SGD per month on tuition for his 5-year-old child, highlighting the extent to which some parents prioritize academic enrichment from an early age. My friend’s kid seemed like a smart one - why drill more knowledge in her from such a young age? In an earlier post, I touched on the education system in Singapore and Hong Kong. Both countries place great emphasis on academic excellence, leading to a thriving tuition landscape in both regions. The perception of tuition being ingrained as a necessity by parents has sparked debates on its potential negative impact on children’s well-being and overall education system. In today’s post, we’ll dive into the emergence of tuition, effects the industry has on parents and children and a comparison of the top tuition centers and their marketing tactics in Hong Kong and Singapore. I’d say tuition is more common with locals, but an increasing number of expats in Singapore is exploring this. In case you missed out, check out my <a href="https://fromhktosg.github.io/education/">earlier article</a> on the education system of Singapore and how it fares against Hong Kong.</p>

<h4 id="emergence-of-tuition-as-an-industry">Emergence of tuition as an industry</h4>

<p><u> Hong Kong <u></u></u></p>

<p>The first tuition center in Hong Kong is believed to be Modern Education, established in 1971 by Mr. Lam Wing-kee. Initially, it aimed to provide supplementary education to students who needed extra assistance. Over time, tuition centers gained popularity due to the competitive nature of the education system and the desire for academic excellence. They became more mainstream in the 1980s and 1990s as the demand for additional academic support grew. Today, tuition centers are a common feature of the education landscape in Hong Kong, catering to students of all ages and academic levels.</p>

<p><u> Singapore <u></u></u></p>

<p>Tuition centers started emerging in Singapore in the late 1970s and early 1980s. As the education system became more competitive, the demand for additional academic support outside of school grew. This led to the establishment of the first tuition centers, which offered supplementary classes and coaching to help students excel in their studies. Over the years, the tuition industry in Singapore has continued to expand and evolve, with a wide range of centers catering to various subjects and academic levels.</p>

<h4 id="why-send-your-children-to-tuition-in-singapore">Why send your children to tuition in Singapore?</h4>

<p>TL;DR - helicopter parents are stressed about their kids not being superstars so they’ll do everything to give their kids a boost</p>

<ul>
  <li>Academic Excellence: Tuition is seen as a pathway to help children achieve better academic results and excel in their studies.</li>
  <li>Supplementing School Education: Tuition provides additional support beyond the regular school curriculum, helping students understand challenging subjects or topics.</li>
  <li>Competitive Academic Environment: Singapore’s competitive education system motivates parents to enroll their children in tuition to gain a competitive edge over their peers.</li>
  <li>Confidence Building: Tuition boosts students’ confidence by providing personalized attention, addressing their weaknesses, and enhancing their understanding of subjects.</li>
  <li>Individualized Learning: Tuition offers a customized learning experience, catering to each child’s unique learning style, pace, and specific needs.</li>
  <li>Addressing Learning Gaps: Tuition helps bridge any knowledge gaps, ensuring students keep up with the rigorous curriculum and stay on track with their peers.</li>
  <li>Enrichment Opportunities: Tuition can provide enrichment activities, projects, and resources that go beyond the school syllabus, broadening students’ knowledge and skills.</li>
  <li>Holistic Development: Some parents see tuition as a means to foster holistic development, focusing on critical thinking, problem-solving, and cultivating a passion for learning.</li>
  <li>Exam Preparation: Tuition centers often specialize in exam preparation, equipping students with effective study strategies, exam techniques, and practice materials.</li>
  <li>Parental Expectations: Parents may send their kids to tuition due to societal and parental expectations, believing that it is essential for their children’s academic success.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="how-do-these-tuition-centers-teach">How do these tuition centers teach?</h4>

<p>Every format you can think of. Depending on whether it’s catered to local Singaporeans or expats in Singapore, they can differ given a preference for smaller class size for the former. Listing a few here -</p>

<ul>
  <li>One-on-one sessions: Personalized attention and focused guidance.</li>
  <li>Group classes: Opportunities for interaction and peer learning.</li>
  <li>Large classes: A cost-effective option with a diverse learning environment.</li>
  <li>Recordings: Flexibility to revisit lessons and review materials.</li>
  <li>Mass streaming: Access to educational content on a larger scale.</li>
  <li>Hybrid models: Combination of in-person and online teaching for flexibility.</li>
  <li>Online platforms: Convenient and accessible learning experience.</li>
  <li>Classroom-based: Traditional setting with teacher-student interaction.</li>
  <li>Tutorial centers: Dedicated centers for subject-specific instruction.</li>
  <li>Home tuition: Individualized teaching in a familiar environment.</li>
  <li>Online tutoring: Virtual tutoring sessions for remote learning.</li>
  <li>Exam-focused crash courses: Intensive courses for exam preparation.</li>
  <li>Subject-specific coaching: Specialized instruction to enhance understanding.</li>
  <li>Remedial tuition: Targeted support for students who need extra help.</li>
  <li>Enrichment programs: Supplementary classes to broaden knowledge and skills.</li>
  <li>Preparatory classes: Preparation for educational transitions and exams.</li>
</ul>

<p>Covid accelerated the online models, and as shown in kdramas, you’ll get masses of students listening to a tutor livestream their teachings.</p>

<h4 id="tuition-in-relations-to-gifted-education-program-in-singapore">Tuition in relations to Gifted Education Program in Singapore</h4>

<p>One ting expats in Singapore may not know is that many go through tuition to get into a Gifted Education Program in Singapore. A Gifted Education Program (GEP) is a specialized educational program designed to meet the needs of academically gifted or talented students. It aims to provide a more challenging and enriched learning experience for students who demonstrate exceptional abilities in intellectual, creative, or specific academic domains. Funnily enough, those who get into GEP continue with education</p>

<p>The specific structure and implementation of GEP may vary between countries and educational systems. In general, however, the program identifies gifted students through various assessment methods, such as standardized tests, teacher recommendations, or portfolio assessments. Once identified, these students are offered specialized instruction and curriculum that goes beyond the standard curriculum provided to their peers.</p>

<p>Gifted education programs often feature accelerated learning, in-depth study of subjects, problem-solving activities, and opportunities for creativity and critical thinking. They may involve small class sizes, specialized teachers, and access to resources and enrichment activities not typically available in regular classrooms.</p>

<p>The goals of a Gifted Education Program are to nurture the talents and potential of gifted students, provide appropriate intellectual stimulation, foster their social and emotional development, and support their overall growth. These programs aim to challenge gifted students academically, help them reach their full potential, and prepare them for future academic and professional success.</p>

<p>Gifted education programs can be found at various levels of education, ranging from primary and secondary schools to higher education institutions. The specific criteria for eligibility and the nature of the program may differ based on the country’s educational policies and practices.</p>

<p>It is important to note that gifted education programs are designed to meet the unique needs of gifted students and provide them with an educational environment that supports their advanced abilities. The aim is to ensure that gifted students are appropriately challenged, engaged, and given opportunities to thrive academically and personally.</p>

<h4 id="so-how-much-is-spent-on-tuition">So how much is spent on tuition?</h4>

<p>The average spend on tuition in Singapore and Hong Kong varies based on factors such as the level of education, subjects, and the individual preferences of students and parents. In Singapore, where tuition is highly prevalent, the average monthly expenditure on tuition can range from SGD 200 to SGD 1,000 or more, depending on the grade level and intensity of the tuition sought. Some families may spend even higher amounts for specialized programs or individual tutoring. Here are a few stats for Singapore - 1) In 2019, Singapore families spent $1.4b on private tuition for kids last year, 2) 70% of parents send their child for tuition. 8 in 10 Primary school students and 6 in 10 Secondary school students pay for private tuition. This sounds pretty unhealthy to me, given the dollars and time invested.</p>

<p>In Hong Kong, the average spend on tuition is also significant, reflecting the competitive academic environment. The monthly expenditure on tuition can range from HKD 1,000 to HKD 5,000 or higher. Like in Singapore, the costs can vary based on the grade level, subjects, and the reputation and quality of the tuition center or private tutor.</p>

<p>It’s important to note that these figures are approximate averages and can vary significantly depending on individual circumstances. Factors such as the number of subjects, frequency of tuition sessions, and the specific educational goals of students and parents can influence the overall expenditure on tuition.</p>

<p>Furthermore, it’s worth mentioning that the tuition landscape in both Singapore and Hong Kong is highly diverse, with a wide range of options available at various price points. Families have the flexibility to choose from group tuition, private tutoring, online platforms, and specialized programs, each with its own cost structure.</p>

<p>Overall, while tuition can be a substantial financial commitment for families in both Singapore and Hong Kong, it is considered a valuable investment in students’ academic success and future prospects. The average spend on tuition reflects the importance placed on education and the willingness of parents to provide additional support to enhance their children’s learning experiences.</p>

<h4 id="negative-effects-of-tuition-and-enrichment-centers">Negative effects of tuition and enrichment centers</h4>

<p>Listing just a few…</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Increased Academic Pressure:
Statistics from the Programme for International Student Assessment (PISA) showed that Singaporean students reported higher levels of academic pressure compared to their international counterparts.
According to a survey conducted by the National Youth Council, around 90% of students in Singapore feel stressed about academic performance.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Impact on Mental Health:
The Institute of Mental Health reported that about 1 in 7 students aged 13 to 16 in Singapore experienced significant symptoms of anxiety and depression.
A study by the National University of Singapore found that high-stress levels due to academic pressure were associated with higher rates of mental health issues among students.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Reduced Creativity and Well-Rounded Development:
The emphasis on academic achievement and structured learning in enrichment centers may limit opportunities for students to explore their creativity and develop a well-rounded skill set.
The Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD) reported that Singaporean students had lower levels of creative problem-solving skills compared to their international peers.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Financial Burden:
Enrichment programs can be expensive, adding to the financial burden on families. According to a survey by the Singapore Department of Statistics, education expenses accounted for a significant portion of household expenditure.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Educational Inequality:
Higher-income families have greater access to enrichment centers, creating educational disparities between socioeconomic groups. This may perpetuate inequality and hinder equal opportunities for academic success.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>I’m sure parents know of these reasons already, but it’s just part of Singapore society now. Tuition centers have woven themselves into the very fabric of Singapore, perpetuating a culture of excessive academic pressure and fostering a dependency on external help for success. This pervasive reliance on tuition has created a system where students feel inadequate without constant supplementary support, breeding a sense of insecurity and stifling their true potential.</p>

<h4 id="top-tuition-centers-in-hong-kong-and-singapore">Top tuition centers in Hong Kong and Singapore</h4>

<p>Top Tuition Centers in Hong Kong: In Hong Kong, several prominent tuition centers have established themselves as leaders in the industry. For instance, Beacon College, known for its strong track record in helping students excel in examinations, offers comprehensive programs and experienced tutors. Similarly, Modern Education, with its personalized approach and small class sizes, aims to provide individual attention to students. These centers employ marketing tactics such as testimonials from successful students, showcasing their achievements and emphasizing the effectiveness of their teaching methods. They also organize workshops and seminars to engage parents and highlight their centers’ expertise.</p>

<p>Top Tuition Centers in Singapore: Likewise, Singapore boasts several renowned tuition centers that have gained popularity among students and parents. The Learning Lab, known for its structured curriculum and highly qualified tutors, focuses on holistic development and academic excellence. Another notable center is MindChamps, which combines academic enrichment with character development, offering a unique approach to education. These centers employ marketing strategies such as informative websites, featuring their success stories and testimonials from satisfied parents. They also leverage social media platforms and collaborate with schools to enhance their visibility and reputation.</p>

<h4 id="marketing-tactics-of-these-tuition-centers">Marketing tactics of these tuition centers</h4>

<p>Let’s switch gears and discuss the marketing tactics of tuition centers.</p>

<p>In a predatory manner, tuition centers in both Hong Kong and Singapore employ manipulative marketing tactics to prey on students and their parents. Exploiting the fears and insecurities surrounding academic success, these centers boast about their high success rates, using testimonials and selective statistics to lure in vulnerable students. By forging partnerships with schools and leveraging online platforms, they establish an air of legitimacy and credibility, deceiving parents into believing that their services are necessary for their child’s educational advancement. These profit-driven establishments capitalize on the educational anxiety of families, perpetuating a toxic cycle of dependency and extracting financial gains at the expense of students’ well-being.</p>

<p>I see photos of young adults and their grades littered across mall banners, bus ads and building displays in Singapore. Great marketing, not healthy for society.</p>

<h4 id="how-is-the-industry-regulated">How is the industry regulated?</h4>

<p>Both Hong Kong and Singapore have regulations in place regarding tuition centers to ensure quality education and safeguard the interests of students.</p>

<p>In Hong Kong, tuition centers are governed by the Education Bureau (EDB) and are required to register with the government. The Education Ordinance sets out guidelines for tuition centers, including requirements for proper facilities, qualified teachers, and adherence to safety regulations. The EDB conducts inspections and imposes penalties for non-compliance or operating without registration.</p>

<p>Similarly, in Singapore, tuition centers are regulated by the Ministry of Education (MOE). Tuition centers must comply with the Private Education Act and the Committee for Private Education (CPE) regulations. They need to be registered with the MOE or be exempted from registration. The MOE monitors tuition centers to ensure they meet the necessary standards, including teacher qualifications, premises safety, and appropriate pedagogical practices.</p>

<p>Both jurisdictions also have regulations in place to prevent excessive advertising and misleading claims by tuition centers. Advertisements must be accurate, transparent, and adhere to guidelines set by the respective authorities. This is to protect consumers, particularly parents and students, from false or exaggerated promises.</p>

<p>These regulations aim to maintain the quality and integrity of tuition services, ensuring that students receive effective and reliable educational support. By imposing standards on tuition centers, the authorities seek to safeguard the educational well-being of students and promote a fair and transparent learning environment.</p>

<h4 id="is-tuition-an-addiction">Is tuition an addiction?</h4>

<p>Yes. Tuition has become an addiction in many educational systems, including in Hong Kong and Singapore. The intense pressure to excel academically, coupled with the fear of falling behind, has created a culture where students and parents alike feel compelled to rely on tuition as a crutch. This addiction is fueled by the belief that extra classes and constant studying are the only pathways to success, leaving little room for personal growth, hobbies, or a balanced lifestyle. Students become dependent on the constant validation and reassurance that tuition provides, fearing that without it, they will lose their competitive edge. The addictive nature of tuition perpetuates a cycle of high expectations, stress, and burnout, ultimately undermining the intrinsic joy of learning and stifling individual creativity and curiosity.</p>

<p>My recommendation to parents is to let the kids learn through school and self study and if they are really struggling in some subjects or want a leg up in another, then explore tuition as an option. Don’t put your kids through enrichment classes every evening. Let them play, enjoy themselves and build knowledge through their own curiosity.</p>

<p>What do you think of the enrichment center system? Comment in your thoughts. Subscribe now to see more content like this.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Education" /><category term="tuition" /><category term="Hong Kong" /><category term="Singapore" /><category term="parents" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[During a casual lunch with a friend, I was taken aback when he revealed that he spends a staggering $1000 SGD per month on tuition for his 5-year-old child, highlighting the extent to which some parents prioritize academic enrichment from an early age. My friend’s kid seemed like a smart one - why drill more knowledge in her from such a young age? In an earlier post, I touched on the education system in Singapore and Hong Kong. Both countries place great emphasis on academic excellence, leading to a thriving tuition landscape in both regions. The perception of tuition being ingrained as a necessity by parents has sparked debates on its potential negative impact on children’s well-being and overall education system. In today’s post, we’ll dive into the emergence of tuition, effects the industry has on parents and children and a comparison of the top tuition centers and their marketing tactics in Hong Kong and Singapore. I’d say tuition is more common with locals, but an increasing number of expats in Singapore is exploring this. In case you missed out, check out my earlier article on the education system of Singapore and how it fares against Hong Kong.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/bamboo.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/bamboo.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Guide to Singapore’s healthcare system: Public vs Private</title><link href="/singapore-healthcare/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Guide to Singapore’s healthcare system: Public vs Private" /><published>2023-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-healthcare</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-healthcare/"><![CDATA[<p>The pandemic’s over. Wahoo! Singapore’s healthcare system, renowned for its efficiency, quality, and accessibility, was put under the spotlight during the past 3 years of COVID. This post explores the distinctions between private and public healthcare in Singapore, examining factors such as cost, accessibility, and quality of care. Additionally, it delves into the remuneration of doctors in Singapore, shedding light on their earning potential and the considerations surrounding their salaries. Oh, you’ll also find out about the best hospitals and where you can find them. By understanding the dynamics of Singapore’s healthcare landscape, we gain insights into the complex interplay between private and public sectors and the compensation structures that shape the medical profession in the country. We won’t be covering insurance in-depth in this post (especially cheap health insurance). We’ll save that for another time.</p>

<h4 id="hk-vs-singapore---a-little-on-their-healthcare-systems">HK vs Singapore - a little on their healthcare systems</h4>

<p>Let’s begin with comparing these two Asian countries before we double click into Singapore. The healthcare systems in Hong Kong and Singapore are often praised for their efficiency, accessibility, and quality of care. Comparing across a few criteria -</p>

<p>Healthcare Expenditure: In terms of healthcare expenditure, Hong Kong and Singapore differ significantly. According to the World Bank, Hong Kong’s healthcare expenditure accounted for approximately 17.5% of its GDP in 2019, while Singapore’s healthcare expenditure was around 4.8% of its GDP in the same year. This substantial disparity suggests that Hong Kong allocates a higher proportion of its resources to healthcare compared to Singapore.</p>

<p>Infrastructure and Facilities: Both Hong Kong and Singapore boast well-developed healthcare infrastructures. Hong Kong features a mix of public and private hospitals, including several renowned medical centers and specialty hospitals. Singapore, on the other hand, is known for its excellent public healthcare system, with a network of public hospitals and polyclinics. Additionally, Singapore has actively promoted medical tourism, attracting patients from around the world to seek specialized treatments.</p>

<p>Healthcare Outcomes: When examining healthcare outcomes, both Hong Kong and Singapore demonstrate commendable results. According to the World Health Organization (WHO), Hong Kong’s life expectancy at birth is approximately 84 years, while Singapore’s stands at around 83 years. These figures indicate that residents of both regions enjoy relatively long and healthy lives.</p>

<p>Patient Satisfaction: Patient satisfaction is a crucial aspect of healthcare delivery. In a survey conducted by the Hong Kong Hospital Authority in 2020, 76% of respondents expressed satisfaction with the quality of healthcare services provided. Similarly, a survey conducted by the Ministry of Health in Singapore in the same year reported that 85% of patients were satisfied with the overall quality of care received. These high satisfaction rates reflect the emphasis placed on patient-centered care in both systems.</p>

<p>Challenges and Opportunities: Despite the positive aspects, both healthcare systems face challenges. In Hong Kong, long waiting times for specialist appointments and limited resources are areas of concern. In Singapore, the rising cost of healthcare and an aging population present challenges to sustainability and affordability. However, these challenges also present opportunities for continuous improvement, innovation, and policy reforms in both regions.</p>

<p>Overall, both systems are robust, advanced and managed well. If you’re deciding which country to live in, I wouldn’t use healthcare as a deciding factor.</p>

<h4 id="cost-of-healthcare">Cost of healthcare</h4>

<p>The average cost of healthcare in Singapore can vary depending on factors such as the type of medical service needed, the healthcare facility, and whether an individual is a citizen, permanent resident, or foreigner. However, it’s important to note that the healthcare system in Singapore operates on a mixed financing model, with government subsidies and insurance coverage helping to make healthcare more affordable for residents.</p>

<p>For Singapore citizens and permanent residents, a significant portion of healthcare costs is covered by government subsidies and the mandatory national health insurance scheme known as MediShield Life. MediShield Life provides basic coverage for hospitalization and selected outpatient treatments.</p>

<p>That being said, there may still be out-of-pocket expenses, such as deductibles, co-payments, and non-subsidized services. The specific costs can vary widely based on factors like the complexity of the medical procedure, the ward class chosen (e.g., public hospital A ward, B1 ward, etc.), and the specific healthcare provider.</p>

<p>For foreigners or individuals without permanent residency in Singapore, the cost of healthcare can be higher (significantly). They are generally not eligible for government subsidies and may need to rely on private insurance or self-payment for medical expenses. Private healthcare providers in Singapore often have their own pricing structures, which can vary significantly. All that being said, expats are most likely covered by private insurance from the company, with most being top-class. My company’s insurance covers $500 USD worth of eyeglasses every year. You just can’t complain. Insurance for expats in Singapore if out of pocket is expensive, but we’ll save that for another time.</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/assets/images/supportsystems.jpg" alt="supportsystems" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>Singapore healthcare is one of the best support systems for the nation’s prosperity</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<h4 id="service-providers">Service providers</h4>

<p>Public Singapore hospitals form the backbone for most of the country. Whilst the wait for public hospitals is generally much longer, the quality of them is top notch in Singapore. These hospitals provide high-quality medical services to cater to the healthcare needs of both local residents and international patients. Here are some features of public hospitals in Singapore:</p>
<ul>
  <li>High-quality medical services: Singapore’s public hospitals have modern facilities and advanced medical technology to deliver excellent healthcare services. These hospitals have top-notch medical experts and nursing staff dedicated to the treatment and care of patients (comparable to private)</li>
  <li>Wide range of specialized healthcare: Singapore’s public hospitals cover various specialized fields, including internal medicine, surgery, obstetrics and gynecology, pediatrics, cardiology, ophthalmology, orthopedics, and more. Whether it’s routine health check-ups or complex surgeries, these hospitals provide comprehensive specialized medical services.</li>
  <li>Medical technology and innovation: Singapore’s public hospitals are committed to driving medical technology innovation and application. These hospitals adopt advanced diagnostic and treatment technologies, including medical imaging, surgical robotics, genetic testing, precision medicine, and more, to provide more accurate and effective healthcare.</li>
  <li>Medical research and education: Public hospitals in Singapore collaborate closely with academic and research institutions to advance medical research and education. These hospitals constantly strive to enhance the level of healthcare and service quality through scientific research and the exchange of medical knowledge.</li>
  <li>Comprehensive healthcare services: Singapore’s public hospitals offer comprehensive healthcare services, including preventive care, health screenings, chronic disease management, and rehabilitation care. These hospitals are committed to maintaining people’s overall health and provide various preventive measures and health promotion activities.</li>
</ul>

<p>In conclusion, public hospitals in Singapore provide top-quality medical services, advanced technology, and a wide range of specialized healthcare. They prioritize patient care and continuously contribute to medical research and education. These hospitals play a crucial role in ensuring the well-being and health of the population in Singapore.</p>

<p>Here’s a list of the popular public hospitals</p>
<ul>
  <li>Singapore General Hospital (SGH): SGH is the largest and oldest public hospital in Singapore. It offers a comprehensive range of medical services and specialties, including general medicine, surgery, cardiology, oncology, and more.</li>
  <li>National University Hospital (NUH): NUH is a tertiary hospital linked to the National University of Singapore. It provides specialized medical care in various areas, including cardiology, orthopedics, neurology, and pediatrics.</li>
  <li>Changi General Hospital (CGH): CGH is located in the eastern part of Singapore and offers a wide range of medical services, including emergency care, surgery, women’s health, and geriatrics.</li>
  <li>Khoo Teck Puat Hospital (KTPH): KTPH is a community hospital with a focus on holistic healthcare and patient-centered services. It provides general medical and surgical services, as well as specialized care in areas such as psychiatry and rehabilitation.</li>
  <li>Tan Tock Seng Hospital (TTSH): TTSH is a leading acute care general hospital in Singapore. It offers a comprehensive range of medical services, including infectious diseases, respiratory medicine, gastroenterology, and more.</li>
</ul>

<p>Others include Alexandra hospital, KK Women’s and Children’s Hospital (KKH), national university hospital and woodlands hospital. When looking for a hospital, remember to see what’s your nearest hospital and the hospital visiting hours.</p>

<h4 id="what-are-polyclinics">What are polyclinics?</h4>
<p>Polyclinics in Singapore are primary healthcare facilities that provide a range of general medical services to the public. These clinics are operated by the National Healthcare Group (NHG) and SingHealth, two major healthcare clusters in Singapore. Polyclinics aim to offer accessible and affordable healthcare services to Singaporean residents.</p>

<p>Here are some key features and services provided by polyclinics:</p>
<ul>
  <li>General Medical Services: Polyclinics offer general outpatient services such as consultations, examinations, diagnosis, and treatment for common medical conditions. They are staffed by a team of general practitioners (GPs) who provide primary healthcare.</li>
  <li>Chronic Disease Management: Polyclinics play a vital role in managing chronic diseases such as diabetes, hypertension, asthma, and others. They provide regular monitoring, health education, and medication management to help patients manage their conditions effectively.</li>
  <li>Health Screening: Polyclinics offer health screening programs that cover various age groups and specific health concerns. These screenings help detect and prevent potential health problems at an early stage.</li>
  <li>Dental Services: Many polyclinics have dental clinics that provide basic dental services like check-ups, scaling, polishing, and extractions.</li>
  <li>Health Promotion and Education: Polyclinics conduct health promotion activities and provide education on preventive measures, healthy lifestyle practices, and disease management.</li>
  <li>Allied Health Services: Some polyclinics have allied health professionals such as dietitians, physiotherapists, and occupational therapists who offer specialized services to support patient care.</li>
</ul>

<p>Polyclinics in Singapore operate on an appointment-based system, although walk-in consultations may be available for urgent cases. The fees charged at polyclinics are subsidized for Singaporean citizens and permanent residents, making healthcare services more affordable. Patients can also use their national health insurance, MediSave, to pay for eligible services at polyclinics. Polyclinics serve as an essential component of Singapore’s primary healthcare system, providing accessible and comprehensive care to the community.</p>

<h3 id="on-to-private-hospitals">On to private hospitals</h3>

<h4 id="why-go-private">Why go private?</h4>

<p>There are several reasons why individuals might choose to go to private hospitals instead of public hospitals in Singapore. Here are some possible reasons:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Shorter waiting times: Private hospitals generally have shorter waiting times for consultations, treatments, and surgeries compared to public hospitals. This can be appealing for individuals who prefer quicker access to medical services.</li>
  <li>More personalized care: Private hospitals often provide a more personalized and luxurious healthcare experience. They may offer amenities such as private rooms, personalized attention from medical staff, and a greater focus on patient comfort and convenience.</li>
  <li>Access to specific doctors or specialists: Private hospitals may have a wider selection of doctors and specialists who may be renowned in their respective fields. Patients who have specific preferences or seek specialized care from a particular doctor may opt for private hospitals to access their preferred healthcare providers.</li>
  <li>Comprehensive health screening packages: Private hospitals often offer comprehensive health screening packages that cater to individuals who prioritize preventive care and regular health check-ups. These packages may include a wide range of tests and examinations to assess overall health and detect potential health issues at an early stage.</li>
  <li>Greater flexibility and choice: Private hospitals provide individuals with more flexibility and choice in terms of appointment scheduling, treatment options, and hospital preferences. Patients may have more control over their healthcare decisions and the ability to tailor their treatment experience according to their preferences.</li>
  <li>Availability of alternative therapies: Private hospitals may offer a broader range of alternative therapies and complementary medicine options that are not typically available in public hospitals. This can attract individuals who prefer a more holistic approach to healthcare. We’ll cover Traditional Chinese Medicine (TCM) another time, but that’s also a huge industry in Singapore.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="popular-private-hospitals">Popular private hospitals</h4>
<p>Here are some notable private hospitals in Singapore:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Mount Elizabeth Hospital: Mount Elizabeth Hospital is one of the largest private hospitals in Singapore. It has two branches, Mount Elizabeth Orchard and Mount Elizabeth Novena, and offers a comprehensive range of medical specialties and advanced treatment options. This is part of the Parkway Health Group.</li>
  <li>Gleneagles Hospital: Gleneagles Hospital is a renowned private hospital in Singapore known for its high-quality healthcare services. It provides specialized care in areas such as cardiology, oncology, orthopedics, and women’s health. This is also part of the Parkway Health Group</li>
  <li>Raffles Hospital: Raffles Hospital is a leading private hospital that offers a wide range of medical services and specialties. It is known for its advanced diagnostic and treatment capabilities and provides personalized and holistic healthcare.</li>
  <li>Thomson Medical Centre: Thomson Medical Centre is a private hospital that specializes in women’s and children’s healthcare. It offers a comprehensive range of obstetrics, gynecology, and pediatric services.</li>
  <li>Parkway East Hospital: Parkway East Hospital is a private general acute care hospital located in the eastern part of Singapore. It provides a broad range of medical services, including surgery, internal medicine, and specialized outpatient care.</li>
</ul>

<p>My humnble opinion of what’s best - I’ve spent a long time at Raffles and recently moved over to Gleneagles / Mount E. Whilst Raffles doctors are fantastic, I struggle with their nurses, booking systems that surprisingly don’t communicate much with each other and insurance expenses (despite having the best medical insurance policy in Singapore). P.S., their health checks all suck.</p>

<h4 id="private-versus-public-comparison">Private versus public comparison</h4>

<p>Whilst these are just approximates, here are cost ranges for healthcare services in Singapore, comparing public and private sectors:</p>

<p><u> Consultation fees <u></u></u></p>
<ul>
  <li>Public healthcare: GP consultation fees range from SGD 20 to SGD 50.</li>
  <li>Private healthcare: GP consultation fees can range from SGD 50 to SGD 150 or more.</li>
</ul>

<p><u> Hospitalization costs (per day) <u></u></u></p>

<p>Public healthcare:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Class B2 ward (shared room): SGD 200 to SGD 400.</li>
  <li>Class B1 ward (semi-private room): SGD 500 to SGD 800.</li>
  <li>Class A ward (single room): SGD 800 to SGD 2,000 or more.</li>
</ul>

<p>Private healthcare: Hospitalization costs can range from SGD 1,000 to SGD 3,000 or more, depending on the ward type and hospital.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Outpatient services and treatments:</li>
  <li>Public healthcare: Diagnostic tests and procedures may have subsidized rates, varying depending on the specific service.</li>
  <li>Private healthcare: Diagnostic tests and procedures in private clinics or specialist centers can range from SGD 100 to SGD 500 or more, depending on the test or procedure.</li>
</ul>

<p>Medications:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Public healthcare: Medications in public hospitals are typically available at subsidized rates, with prices varying based on the specific medication.</li>
  <li>Private healthcare: Medication costs in private healthcare settings can vary significantly depending on the medication and the pharmacy. Branded or specialized medications may be more expensive.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="singapore-absolutely-crushed-the-pandemic">Singapore absolutely crushed the pandemic</h4>

<p>Singapore has been widely recognized for its effective management of the COVID-19 pandemic. The government implemented a comprehensive and proactive approach to control the spread of the virus and protect public health. Here are some key measures and strategies employed by Singapore:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Early Response and Preparedness: Singapore responded swiftly to the outbreak by establishing a multi-ministry task force and implementing a range of preventive measures even before the first local cases were reported. This included border controls, contact tracing, quarantine measures, and public communication campaigns.</li>
  <li>Robust Testing and Contact Tracing: Singapore implemented widespread testing to identify and isolate infected individuals. Contact tracing efforts were intensified through the use of technology, such as the + TraceTogether mobile app, which helped identify and notify close contacts of confirmed cases.</li>
  <li>Stringent Quarantine and Isolation Measures: Infected individuals and close contacts were required to undergo mandatory quarantine or isolation in dedicated facilities or at home. Strict enforcement and monitoring were in place to ensure compliance.</li>
  <li>Public Health Measures: Singapore implemented various public health measures such as mask-wearing, safe distancing, and regular hand hygiene. These measures were communicated to the public through extensive public education campaigns.</li>
  <li>Effective Healthcare System: Singapore’s healthcare system, with its strong infrastructure and capacity, played a crucial role in managing the pandemic. The government worked closely with healthcare institutions to increase testing capabilities, hospital capacity, and ensure sufficient resources for patient care.</li>
  <li>Clear Communication and Public Engagement: Regular updates and clear communication from government authorities helped to keep the public informed and educated about the evolving situation. Public engagement and adherence to guidelines were emphasized to foster a collective responsibility in managing the pandemic.</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="given-the-healthcare-system-is-so-robust-how-much-are-doctors-being-paid">Given the healthcare system is so robust, how much are doctors being paid?</h4>

<p>You’ll be surprised with this one.</p>

<p>1st year doctor pay in USD</p>
<ul>
  <li>SG: $3400</li>
  <li>HK: $10K</li>
  <li>US: $5400</li>
</ul>

<p>Median gross monthly salary for Singapore fresh graduates is $3.1K USD. (source - Strait times). It baffles me how little these first year doctors earn. For context, a fresh non-tech grad at Google in the US earns $8000 working 40 hours a week. Singapore first year doctors work at least 60% more hours.</p>

<p>I personally know 1st year doctors who were thrown into COVID wards, and whilst there was overall fear, the resounding message was the government is in control. All that being said, they were awarded with medals (versus any sort of monetary reward) for their service. I understand doctors are here to serve the public but it’d be nice for them to be compensated.</p>

<h4 id="no-wonder-theres-a-shortage-on-doctors">No wonder there’s a shortage on doctors…</h4>

<p>What’s interesting now is that there’s a shortage of doctors. As of my knowledge cutoff in September 2021, Singapore has been experiencing a relative shortage of doctors in certain specialties and settings. While Singapore has a well-established healthcare system and a sufficient number of doctors overall, there are specific areas that face challenges in terms of doctor availability.</p>

<p>One area of concern is the demand for specialized medical professionals, such as oncologists, cardiologists, and psychiatrists, which has been growing due to an aging population and increased healthcare needs. Additionally, some rural or remote areas in Singapore may have difficulty attracting doctors, leading to a disparity in healthcare access.</p>

<p>To address this, the Singaporean government has implemented various initiatives to increase the supply of doctors. These efforts include expanding medical education capacity, attracting foreign doctors, and offering scholarships and incentives to encourage medical students to specialize in needed fields.
It’s important to note that the situation may have evolved since my last update, and it’s recommended to refer to recent reports and studies for the most accurate and up-to-date information on the current doctor shortage in Singapore. Please increase pay for public doctors.</p>

<p>The healthcare system in Singapore is undeniably a privilege. With its efficient, high-quality, and accessible healthcare services, supported by well-funded public hospitals, advanced medical technology, and government subsidies, Singaporeans are fortunate to have comprehensive healthcare coverage that is the envy of many nations. The ability to receive top-notch medical care without significant financial burden truly makes Singapore’s healthcare system a valuable privilege for its expats and citizens.</p>

<p>Comment in your thoughts. Subscribe now to see more content like this.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Healthcare" /><category term="hospitals" /><category term="cost of living" /><category term="Hong Kong" /><category term="Singapore" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The pandemic’s over. Wahoo! Singapore’s healthcare system, renowned for its efficiency, quality, and accessibility, was put under the spotlight during the past 3 years of COVID. This post explores the distinctions between private and public healthcare in Singapore, examining factors such as cost, accessibility, and quality of care. Additionally, it delves into the remuneration of doctors in Singapore, shedding light on their earning potential and the considerations surrounding their salaries. Oh, you’ll also find out about the best hospitals and where you can find them. By understanding the dynamics of Singapore’s healthcare landscape, we gain insights into the complex interplay between private and public sectors and the compensation structures that shape the medical profession in the country. We won’t be covering insurance in-depth in this post (especially cheap health insurance). We’ll save that for another time.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/supportsystems.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/supportsystems.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>