<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2025-03-28T05:15:56+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">From HK to SG</title><entry><title type="html">Grab vs Gojek vs taxi in Singapore: Cheapest Rides &amp;amp; How to Chooses</title><link href="/singapore-taxi-grab-apps/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Grab vs Gojek vs taxi in Singapore: Cheapest Rides &amp;amp; How to Chooses" /><published>2025-03-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-taxi-grab-apps</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-taxi-grab-apps/"><![CDATA[<p>Grab and Gojek have changed the way we get around, replacing the old-fashioned taxi hunt with the magic of ride-hailing apps.</p>

<p>Whether you’re booking a GrabCar, a GrabTaxi, or wondering which app offers the cheapest ride in Singapore, there’s a service for almost every need—except maybe teleportation. But how different are ride-hailing apps from regular taxi apps, and do they actually make money, or are they just burning investor cash? And if you’ve got a pet, a baby, or an unreasonable number of suitcases, how do you even book the right ride? Let’s break down the chaos of Singapore’s ride-hailing scene and figure out what’s worth your time (and your wallet).</p>

<h3 id="what-are-ride-hailing-apps">What are ride-hailing apps?</h3>

<p>Ride-hailing apps like Grab Singapore and Gojek Singapore let you book rides through your phone, connecting you with nearby drivers—at a price that may surge when you need it most. Unlike taxis, these apps offer different vehicle options, from budget to premium, and use dynamic pricing instead of fixed fares. They’re a modern, convenient way to get around—just be ready for the occasional sticker shock.</p>

<h3 id="how-are-taxi-apps-different-from-ride-hailing-apps">How are taxi apps different from ride-hailing apps?</h3>

<p>Taxi apps connect you to metered cabs, while ride-hailing apps like Grab Singapore and Gojek Singapore let you book both private-hire cars and taxis. With options like GrabTaxi, you can still get a traditional cab through a ride-hailing app, but services like GrabCar use dynamic pricing that fluctuates with demand. Ride-hailing apps also offer more vehicle choices, from budget rides to premium cars—though no app can guarantee your driver won’t cancel at the last minute. In short, taxi apps stick to old-school metered fares, while ride-hailing apps give you more options (and sometimes, more surprises).</p>

<h3 id="what-types-of-services-do-ride-hailing-apps-provide">What types of services do ride-hailing apps provide?</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Ride-hailing apps in Singapore offer a variety of services to cater to different needs:</li>
  <li>Standard Rides – Most apps, like Grab Singapore and Gojek Singapore, offer basic ride options, from budget-friendly GrabCar to slightly more luxurious choices.</li>
  <li>Taxi Booking – You can book traditional metered taxis through apps like ComfortDelGro and Grab (via GrabTaxi).</li>
  <li>Carpooling – Apps like Ryde provide carpooling services, letting you share a ride with others for a lower fare.</li>
  <li>Premium Rides – For those wanting a little more luxury, services like GrabPremium offer higher-end cars.</li>
  <li>Pet-Friendly Rides – Ryde and Gojek Singapore offer pet-friendly options for those traveling with animals.</li>
  <li>Food and Package Delivery – Grab extends beyond rides, offering GrabFood and GrabExpress for deliveries.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="what-common-taxi-apps-and-ride-hailing-apps-are-there-in-singapore">What common taxi apps and ride-hailing apps are there in SIngapore?</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Grab Singapore – Offers GrabCar, GrabTaxi, and other transport options.</li>
  <li>Gojek Singapore – Competes with Grab, often with lower fares and promotions.</li>
  <li>Ryde – Provides carpooling, private-hire rides, and even pet-friendly options.</li>
  <li>TADA – A commission-free ride-hailing app that claims to offer fairer pricing.</li>
  <li>ComfortDelGro – Lets you book traditional metered taxis or fixed-fare rides.</li>
</ul>

<p>Note - Uber or Lyft does not exist in SIngapore</p>

<h3 id="how-do-these-apps-compare-against-each-other">How do these apps compare against each other?</h3>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th><strong>App</strong></th>
      <th><strong>Strengths</strong></th>
      <th><strong>Drawbacks</strong></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td><strong>Grab Singapore</strong></td>
      <td>Most widely used, offers a range of services beyond transport</td>
      <td>Surge pricing, occasional driver cancellations</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><strong>Gojek Singapore</strong></td>
      <td>Competitive pricing, frequent promotions, motorcycle rides</td>
      <td>Smaller fleet, limited availability during peak hours</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><strong>Ryde</strong></td>
      <td>Carpooling, pet-friendly, eco-friendly options</td>
      <td>Smaller user base, fewer available rides</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><strong>TADA</strong></td>
      <td>Commission-free, potentially lower fares</td>
      <td>Limited fleet, less widespread</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td><strong>ComfortDelGro</strong></td>
      <td>Well-established, large fleet of traditional taxis</td>
      <td>Only traditional taxis, lacks variety compared to others</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<h3 id="which-of-these-apps-is-the-cheapest">Which of these apps is the cheapest?</h3>

<p>The cheapest ride-hailing app in Singapore often depends on several factors, such as the time of day, location, and demand. However, generally speaking:
Gojek Singapore is often considered one of the cheapest options due to its competitive pricing and regular promotions. They tend to offer more affordable fares, especially during off-peak hours or with special discounts.</p>

<p>TADA also positions itself as an affordable option since it operates with a commission-free model, which can result in lower fares for passengers.</p>

<p>Grab tends to have higher fares due to its more extensive range of services (e.g., GrabFood, GrabExpress) and premium options, although it does have occasional discounts and promotions.
How do I order a ride if I have a dog or a cat?</p>

<p>To travel with pets on Grab, you can use the GrabPet service, which is available in select regions. When booking a ride, simply select GrabPet as your ride option, and your driver will be prepared to accommodate your furry friend. Always check with the driver beforehand to confirm if pets are allowed, as policies may vary. Other competitors have similar offerings</p>

<h3 id="how-do-i-order-a-ride-if-i-have-a-baby">How do I order a ride if I have a baby?</h3>

<p>To order a ride with a baby, use GrabFamily on the Grab app, which offers cars equipped with child-friendly features like car seats. Alternatively, you can request a regular ride and bring your own car seat, but it’s always good to confirm with the driver beforehand.</p>

<h3 id="how-do-i-order-a-ride-if-i-have-two-suitcases">How do I order a ride if I have two suitcases?</h3>

<p>To order a ride with two suitcases, you can choose a larger vehicle option like GrabXL or Gojek XL for more luggage space. However, a normal car can generally fit two medium-sized suitcases, so you can also select a standard ride and confirm with the driver if there’s enough space for your bags.</p>

<h3 id="how-do-i-order-a-ride-if-i-have-four-suitcases">How do I order a ride if I have four suitcases?</h3>

<p>To order a ride with four suitcases, it’s generally not possible in a standard vehicle. You would need to select a larger option like GrabXL or Gojek XL, but even then, it is not possible to fit four large suitcases. It’s best to just order two Grabs.</p>

<h3 id="how-far-in-advance-should-i-schedule-my-ride">How far in advance should I schedule my ride?</h3>

<p>You can schedule a ride on most ride-hailing apps, like Grab and Gojek, up to 7 days in advance. However, it’s recommended to book at least 30 minutes to an hour before your desired time to ensure availability. Alternatively, you can just order and wait a few minutes, especially during non-peak times when rides are usually available faster.</p>

<h3 id="can-you-still-hail-a-taxi-from-the-streets-these-days">Can you still hail a taxi from the streets these days?</h3>

<p>Grab prioritizes riders based on factors like proximity to available drivers, ride type (e.g., GrabCar, GrabTaxi, GrabXL), and surge pricing. Riders in high-demand areas or during peak times may be prioritized with higher fares due to surge pricing. Additionally, riders with a higher GrabRewards status may find it easier to get a ride, as frequent users or those with better ratings are often given priority.</p>

<h3 id="do-ride-hailing-apps-make-money">Do ride-hailing apps make money?</h3>

<p>Ride-hailing apps like Grab and Gojek are not yet profitable, despite generating significant revenue. They prioritize growth and market share, often spending heavily on promotions and incentives. While they aim to become profitable through diversification and efficiency, many still have no clear path to profitability.</p>

<p>Personally, I only take grabs in urgent situations or to the airport. What about you?</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Singapore" /><category term="taxi" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Grab and Gojek have changed the way we get around, replacing the old-fashioned taxi hunt with the magic of ride-hailing apps.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/taxi.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/taxi.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">McDonald’s Singapore March 2025: Latest Menu, Pokémon Collab and App Deals</title><link href="/singapore-mcdonalds-march/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="McDonald’s Singapore March 2025: Latest Menu, Pokémon Collab and App Deals" /><published>2025-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-mcdonalds-march</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-mcdonalds-march/"><![CDATA[<p>Ah, McDonald’s in Singapore—where every meal feels like a new opportunity to indulge in the latest food fads, whether it’s their McDonald’s latest March menu or a collaboration with Pokémon.</p>

<p>Of course, you’re probably wondering where to find the best McDonald’s deals in March, or how to get the most out of those McDonald’s Singapore app promotions—don’t worry, we’ve got you covered. As if that wasn’t enough, there’s even an Easter party to look forward to, because nothing says festive quite like fast food. Whether you’re here to discover exclusive menu items or figure out how to optimize and get the best deal in McDonald’s, rest assured you’ll be in the know. So let’s dive into all the ways you can make your next McDonald’s experience a bit more…strategic.</p>

<h3 id="mcdonalds-latest-march-menu">McDonalds latest March menu</h3>

<p>Here’s a look at McDonald’s Singapore’s limited-time offerings for March 2025:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Curry Chicken McNuggets – Marinated in aromatic curry spices, these nuggets offer a savory twist to the classic Chicken McNuggets, available in 6, 9, or 20-piece servings.</li>
  <li>Nasi Lemak Burger – Featuring a crispy chicken patty infused with coconut flavors, fresh cucumbers, a fried egg, caramelized onions, sambal sauce, and ikan bilis, making a delicious return to the menu.</li>
  <li>Ovaltine McFlurry – A sweet treat with creamy vanilla soft serve and crunchy Ovaltine flakes, giving a comforting, local twist to the classic McFlurry.</li>
  <li>Coke® Float – A refreshing dessert combining creamy vanilla soft serve with the crisp fizz of Coca-Cola.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="best-mcdonalds-deals-in-march">Best McDonalds deals in March</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Curry Chicken McNuggets Feast: Enjoy 9 pieces of Curry Chicken McNuggets for just $9.90 when you order through the McDonald’s app.</li>
  <li>McSaver Meal Deals: Order any McSaver meal starting from $5 through the McDonald’s app, offering value without compromising on taste.</li>
  <li>$1.50 Sundaes: From March 17 to 21, indulge in Hot Fudge and Strawberry Sundaes at a special price of $1.50 each (usual price $2.40) at all Dessert Kiosks and restaurants islandwide</li>
</ul>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/assets/images/mc1.webp" alt="mc1" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>Curry chicken nuggets</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p><u>Ramadan Bundle Deals<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>8 pieces of McWings</li>
  <li>20 pieces of Chicken McNuggets® (choose from non-spicy, curry, or a mix)​</li>
  <li>3 medium fries​</li>
  <li>3 medium drinks</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Ramadan Burger Deal:<u></u></u></p>

<p>For just $14.90, enjoy a fulfilling and tasty meal perfect for Ramadan. This bundle includes:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Two juicy burgers – Choose from the spicy McSpicy, the crispy Filet-O-Fish, or the classic and comforting Double Cheeseburger.</li>
  <li>1 large serving of fries – Golden, crispy fries that are impossible to resist.</li>
  <li>1 refreshing drink – Choose from a variety of beverages to complement your meal.</li>
  <li>1 delicious Apple Pie – End your meal on a sweet note with McDonald’s signature warm and crispy Apple Pie.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="mcdonalds-singapore-app-promotions">McDonalds Singapore app promotions</h3>

<p>McDonald’s Singapore is offering a variety of app-exclusive promotions throughout March 2025. Here’s a summary of the current deals:​</p>
<ul>
  <li>Curry Chicken McNuggets Feast: Enjoy 9 pieces of curry-infused McNuggets, Smoky BBQ McShaker Fries, an Apple Pie, and a drink for just $9.90 (originally $12.80). Available daily from 12 PM to 11:55 PM through the McDonald’s app until March 26, 2025.​</li>
  <li>Free McDonald’s x Coca-Cola Cup with Selected Meals: From March 13 to 26, 2025, receive a complimentary limited-edition McDonald’s x Coca-Cola Cup with every order of a Curry Chicken McNuggets® Feast or Nasi Lemak Burger Feast via McDelivery, foodpanda, or Deliveroo.</li>
  <li>$1.50 Sundaes: Indulge in Hot Fudge and Strawberry Sundaes at a special price of $1.50 each (usual price $2.40) from March 17 to 21, 2025. Available at all Dessert Kiosks and restaurants.​</li>
  <li>Coke Float Deal: Enjoy a refreshing Coke Float for $1.50 (usual price $2.40) from March 17 to 21, 2025. Available via the McDonald’s app.</li>
  <li>Sausage McGriddles® with Egg Meal: Indulge in a Sausage McGriddles® with Egg Meal for only $6 when ordered through the McDonald’s app. Plus, every McGriddles® purchase comes with a chance to win premium gadgets and gifts.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="mcdonalds-easter-party">McDonalds Easter party</h3>
<p>​
McDonald’s Singapore is embracing the festive spirit of Easter with a series of engaging activities and promotions throughout March 2025. While specific details about an Easter party event have not been publicly announced, the following offerings are sure to delight both the young and the young at heart:​</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Easter-Themed Happy Meal Toys
In celebration of Easter, McDonald’s is introducing special Easter-themed Happy Meal toys. These toys are available with every Happy Meal purchase and are designed to add a festive touch to your meal.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Parties at McDonald’s
For an extra festive touch this Easter, McDonald’s Singapore is hosting an Easter Party at Queensway for just $25. This fun-filled event includes:</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<ol>
  <li>A Happy Meal for each participant</li>
  <li>Surprise door gifts to add an element of excitement</li>
  <li>Arts and crafts activities to spark creativity</li>
  <li>Games to keep the energy high and fun flowing</li>
  <li>A lucky draw with fantastic prizes to be won</li>
  <li>Best dress prizes for those who come dressed in their Easter finest</li>
</ol>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/assets/images/mc2.webp" alt="mc2" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>Easter McDonalds party</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<h3 id="mcdonalds-x-pokemon-collaboration">McDonalds x pokemon collaboration</h3>

<p>McDonald’s Singapore is partnering with Pokémon for an exciting collaboration this March 2025. Here’s what you can expect from this highly anticipated combo:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Exclusive Pokémon Cards: When you purchase a Happy Meal, you’ll receive a pack of four random Pokémon cards featuring popular characters like Pikachu, Charizard, and Eevee. These collectible cards are part of a limited-edition series that’s only available while stocks last.</li>
  <li>Weekly Releases: Every Thursday at 11 AM, McDonald’s releases new designs, ensuring there’s always something fresh to collect. Whether you’re a die-hard Pokémon fan or just love a fun surprise, these cards are perfect for your collection.</li>
  <li>Pokémon-Themed Happy Meals: Along with the cards, your Happy Meal will come with fun Pokémon-themed toys, making each meal even more exciting for kids (and adults who are still young at heart).</li>
</ul>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/assets/images/mc3.webp" alt="mc3" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>Pokemon x McDonalds</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<h3 id="secret-mcdonald-tips-in-singapore">Secret McDonald tips in Singapore</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Ask for extra sauce: Whether it’s for your nuggets, fries, or burger, don’t hesitate to ask for extra sauce. You might be surprised at how generous they are when you ask!</li>
  <li>Get a fresh batch of fries: If you’re craving crispy fries, simply ask for a fresh batch. This way, you can enjoy fries that are hot and perfectly crispy, not the ones that have been sitting under the heat lamp.</li>
  <li>Fries with no salt: If you prefer your fries without salt, just ask. They’ll make a fresh batch for you without any seasoning. You can always add your own salt later, or enjoy the natural flavor.</li>
  <li>Less ice in drinks: If you’re not a fan of watered-down drinks, ask for less ice. That way, your drink stays at its full strength and cool without being diluted.</li>
  <li>Salt and pepper packets for seasoning: A simple trick to elevate the flavor of your food—ask for salt and pepper packets to season your fries, burgers, or even chicken. It’s a small change that makes a big difference.</li>
  <li>Customize your burgers: Want to add a little extra flavor? Ask to swap ingredients—like replacing the cheese or adding more pickles or onions to your burger. It’s a quick and easy way to get your meal just the way you like it.</li>
  <li>Split a meal: If you’re not that hungry or want to save money, you can ask to split your meal into two smaller portions. Sometimes they’ll be happy to accommodate your request.</li>
  <li>Free water on request: While you’re paying for your meal, you don’t need to pay for water. Simply ask for a cup of water, and they’ll give it to you for free.</li>
  <li>Order breakfast all day: In Singapore, McDonald’s offers breakfast all day at selected outlets, so if you’re craving an Egg McMuffin, you can get it whenever the mood strikes.</li>
  <li>Discounts for students and seniors: If you’re a student or senior, don’t forget to ask about special discounts—some locations offer them, especially during certain times of the day or for specific menu items.</li>
</ul>

<p>Happy munching!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Singapore" /><category term="food" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ah, McDonald’s in Singapore—where every meal feels like a new opportunity to indulge in the latest food fads, whether it’s their McDonald’s latest March menu or a collaboration with Pokémon.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/mcpk.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/mcpk.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Singapore and International (UK/US/China) Passport Renewal and Photo Guide</title><link href="/singapore-passport-renewal-photos/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Singapore and International (UK/US/China) Passport Renewal and Photo Guide" /><published>2025-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-passport-renewal-photos</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-passport-renewal-photos/"><![CDATA[<p>Renewing your passport is one of those thrilling administrative tasks that everyone just loves to do.</p>

<p>If you’re in Singapore, you’ll need to follow ICA passport photo guidelines carefully—because nothing’s worse than having your Singapore passport photo size rejected after waiting in line. But before you rush to the nearest passport photo services Singapore shop, you might wonder: Do you really need to go to a store, or can you take a digital passport photo Singapore from the comfort of your own home? This guide covers everything you need to know about passport renewal photo Singapore options, from official requirements to the best apps that make the process less painful. All step by step around passport renewal for common countries also included.</p>

<h3 id="how-often-should-you-renew-your-singapore-passport-or-international-passport">How often should you renew your Singapore passport or international passport?</h3>

<p>For Singapore citizens, a Singapore passport is typically valid for 10 years if issued when you’re 16 or older. If you got it before turning 16, it’s only valid for 5 years. It’s best to renew your passport about 6 months before it expires, as some countries require at least 6 months’ validity for entry.</p>

<p>For international passports, renewal rules vary by country. Most passports are valid for 5 to 10 years, with many countries also requiring at least 6 months’ validity for travel. Always check your home country’s immigration website for exact renewal guidelines.</p>

<h3 id="where-can-you-take-passport-photos-in-singapore-for-all-nationalities">Where can you take passport photos in Singapore for all nationalities?</h3>

<p>In Singapore, you can take passport photos at various locations, whether you’re a Singapore citizen or holding an international passport. Here are some options:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Photo Studios &amp; Shops – Many professional passport photo services Singapore locations, such as those in shopping malls, neighborhood photo studios, and even some printing shops, offer passport photos that meet ICA and other international requirements.</li>
  <li>ICA Building – If you’re renewing a Singapore passport, you can take an official passport renewal photo Singapore at the ICA building, though it’s usually more convenient to have one ready before you go.</li>
  <li>MRT Station Booths – Some MRT stations have instant photo booths where you can take digital passport photo Singapore shots, but check if they meet the required dimensions and specifications.</li>
  <li>Mobile Apps &amp; Online Services – If you’re feeling tech-savvy, you can use online services or apps to take and format your own passport photo—just make sure it follows the ICA passport photo guidelines or your local country’s guidance. More on this later</li>
  <li>Convenience Stores &amp; Printing Shops – Some outlets like Fujifilm or Kodak stores offer passport photo printing services, perfect if you already have a digital copy and just need prints.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="do-you-really-need-to-go-to-a-photo-store-to-take-a-passport-photo">Do you really need to go to a photo store to take a passport photo?</h3>

<p>TL;DR: No, you don’t need to go to a photo store. Be smart and save a couple of bucks</p>

<h3 id="what-apps-can-you-use-to-take-singapore-passport-photos">What apps can you use to take Singapore passport photos?</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Singapore Passport Photo (iOS, Android) – Designed specifically for ICA requirements.</li>
  <li>證件照應用 – A simple-to-use app offering various size options, including the common two-inch and one-inch photos, as well as visa photo specifications for different countries.</li>
  <li>PersoPhoto – Online tool that adjusts your photo to official passport dimensions.</li>
  <li>Passport Photo ID Maker Studio – Lets you take, edit, and print passport photos.</li>
  <li>Biometric Passport Photo – Ensures your photo meets biometric standards.</li>
  <li>履歴書カメラ – A Japanese app with a simple interface that guides you to align your face correctly, offers skin tone and style adjustments, and allows for blemish removal.</li>
  <li>身份證照片和護照照片 – 人像裁剪 – This app provides multiple common sizes and visa specifications for different countries, allowing you to crop photos accordingly. ​</li>
  <li>Passport Photo ID Maker Studio – An app that allows you to take, edit, and print passport photos, ensuring they meet the required specifications.</li>
</ul>

<p>In fact, these apps can work for other countries like UK passport photos or US passport photos.</p>

<h3 id="what-apps-are-dedicated-for-singapore-ic-renewal">What apps are dedicated for Singapore IC renewal?</h3>

<p>For Singapore IC renewal, here are the top 3 apps you can use:</p>

<ul>
  <li>MyICA Mobile – The official ICA app allows you to renew your NRIC, apply for passports, and handle other immigration matters conveniently.</li>
  <li>Singpass Mobile – While not directly for IC renewal, this app is essential for logging into ICA services securely to submit your renewal application.</li>
  <li>IC Photo Apps (e.g., Passport Photo ID Maker Studio) – While not for renewal itself, apps like these help ensure your IC photo meets ICA’s strict requirements before submission.</li>
</ul>

<p>I’ve found these to work really well!</p>

<h3 id="should-you-edit-your-photo-after-using-one-of-the-passport-photo-id-apps">Should you edit your photo after using one of the passport photo ID apps?</h3>

<p>Ideally, no—but always check the final result.</p>

<p>Most passport photo services Singapore apps are designed to follow ICA passport photo guidelines, so heavy editing isn’t necessary. However, you should always review the output to ensure the background is evenly white, the lighting is correct (no shadows), and your facial expression meets the strict “neutral” requirement. If the app over-smooths your face or alters features unnaturally, you might need to retake the photo rather than risk rejection. Because let’s be honest—ICA isn’t going to accept a filtered, airbrushed, magazine-cover version of you.</p>

<h3 id="where-is-the-singapore-ica">Where is the Singapore ICA?</h3>

<p>The Immigration &amp; Checkpoints Authority (ICA) of Singapore is located at:</p>

<p>📍 ICA Building
 10 Kallang Road, Singapore 208718
 (Next to Lavender MRT, Exit B)</p>

<p>This is the place where you handle passport renewal Singapore, NRIC matters, and other immigration-related services. Pro tip: If you have an appointment, arrive on time—but if you’re doing a walk-in, be prepared to wait (or better yet, just do everything online via MyICA).</p>

<h3 id="what-is-the-process-of-renewing-your-singapore-passport">What is the process of renewing your Singapore passport?</h3>

<ol>
  <li>Apply Online – Submit your application via MyICA or the MyICA mobile app.</li>
  <li>Upload a Passport Photo – Ensure it meets ICA passport photo guidelines (neutral expression, white background, no filters).</li>
  <li>Pay the Fee – $70 for online applications.</li>
  <li>Wait for Approval – Processing takes about 1 week (longer if ICA needs more info).</li>
  <li>Collect Your Passport – Once approved, book an appointment and pick it up at ICA Building or selected post offices.</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="what-is-the-process-of-renewing-your-uk-passport-in-singapore">What is the process of renewing your UK passport in Singapore?</h3>

<ol>
  <li>Apply Online – Go to the UK Government website and complete the renewal form.</li>
  <li>Upload a Digital Passport Photo – Follow UK passport photo guidelines (similar to Singapore passport photo ICA guidelines but with UK-specific dimensions).</li>
  <li>Pay the Fee – £88.50 (online) or £100 (paper form).</li>
  <li>Send Your Old Passport – Mail your current passport to the UK processing center (you’ll get instructions on where to send it).</li>
  <li>Wait for Processing – Takes about 10 weeks (or longer if additional checks are needed).</li>
  <li>Receive Your New Passport – It’ll be mailed to your Singapore address.</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="what-is-the-process-of-renewing-your-china-passport-in-singapore">What is the process of renewing your China passport in Singapore?</h3>

<ol>
  <li>Prepare Documents – You’ll need:</li>
</ol>

<ul>
  <li>Your current passport.</li>
  <li>A completed passport renewal form (available at the Chinese Embassy’s website).</li>
  <li>A passport photo that meets China’s requirements (similar to ICA’s but with specific size and background).</li>
  <li>Proof of citizenship (if applicable).</li>
  <li>Book an Appointment – You must make an appointment at the Chinese Embassy or Consulate-General in Singapore (appointments can be made online).</li>
</ul>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Submit Your Application – Visit the embassy/consulate in person on your appointment day. Bring your documents, application form, and payment.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Pay the Fee – The fee is approximately S$100–S$120 depending on the processing time.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Wait for Processing – Typically takes about 4–6 weeks for standard processing.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Collect Your New Passport – Once ready, you’ll be notified to collect your new passport at the embassy or consulate.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<h3 id="what-is-the-process-of-renewing-your-us-passport-in-singapore">What is the process of renewing your US passport in Singapore?</h3>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Check Eligibility – Ensure your passport is eligible for renewal (it must be undamaged, issued within the last 15 years, and still in your name).</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Complete the DS-82 Form – Fill out the DS-82 form online and print it.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Prepare Documents – You’ll need:</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<ul>
  <li>Your current passport.</li>
  <li>A passport photo that meets US requirements.</li>
  <li>Payment for the renewal fee (approximately USD $130 for adult passports).</li>
  <li>Book an Appointment – While many renewals can be done by mail, if you’re renewing by mail from Singapore, you will need to send your documents to the U.S. Embassy in Singapore. Alternatively, you can request an in-person appointment for expedited services.</li>
</ul>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Submit Your Application – Submit your completed DS-82 form, payment, passport photo, and supporting documents.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Wait for Processing – Standard processing takes about 10–12 weeks, or you can request expedited processing (for an additional fee) which takes around 5–7 weeks.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Collect Your New Passport – The embassy will send your new passport by mail, and you can track the status through their service.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<h3 id="what-is-the-process-of-renewing-your-indonesian-passport-in-singapore">What is the process of renewing your Indonesian passport in Singapore?</h3>

<ol>
  <li>Prepare Documents – You’ll need:</li>
</ol>

<ul>
  <li>Your current passport.</li>
  <li>A completed passport renewal form (available on the Indonesian Embassy website).</li>
  <li>A passport photo that meets Indonesian requirements.</li>
  <li>Proof of residence (if applicable).</li>
</ul>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Book an Appointment – Schedule an appointment at the Indonesian Embassy in Singapore (appointments can be made online).</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Submit Your Application – Visit the embassy on your appointment date with the required documents.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Pay the Fee – The fee is around S$50–S$80, depending on the processing time.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Wait for Processing – Standard processing takes about 4–6 weeks.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Collect Your New Passport – You’ll be notified when your passport is ready for pick-up at the embassy.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<h3 id="how-long-does-it-take-to-process-your-passport">How long does it take to process your passport?</h3>

<p>In general, passport processing times vary by country and application type:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Singapore: Typically 1 week for online renewals.</li>
  <li>UK: 10 weeks for standard processing.</li>
  <li>China: About 4–6 weeks.</li>
  <li>US: 10–12 weeks (expedited: 5–7 weeks).</li>
  <li>Indonesia: Usually 4–6 weeks.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="where-are-the-foreign-embassies-located-in-singapore">Where are the foreign embassies located in Singapore?</h3>

<p>Foreign embassies in Singapore are primarily located in the following areas:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Orchard Road / Tanglin – This area is home to many embassies, including those of the US, UK, Canada, Australia, and Indonesia.</li>
  <li>Newton – The Indonesian Embassy and some other embassies can be found here.</li>
  <li>Shenton Way / Raffles Place – Some diplomatic missions and consulates, including the Russian Federation, are based in this central business district.</li>
</ul>

<p>Embassy locations in Singapore are generally spread out, but many are clustered in these central areas. If you’re planning a visit, it’s always best to check online for the specific address and appointment requirements.</p>

<p>We’ll cover visas another time. For PRs, remember to bring your re-entry permit (REP) when you travel abroad. Happy vacation!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Singapore" /><category term="society" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Renewing your passport is one of those thrilling administrative tasks that everyone just loves to do.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/passport.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/passport.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ultimate Guide to Food Delivery in Singapore: Best Apps, Deals &amp;amp; Hacks</title><link href="/singapore-food-delivery/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ultimate Guide to Food Delivery in Singapore: Best Apps, Deals &amp;amp; Hacks" /><published>2025-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-food-delivery</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-food-delivery/"><![CDATA[<p>Food delivery in Singapore has become a way of life—because why brave the humidity when food delivery Singapore exists?</p>

<p>With an overwhelming number of options, from online food delivery Singapore platforms like GrabFood and Foodpanda to niche services specializing in Chinese food delivery Singapore, there’s something for every craving. Of course, convenience comes at a cost—hidden fees, inflated menu prices, and service charges that make you wonder if you accidentally ordered caviar. But don’t worry, there are always hacks to make the best food delivery in Singapore a little more wallet-friendly (or at least less painful).</p>

<h3 id="what-food-delivery-apps-and-services-are-there-in-singapore">What food delivery apps and services are there in Singapore?</h3>

<ul>
  <li>GrabFood – The biggest player, offering everything from fast food to fancy restaurants.</li>
  <li>Foodpanda – Known for frequent promo codes and pink delivery bags.</li>
  <li>Deliveroo – Focuses on higher-end restaurants and faster delivery.</li>
  <li>Oddle Eats – Connects you directly with restaurants for islandwide delivery.</li>
</ul>

<p>If you’re craving something quick, don’t forget about fast food-specific apps like McDelivery and KFC Delivery, which make sure your burgers and fried chicken come right to your door without the need to lift a finger.</p>

<h3 id="what-additional-fees-do-food-delivery-apps-have">What additional fees do food delivery apps have?</h3>

<p>Food delivery apps in Singapore can charge various additional fees on top of the menu price. Here’s a breakdown of the common ones:</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Delivery Fees
This is the most common extra charge, varying based on factors like distance, restaurant choice, and demand. Typically ranges from $1.50 to $6, but can spike during peak hours or surge pricing periods.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Service Fees
Most apps charge a service fee, which can be $0.99 to $2. It covers operational costs like maintaining the app and processing payments.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Booking Fees
Apps like Oddle Eats may add a small booking fee, usually around $1 to $2, especially for special orders or reservations for larger groups.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Packaging Fees
Some apps (especially for premium restaurants or meal kits) charge a packaging fee to cover the cost of containers and other packaging materials, usually around $0.50 to $2.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Surge Pricing
During peak times (like weekends or lunch/dinner hours), some platforms apply surge pricing to the delivery fee. This can increase the total delivery cost by 20-30%.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Tip/Gratuity
While optional, some platforms allow you to add a tip for the delivery rider, typically ranging from $1 to $5, depending on your generosity (or guilt).</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Subscription Fees
Apps like Deliveroo Plus and GrabFood’s subscription plans offer benefits like free delivery and exclusive deals for an annual or monthly fee, usually $10 to $15 per month.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<h3 id="comparing-singapore-delivery-app-prices">Comparing Singapore delivery app prices</h3>

<ol>
  <li>GrabFood</li>
</ol>

<ul>
  <li>Fees: Delivery fees can vary from $1.50 to $4.50, with additional service charges.</li>
  <li>Restaurant Options: Wide variety, from fast food to premium restaurants, including local eateries and cloud kitchens.</li>
  <li>Easy to Use: User-friendly interface with smooth navigation and checkout.</li>
  <li>Promos/Discounts: Frequent promo codes, discounts for GrabRewards members, and cashback with GrabPay.</li>
</ul>

<p>Verdict: Moderately priced, though costs can creep up during peak times or with larger orders.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Foodpanda</li>
</ol>

<ul>
  <li>Fees: Delivery fees range from $2 to $6, depending on the restaurant and location. Surge pricing can apply.</li>
  <li>Restaurant Options: Extensive options covering fast food, local favorites, international chains, and niche eateries.</li>
  <li>Easy to Use: Simple to use, though order tracking can be inconsistent at times.</li>
  <li>Promos/Discounts: Offers discounts, free delivery promotions, and exclusive deals for PandaPerks members.</li>
</ul>

<p>Verdict: Moderately expensive, with delivery fees that can be higher compared to others, especially during surge times.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Deliveroo</li>
</ol>

<ul>
  <li>Fees: Delivery charges typically range from $2 to $4, with higher fees during peak demand.</li>
  <li>Restaurant Options: Premium restaurants, gourmet dining, and fast food options.</li>
  <li>Easy to Use: Clean and easy-to-navigate interface, with precise order tracking.</li>
  <li>Promos/Discounts: Regular discounts and exclusive offers for Deliveroo Plus members.</li>
</ul>

<p>Verdict: More expensive than GrabFood and Foodpanda, especially for premium restaurant deliveries.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Oddle Eats</li>
</ol>

<ul>
  <li>Fees: Delivery fees are generally reasonable but vary depending on the restaurant. Some restaurants may charge additional service fees.</li>
  <li>Restaurant Options: Focuses on local, independent restaurants, with fewer options compared to the larger platforms.</li>
  <li>Easy to Use: Straightforward app, though it’s not as polished as the bigger services.</li>
  <li>Promos/Discounts: Fewer platform-wide discounts, but restaurant-specific promos are available.</li>
</ul>

<p>Verdict: Least expensive, particularly for local and independent restaurants with more consistent fees.</p>

<p><u>Final Verdict<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>Most Expensive: Deliveroo, particularly if you opt for premium restaurant deliveries.</li>
  <li>Moderately Expensive: Foodpanda and GrabFood can get pricey during peak times, especially when factoring in delivery and service fees.</li>
  <li>Least Expensive: Oddle Eats, thanks to more consistent and reasonable delivery fees, especially for local restaurant orders.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="how-much-extra-are-food-delivery-apps-versus-usual-restaurant-prices">How much extra are food delivery apps versus usual restaurant prices?</h3>

<p>Food delivery apps in Singapore typically charge more than usual restaurant prices, thanks to additional fees and commissions. Here’s a breakdown of the extra costs you might face:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Delivery Fees</li>
</ol>

<p>These can range from $1.50 to $6, depending on distance, time, and surge pricing. This is an obvious markup on the usual in-store dining experience, where there are no delivery charges.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Service Fees</li>
</ol>

<p>Service fees can range from $0.99 to $2, which are applied on top of the order total. Restaurants don’t usually charge these when you dine in.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Menu Price Markup</li>
</ol>

<p>Some restaurants increase their menu prices for deliveries. This can be around 5% to 20% higher than in-store prices to cover the platform’s commission and other operational costs. While some restaurants keep their prices the same, it’s common to see higher prices for delivery.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Packaging Fees</li>
</ol>

<p>For takeaway or delivery, some restaurants add a packaging fee (usually $0.50 to $2) to cover the cost of containers and cutlery. This isn’t something you’d pay if you dine in.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Subscription Fees</li>
</ol>

<p>If you subscribe to premium delivery services like Deliveroo Plus or GrabFood’s subscription, you might pay $10 to $15 per month. While this can save you on delivery fees, it still adds to the overall cost.</p>

<h3 id="what-hacks-are-there-for-cheaper-food-delivery">What hacks are there for cheaper food delivery?</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Call the Restaurant Directly: Some restaurants offer cheaper or direct delivery services, avoiding high app fees.</li>
  <li>Use Promo Codes: Keep an eye on app promotions or sign up for newsletters to get discount codes.</li>
  <li>Join Loyalty Programs: Programs like GrabRewards or PandaPerks offer discounts or free delivery for frequent users.</li>
  <li>Order in Bulk: Group orders often come with discounts or waived delivery fees.</li>
  <li>Sign Up for Subscriptions: Plans like Deliveroo Plus or GrabFood’s subscription offer free delivery and perks.</li>
  <li>Avoid Peak Hours: Order during off-peak times to avoid surge pricing.</li>
  <li>Compare Apps: Different platforms may offer better prices or lower fees for the same restaurant.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="should-you-get-a-food-delivery-app-subscription">Should you get a food delivery app subscription?</h3>

<p>Whether or not you should get a food delivery app subscription depends on how often you order delivery. Here’s a quick breakdown:</p>

<p>Yes, Get a Subscription If:</p>

<ul>
  <li>You order frequently (e.g., a few times a week). Subscriptions like GrabFood Plus or Deliveroo Plus offer free delivery and exclusive discounts, which can quickly offset the monthly fee.</li>
  <li>You want to avoid fluctuating delivery charges, especially during peak hours when prices can surge.</li>
  <li>You want additional perks like loyalty rewards, cashback, or access to exclusive deals.</li>
</ul>

<p>No, Don’t Get a Subscription If:</p>

<ul>
  <li>You order delivery only occasionally. In this case, the subscription fee may not be worth it, as you can simply rely on promotions or one-off discounts.</li>
  <li>You prefer variety and like to switch between different apps. Subscriptions are usually tied to one platform, and you may miss out on better deals elsewhere.</li>
</ul>

<p>Let’s break down the math for GrabFood Plus to help you decide if it’s worth it.</p>

<p><u>GrabFood Plus Subscription<u></u></u></p>

<p>Cost: $12.98 per month (before GST).</p>

<p>Benefits:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Free delivery on all orders (minimum order may apply).</li>
  <li>Exclusive deals and discounts for members.</li>
  <li>Priority customer support.</li>
</ul>

<p>Without GrabFood Plus:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Average Delivery Fee: $2.50 to $4.50 per order (could vary depending on time and distance).</li>
  <li>Average Meal Cost: Let’s assume each order costs around $15 (this could be higher for premium restaurants).</li>
</ul>

<p>Scenario 1: Ordering Once a Week (4 times a month)</p>

<p>Without Subscription:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Delivery Fee: $3 per order x 4 orders = $12</li>
  <li>Total for the Month (without subscription): $15 x 4 (meal cost) + $12 (delivery fees) = $72</li>
</ul>

<p>With Subscription:</p>
<ul>
  <li>GrabFood Plus Subscription: $12.98 per month (plus GST, let’s say around $13.90)</li>
  <li>Total for the Month (with subscription): $13.90 (subscription) + $60 (meal cost, $15 x 4) = $73.90</li>
</ul>

<p>Verdict: In this scenario, a subscription doesn’t save you money if you’re only ordering 4 times a month. You’d actually spend a little more with the subscription ($73.90 vs. $72).</p>

<p>Do the maths!</p>

<h3 id="should-you-tip-for-food-delivery-in-singapore">Should you tip for food delivery in Singapore?</h3>

<p>I tip if it rains. Else wise, tipping culture is not big in Singapore.</p>

<p>I’m lazy but most times I can’t stomach paying a platform fee to have my food delivered. It’s even more egregious in the US. Good thing we’re in Singapore</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Singapore" /><category term="food" /><category term="restaurants" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Food delivery in Singapore has become a way of life—because why brave the humidity when food delivery Singapore exists?]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/deliver.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/deliver.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Singapore Monsoon Weather: Why is it raining and what can you do in a monsoon</title><link href="/singapore-monsoon-weather/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Singapore Monsoon Weather: Why is it raining and what can you do in a monsoon" /><published>2025-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-monsoon-weather</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-monsoon-weather/"><![CDATA[<p>Singapore’s monsoon season isn’t just a weather phenomenon—it’s practically a national pastime.</p>

<p>We love talking about the weather. If you enjoy stepping out into clear skies only to be drenched five minutes later, monsoon season in Singapore has got you covered. With the Northeast monsoon bringing months of relentless rain, occasional floods, and that ever-familiar damp sock experience, it’s no wonder people constantly search for the Singapore monsoon forecast or wonder when does it rain in Singapore (hint: all the time). But before you break out the ark, let’s take a look at why the rainy season in Singapore is so persistent, how it impacts daily life, and whether checking the weather in Singapore today actually helps. Spoiler alert: it doesn’t.</p>

<h3 id="why-is-it-raining-so-much-in-singapore-in-march">Why is it raining so much in Singapore in March?</h3>

<p>If you’re wondering why it’s raining so much in Singapore in March, you’re not alone. March sits at the tail end of the Northeast Monsoon season, which usually lasts from December to early March. During this period, lingering monsoon surges can still bring heavy rain and thunderstorms. Additionally, March marks the transition to the Inter-monsoon season, where warm temperatures and high humidity lead to frequent afternoon showers and even sudden thunderstorms. Combine that with climate change and the usual unpredictability of tropical weather, and you’ve got the perfect recipe for feeling like you live inside a rain cloud. So, if you were hoping for dry, sunny days—well, maybe check back in June.</p>

<h3 id="how-long-will-this-monsoon-rain-last-for">How long will this monsoon rain last for?</h3>

<p>Singapore’s monsoon rain should last about one to two more weeks, with the Northeast Monsoon season ending by mid-March. But don’t ditch the umbrella yet—Inter-monsoon season kicks in right after, bringing unpredictable downpours.</p>

<h3 id="how-do-you-check-the-weather-in-singapore">How do you check the weather in Singapore?</h3>

<p>You can check the weather in Singapore through these sources:</p>
<ul>
  <li>NEA (National Environment Agency) Website – Official weather updates and forecasts.</li>
  <li>myENV App – NEA’s mobile app for real-time weather alerts.</li>
  <li>Weather.gov.sg – Detailed forecasts, rainfall radar, and lightning alerts.</li>
  <li>Google Weather – Quick and easy weather updates via Google search.</li>
  <li>The Weather Channel / AccuWeather – Global weather apps with Singapore-specific forecasts.</li>
  <li>SG Weather Bots on Telegram – Automated alerts for rain and storms.</li>
  <li>Local News Websites (CNA, Straits Times, Today Online) – Weather reports and advisories.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="how-do-you-stay-dry-in-the-monsoon-season">How do you stay dry in the monsoon season?</h3>

<p>To stay dry during the monsoon season in Singapore, try these:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Shut your windows – Unless you enjoy unexpected indoor puddles.</li>
  <li>Carry an umbrella – A compact one for convenience, a sturdy one for stormy days.</li>
  <li>Wear a waterproof parka or raincoat – Keeps you dry without battling a flimsy umbrella in strong winds.</li>
  <li>Use waterproof shoes or sandals – Because wet socks are the worst.</li>
  <li>Plan your route – Stick to sheltered walkways and MRT underpasses.</li>
  <li>Check the weather forecast – Apps like myENV help you dodge the worst downpours.</li>
  <li>Keep an extra set of clothes – Just in case the rain wins.</li>
  <li>Use a plastic bag rain shield – If you forgot your umbrella, a plastic bag over your head is a (questionable but effective) + backup plan.</li>
  <li>Employ the “human shield” method – Walk behind someone with a huge umbrella (bonus points if they don’t notice).</li>
  <li>Turn rainy days into Grab days – Just surrender to the weather and take a ride—your shoes will thank you.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="what-to-do-indoors-at-home-in-the-monsoon-season-if-you-live-alone">What to do indoors at home in the monsoon season if you live alone?</h3>

<p>When it’s monsoon season and you’re stuck indoors alone, here are some things to do:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Binge-watch your favorite shows or movies – Rainy days are perfect for that Netflix marathon.</li>
  <li>Get cozy with a book – Escape into a good novel, or catch up on that reading you’ve been putting off.</li>
  <li>Try cooking or baking – Experiment with new recipes and enjoy some homemade comfort food.</li>
  <li>Organize and declutter – Tackle that drawer or closet you’ve been avoiding; monsoon days are great for getting things in order.</li>
  <li>Learn a new skill – Whether it’s a language, a craft, or a new hobby, use the time indoors to grow.</li>
  <li>Have a self-care day – Pamper yourself with a long bath, face masks, and all things relaxing.</li>
  <li>Start an indoor garden – Pot some plants or herbs and bring a bit of greenery into your home.</li>
  <li>Play video games or board games – Challenge yourself or dive into an immersive world.</li>
  <li>Do a home workout – Get your body moving with an indoor workout or yoga session.</li>
  <li>Listen to podcasts or music – Create the perfect rainy-day playlist or catch up on interesting podcasts.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="what-to-do-indoors-at-home-in-the-monsoon-season-if-you-live-with-someone-or-your-family">What to do indoors at home in the monsoon season if you live with someone or your family?</h3>

<p>When it’s monsoon season and you’re indoors with someone or your family, here are some fun and cozy ideas:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Movie or TV show marathon – Set up a cozy movie night with popcorn and binge-watch your favorite shows together.</li>
  <li>Cook a big meal or bake treats – Get everyone involved in the kitchen to try new recipes or bake some rainy-day snacks.</li>
  <li>Play board games or card games – Bring out the competitive spirit with some classic games or fun card games.</li>
  <li>Have an indoor picnic – Set up a picnic on the living room floor with blankets, snacks, and drinks to make it feel special.</li>
  <li>Do a DIY craft project – Get creative with arts and crafts, whether it’s painting, building something, or making homemade decorations.</li>
  <li>Read books aloud – Pick a book to read as a family, and take turns reading chapters or pages.</li>
  <li>Do a family workout – Try a fun group workout, like yoga or a dance challenge, to stay active indoors.</li>
  <li>Build an indoor fort – Use blankets, pillows, and furniture to create a cozy fort, perfect for lounging or telling stories.</li>
  <li>Play video games together – Dive into multiplayer games or family-friendly video games for some interactive fun.</li>
  <li>Have a photo shoot – Take silly or themed photos, and use the rainy day as an excuse to capture some memories.</li>
</ul>

<p>Video games are the best. Stay dry during the monsoon weather.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Singapore" /><category term="weather" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Singapore’s monsoon season isn’t just a weather phenomenon—it’s practically a national pastime.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/monsoon.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/monsoon.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Singapore Grand Prix 2025: Tickets, Schedule, G-Dragon &amp;amp; F1 Weekend Guide</title><link href="/singapore-f1-racing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Singapore Grand Prix 2025: Tickets, Schedule, G-Dragon &amp;amp; F1 Weekend Guide" /><published>2025-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-f1-racing</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-f1-racing/"><![CDATA[<p>The Singapore Grand Prix 2025 isn’t just about fast cars and loud engines — it’s a whole experience packed with drama, dollars, and the occasional dose of confusion.</p>

<p>Whether you’re hunting for F1 Singapore tickets, curious about the Singapore GP schedule, or wondering what exactly happens at the Marina Bay Street Circuit, there’s plenty to know. Add in some iconic teams battling for glory, overpriced hotels, and a headliner concert that may or may not be worth the hype — and you’ve got yourself quite the weekend. Don’t forget the post-race excitement when fans eagerly check the Singapore Grand Prix results or relive the action with an F1 Singapore live stream. And if you’re after tips for scoring those pricey F1 Singapore qualifying tickets without maxing out your credit card — I’ve got you covered.</p>

<h3 id="what-is-f1">What is F1?</h3>

<p>Formula 1 (F1) is the pinnacle of motorsport — a high-speed, high-stakes competition where the world’s best drivers push multi-million-dollar cars to their absolute limit. Think of it as the Olympics of racing, but with way more tire changes and fewer gold medals. Each season features a series of races, known as Grands Prix, held on circuits across the globe. The teams? They’re engineering powerhouses like Mercedes, Red Bull, and Ferrari, constantly battling for bragging rights and championship points. In short, F1 is fast, flashy, and fiercely competitive — perfect for those who love speed or just want an excuse to sip champagne trackside.</p>

<h3 id="how-does-the-f1-circuit-work">How does the F1 circuit work?</h3>

<p>The F1 circuit isn’t just about drivers flooring it and hoping for the best — there’s a method to the madness. Each season has a set number of Grands Prix races held in different countries, forming the F1 calendar. Drivers and teams earn points based on their race positions, with the ultimate goal of winning either the Drivers’ Championship (for the fastest human) or the Constructors’ Championship (for the team that nailed both speed and strategy). Races are held on a mix of purpose-built tracks and challenging street circuits — like Singapore’s iconic Marina Bay Street Circuit. Oh, and there’s qualifying too — a three-part session where drivers fight for the best starting position, because nobody wants to start the race staring at everyone else’s exhaust.</p>

<h3 id="what-are-the-f1-race-tracks-globally">What are the F1 race tracks globally?</h3>

<p>F1 race tracks span the globe, from iconic circuits with decades of history to modern marvels designed for pure speed. You’ve got legendary tracks like Monza in Italy, known as the “Temple of Speed,” and the twisty streets of Monaco, where millionaires park their yachts just to watch cars squeeze through hairpin turns. Over in Japan, Suzuka keeps drivers on their toes with its infamous figure-eight layout, while Silverstone in the UK is the birthplace of F1 itself. And let’s not forget Singapore’s very own Marina Bay Street Circuit, where drivers race under dazzling lights in one of the most intense night races on the calendar. Whether it’s speed, strategy, or scenery, F1 tracks have a bit of everything—and a whole lot of tire smoke.</p>

<p>Here’s a list of the current circuits featured in the 2025 Formula One season:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Albert Park Circuit, Melbourne, Australia</li>
  <li>Shanghai International Circuit, Shanghai, China</li>
  <li>uzuka International Racing Course, Suzuka, Japan</li>
  <li>Bahrain International Circuit, Sakhir, Bahrain</li>
  <li>Jeddah Corniche Circuit, Jeddah, Saudi Arabia</li>
  <li>Miami International Autodrome, Miami, USA</li>
  <li>Imola Circuit, Imola, Italy</li>
  <li>Circuit de Monaco, Monaco</li>
  <li>Circuit de Barcelona-Catalunya, Montmeló, Spain</li>
  <li>Circuit Gilles Villeneuve, Montreal, Canada</li>
  <li>Red Bull Ring, Spielberg, Austria</li>
  <li>Silverstone Circuit, Silverstone, UK</li>
  <li>Circuit de Spa-Francorchamps, Stavelot, Belgium</li>
  <li>Hungaroring, Mogyoród, Hungary</li>
  <li>Circuit Zandvoort, Zandvoort, Netherlands</li>
  <li>Monza Circuit, Monza, Italy</li>
  <li>Baku City Circuit, Baku, Azerbaijan</li>
  <li>Marina Bay Street Circuit, Singapore</li>
  <li>Circuit of the Americas, Austin, USA</li>
  <li>Autódromo Hermanos Rodríguez, Mexico City, Mexico</li>
  <li>Interlagos Circuit, São Paulo, Brazil</li>
  <li>Las Vegas Strip Circuit, Paradise, USA</li>
  <li>Lusail International Circuit, Lusail, Qatar</li>
  <li>Yas Marina Circuit, Abu Dhabi, UAE</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="what-are-the-top-f1-teams-and-their-drivers">What are the top F1 teams and their drivers?</h3>

<p>The 2025 Formula 1 season has brought a fresh wave of excitement with significant team and driver changes. Here’s a rundown of the top teams and their current driver line-ups:</p>

<p><u>McLaren Formula 1 Team<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>Lando Norris (Car No. 4)</li>
  <li>Oscar Piastri (Car No. 81)</li>
</ul>

<p>McLaren has retained its dynamic duo, aiming to build on their previous successes.</p>

<p><u>Scuderia Ferrari HP<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>Charles Leclerc (Car No. 16)</li>
  <li>Lewis Hamilton (Car No. 44)</li>
</ul>

<p>In a headline-grabbing move, seven-time world champion Lewis Hamilton has joined Ferrari, partnering with Charles Leclerc.</p>

<p><u>Oracle Red Bull Racing<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>Max Verstappen (Car No. 1)</li>
  <li>Liam Lawson (Car No. 30)</li>
</ul>

<p>Red Bull introduces rookie Liam Lawson alongside reigning champion Max Verstappen.</p>

<p><u>Mercedes-AMG PETRONAS Formula One Team<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>George Russell (Car No. 63)</li>
  <li>Andrea Kimi Antonelli (Car No. 12)</li>
</ul>

<p>Mercedes bets on youth by bringing in rookie Andrea Kimi Antonelli to race alongside George Russell.</p>

<p><u>Aston Martin Aramco Formula One Team<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>Fernando Alonso (Car No. 14)</li>
  <li>Lance Stroll (Car No. 18)</li>
</ul>

<p>Aston Martin maintains its experienced line-up with Alonso and Stroll.</p>

<p><u>BWT Alpine Formula 1 Team<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>Pierre Gasly (Car No. 10)</li>
  <li>Jack Doohan (Car No. 7)</li>
</ul>

<p>Alpine brings in rookie Jack Doohan to partner with the seasoned Pierre Gasly.</p>

<p><u>MoneyGram Haas F1 Team<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>Esteban Ocon (Car No. 31)</li>
  <li>Oliver Bearman (Car No. 87)</li>
</ul>

<p>Haas revamps its roster with Ocon and rookie Oliver Bearman.</p>

<p><u>Visa Cash App Racing Bulls Formula One Team<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>Isack Hadjar (Car No. 6)</li>
  <li>Yuki Tsunoda (Car No. 22)</li>
</ul>

<p>Racing Bulls introduces rookie Isack Hadjar alongside Yuki Tsunoda</p>

<p><u>Atlassian Williams Racing<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>Alexander Albon (Car No. 23)</li>
  <li>Carlos Sainz Jr. (Car No. 55)</li>
</ul>

<p>Williams secures the talents of Carlos Sainz Jr., partnering him with Alexander Albon.</p>

<p><u>Stake F1 Team Kick Sauber<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>Nico Hülkenberg (Car No. 27)</li>
  <li>Gabriel Bortoleto (Car No. 5)</li>
</ul>

<p>Sauber brings in veteran Nico Hülkenberg and rookie Gabriel Bortoleto.</p>

<p>These line-ups reflect a blend of experience and fresh talent, setting the stage for a thrilling 2025 season.</p>

<h3 id="what-is-special-and-difficult-about-the-f1-singapore-race-track">What is special and difficult about the F1 Singapore race track?</h3>

<p>The F1 Singapore race track, better known as the Marina Bay Street Circuit, is no ordinary loop of tarmac — it’s a brutal test of endurance disguised as a dazzling night race. With 23 tight corners, limited overtaking spots, and unforgiving walls just centimeters from the racing line, there’s little room for error. The sweltering Singapore humidity makes things even tougher, pushing drivers to their physical limits — some have reported losing up to 3 kg of body weight in sweat during the race. Add in the race’s tendency to run close to the two-hour limit, and it’s no surprise that Singapore is considered one of the most mentally and physically demanding races on the calendar. Survive this one, and you’ve definitely earned that post-race champagne.</p>

<h3 id="what-other-festivities-are-there-besides-the-race-itself-in-singapore">What other festivities are there besides the race itself in singapore?</h3>

<p>Beyond the race itself, the Singapore Grand Prix weekend is packed with festivities. Expect concerts featuring global headliners, vibrant trackside parties, and exclusive F1-themed events across the city. Popular nightlife spots like Clarke Quay and Marina Bay Sands often host special F1 parties, while luxury brands and bars roll out VIP experiences. For something more relaxed, you’ll also find pop-up food festivals and immersive motorsport exhibits throughout the city.</p>

<h3 id="who-is-headlining-the-f1-singapore-concert">Who is headlining the F1 Singapore concert?</h3>

<p>The 2025 Singapore Grand Prix is set to feature stellar performances from international music icons. South Korean superstar G-Dragon will kick off the festivities on Friday, October 3, at the Padang Stage in Zone 4. Renowned British musician Elton John will close the weekend with a performance on Sunday, October 5, at the same venue</p>

<h3 id="what-are-the-zones-in-f1-singapore">What are the zones in F1 Singapore?</h3>

<p>The F1 Singapore Grand Prix is divided into several zones, each offering different views, experiences, and amenities. Here’s a quick breakdown:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Zone 1: Closest to the Pit Building, featuring the Starting Grid, Paddock Club, and exclusive hospitality suites.</li>
  <li>Zone 2: Offers prime views of technical corners and exciting overtaking spots.</li>
  <li>Zone 3: Known for its relaxed vibe, with several chill-out areas and food stalls.</li>
  <li>Zone 4: The liveliest zone, home to the Padang Stage, major concerts, and easy access to city landmarks like Esplanade and Raffles Avenue.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="what-type-of-f1-singapore-tickets-are-there-and-how-much-are-the-f1-singapore-tickets">What type of F1 Singapore tickets are there and how much are the F1 singapore tickets?</h3>

<p>Attending the Formula 1 Singapore Grand Prix offers a variety of ticket options to suit different preferences and budgets. 
Here’s a breakdown of the main ticket types and their approximate prices:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Grandstand Tickets: These provide reserved seating with clear views of specific track sections.</li>
</ol>

<p>Pit Grandstand: Located along the start/finish straight, offering views of the pit lane and team garages. Prices start at $1,548 SGD for a three-day pass.</p>

<p>Turn 1 and Turn 2 Grandstands: Positioned at the first and second corners, ideal for witnessing overtaking maneuvers. Three-day passes are priced at $1,548 SGD each.</p>

<p>Padang Grandstand: Situated in Zone 4, close to the Padang Stage where major concerts are held. Three-day tickets are available for $549 EUR (approximately $579 USD).</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Walkabout Tickets: These general admission tickets allow spectators to access various zones without reserved seating.
Zone 4 Walkabout: Grants access to Zone 4, including areas around the Padang Stage. Three-day tickets are priced at €123.78 (approximately $133 USD).</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Combination Packages: These offer varied experiences across different zones on different days.
Zone 1 Walkabout Combination: Provides access to Zone 1 on selected days and Zone 4 on others. Priced at $1,108 SGD.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Hospitality Packages: For a premium experience, hospitality suites offer luxury amenities, gourmet dining, and exclusive viewing areas.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>Sky Suite: A high-end option with panoramic views, priced at $7,028.54 USD for the three-day event.
Green Room: Offers a more affordable hospitality experience at $4,576.73 USD for three days.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Single-Day Tickets: For those unable to attend all three days, single-day tickets are available.
Pit Grandstand Friday: Access to the Pit Grandstand on Friday, priced at $328 SGD.</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="where-do-you-stay-in-singapore-during-f1">Where do you stay in Singapore during F1?</h3>

<p>If you’re visiting Singapore for the F1 Singapore Grand Prix, here are some top accommodation options, focusing on comfort and convenience:</p>

<p><u>Luxury Hotels (Closest to the Action)<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>The Ritz-Carlton, Millenia Singapore – Overlooks the track with stunning views.</li>
  <li>Mandarin Oriental Singapore – Prime location near Marina Bay.</li>
  <li>The Fullerton Hotel Singapore – Iconic spot along the race route.</li>
  <li>Pan Pacific Singapore – Close to key viewing points and entertainment zones.</li>
  <li>JW Marriott Singapore South Beach – Modern luxury near the race circuit.</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Mid-Range Hotels (Comfortable Yet Supposedly Affordable)<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>Parkroyal Collection Marina Bay – Stylish with great track proximity.</li>
  <li>M Hotel Singapore – Affordable option near the city centre.</li>
  <li>Hotel G Singapore – A chic boutique hotel with reasonable rates.</li>
  <li>For the best experience, book early — F1 weekend fills hotels faster than a Red Bull pit stop.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="how-expensive-are-hotels-for-f1-in-singapore">How expensive are hotels for F1 in Singapore?</h3>

<p>During the F1 Singapore Grand Prix, hotel prices surge like a Ferrari on a straight. Here’s a rough guide to what you can expect:</p>

<p><u>Luxury Hotels (Near the Track)<u></u></u></p>

<p>$1,200 – $2,500+ SGD per night (~$880 – $1,840 USD)
Examples: The Ritz-Carlton, Mandarin Oriental, The Fullerton Hotel</p>

<p><u>Mid-Range Hotels (Comfortable yet still pricy)<u></u></u></p>

<p>$400 – $800 SGD per night (~$295 – $590 USD)</p>

<p>Examples: Parkroyal Collection Marina Bay, M Hotel Singapore, Hotel G Singapore</p>

<p>Be ready to fork out an arm and a leg</p>

<h3 id="tips-to-buying-f1-singapore-tickets-for-cheap">Tips to buying F1 singapore tickets for cheap</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Buy Early – Early bird sales often offer the best prices, so book as soon as tickets are released.</li>
  <li>Look for Resale Deals – Closer to race day, some fans sell their passes at discounted prices if they can’t attend.</li>
  <li>Buy Someone’s Pass When They’re Leaving – Some attendees leave early and may sell their remaining pass at a bargain. Just be quick!</li>
  <li>Choose Walkabout Tickets – These are the most affordable options, giving you access to multiple zones without a reserved seat.</li>
  <li>Check Package Deals – Some travel agencies or hotels bundle tickets with accommodation for less than booking separately.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="where-can-you-watch-f1-for-free-in-singapore">Where can you watch F1 for free in Singapore?</h3>

<p><u>On TV (Best for Comfort)<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>Mediacorp Channel 5 – Often broadcasts the race live for free.</li>
  <li>MeWATCH – Free online streaming option for Singapore residents.</li>
  <li>F1’s Official Social Media – Sometimes shows highlights or key moments live.</li>
</ul>

<p><u>In-Person (Best for Atmosphere)<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>Esplanade Roof Terrace – Overlooks parts of the track with a decent view.</li>
  <li>Marina Square Mall – Some upper-floor restaurants may offer partial track views.</li>
  <li>Helix Bridge – Limited glimpses, but you’ll still catch the roar of engines.</li>
  <li>The Ritz-Carlton, Millenia Singapore – Certain rooms offer prime track views (if you know someone staying there).</li>
  <li>Mandarin Oriental Singapore – Some dining areas and rooms face the circuit.</li>
</ul>

<p>For the best chance at a solid view, arrive early — these spots fill up faster than a DRS-boosted overtake.</p>

<p>I’m heading to see Gdragon. What about you?</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Singapore" /><category term="entertainment" /><category term="sports" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Singapore Grand Prix 2025 isn’t just about fast cars and loud engines — it’s a whole experience packed with drama, dollars, and the occasional dose of confusion.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/f1.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/f1.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Best Cinemas in Singapore: IMAX, Indie Cinema, Ticket Guide</title><link href="/singapore-movies-cinema/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Best Cinemas in Singapore: IMAX, Indie Cinema, Ticket Guide" /><published>2025-03-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-movies-cinema</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-movies-cinema/"><![CDATA[<p>Cinemas in Singapore are more than just a place to catch the latest blockbuster — they’re practically a national pastime. They were at least.</p>

<p>Whether you’re hunting for the best IMAX experience, comparing cinema ticket prices, or hoping to stumble upon an elusive “cinema promotion,” there’s no shortage of options to explore. From plush recliners and gourmet popcorn to old-school theatres that still feel like a throwback to simpler times, Singapore’s movie scene has something for everyone — including those who just like to complain about ticket prices. In this guide, we’ll break down the best cinemas in town, how to find promotions that actually feel like a win, and what you need to know about new movie releases. So grab your overpriced popcorn, and let’s dive in.</p>

<h3 id="what-cinemas-are-there-in-singapore">What cinemas are there in Singapore?</h3>

<p>Singapore offers a solid mix of mainstream chains and unique cinema experiences. Here are the major ones:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Golden Village (GV) – The go-to chain with plenty of locations, including Gold Class for those who enjoy reclining in style.</li>
  <li>Shaw Theatres – Reliable with IMAX options and premium seating like Lumiere.</li>
  <li>Cathay Cineplexes – Known for its sleek cinemas and student deals.</li>
  <li>The Projector – A quirky indie cinema with vintage vibes and artsy films.</li>
  <li>EagleWings Cinematics – A boutique cinema that feels more like a private lounge.</li>
  <li>Filmgarde Cineplexes – Focuses on blockbusters but offers a more intimate setting.</li>
</ul>

<p>Whether you’re after big-screen thrills or something a little artsier, Singapore’s cinema scene has you covered.</p>

<h3 id="here-are-some-popular-cinema-locations-across-singapore">Here are some popular cinema locations across Singapore:</h3>

<p><u>Golden Village (GV)<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>GV VivoCity (HarbourFront)</li>
  <li>GV Plaza Singapura (Dhoby Ghaut)</li>
  <li>GV Suntec City (Esplanade)</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Shaw Theatres<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>Shaw Theatres Lido (Orchard)</li>
  <li>Shaw Theatres Jewel (Changi Airport)</li>
  <li>Shaw Theatres Waterway Point (Punggol)</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Cathay Cineplexes<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>The Cathay Cineplex (Dhoby Ghaut)</li>
  <li>Cathay Cineplex Jem (Jurong East)</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="how-much-is-a-cinema-ticket-in-singapore">How much is a cinema ticket in Singapore?</h3>

<p>Cinema ticket prices in Singapore vary depending on the day, time, and cinema chain. Here’s a rough guide:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Weekday (Standard 2D): ~$9 to $13</li>
  <li>Weekend (Standard 2D): ~$13 to $15</li>
  <li>IMAX or Premium Screens: ~$20 to $25</li>
  <li>Gold Class or VIP Experience: ~$30 to $40+</li>
  <li>Student/Senior Deals: Often ~$7 to $9 (weekdays before 6 PM)</li>
</ul>

<p>Promotions, bundle deals, and loyalty programs can sometimes cut costs, so it’s worth keeping an eye out. And yes, those fancy recliner seats may cost more — but at least you’ll feel like royalty while dramatically overpaying for popcorn.</p>

<h3 id="how-often-do-cinemas-in-singapore-refresh-their-movies">How often do cinemas in Singapore refresh their movies?</h3>

<p>Cinemas in Singapore typically refresh their movie lineup every Thursday. This is when new blockbuster releases, indie films, and even some international titles make their debut. Major chains like Golden Village, Shaw Theatres, and Cathay Cineplexes follow this weekly schedule closely.</p>

<p>That said, big-ticket films (think Marvel or major holiday releases) may occasionally drop on Wednesdays to build early buzz. Meanwhile, smaller indie cinemas like The Projector may switch up their schedule depending on special events or themed screenings.</p>

<p>So if you’re wondering when that shiny new movie lands — Thursday’s your magic day.</p>

<h3 id="how-do-cinemas-in-singapore-make-money">How do cinemas in Singapore make money?</h3>

<p>Cinemas in Singapore don’t just rely on ticket sales — they’ve mastered the art of turning your movie night into a mini spending spree. Here’s how they cash in:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Ticket Sales – While a chunk goes back to film distributors, cinemas still take a cut — especially from premium formats like IMAX or Gold Class.</li>
  <li>Concession Stands – That $10 popcorn combo? Pure profit. Snacks are where cinemas really clean up.</li>
  <li>Advertising – Those endless pre-movie ads aren’t just for your boredom; brands pay top dollar to show them.</li>
  <li>Event Screenings &amp; Private Bookings – From birthday parties to corporate events, cinemas make bank renting out their halls.</li>
  <li>Loyalty Programs &amp; Memberships – Perks like discounts and free tickets keep moviegoers coming back (and spending more).</li>
  <li>Merchandise &amp; Tie-ins – Some cinemas sell limited-edition collectibles or themed snacks during major film releases.</li>
</ul>

<p>Basically, cinemas are experts at getting you to spend — and somehow convincing you that $6 nachos are totally reasonable.</p>

<h3 id="why-are-cinemas-in-singapore-struggling">Why are cinemas in Singapore struggling?</h3>

<p>Cinemas in Singapore have been grappling with several challenges in recent years, leading to notable closures and financial strains. Key factors contributing to their struggles include:</p>

<ul>
  <li>COVID-19 Pandemic: The pandemic led to prolonged closures and capacity restrictions, significantly reducing revenue. For instance, Cathay Cineplexes faced months-long shutdowns in 2020, followed by operations at reduced capacities.</li>
  <li>Shifts in Consumer Behavior: The rise of streaming platforms has altered viewing habits, with many opting to watch movies at home. This shift has impacted traditional cinema attendance.</li>
  <li>Operational Costs and Rental Pressures: High operational expenses, including rental costs, have strained profitability. In January 2025, Cathay Cineplexes received letters of demand for approximately S$2.7 million in unpaid rent and related costs for its operations at Century Square and Causeway Point.</li>
</ul>

<p>These challenges have led to several cinema closures in Singapore:</p>

<ul>
  <li>The Cathay Cineplex (Handy Road): Ceased operations on June 26, 2022, ending 83 years of cinematic history at the site.</li>
  <li>Cathay Cineleisure Orchard: Closed on June 30, 2023. Subsequently, a collaboration between Golden Village and The Projector took over the cinema space.</li>
  <li>Cathay Cineplex at Parkway Parade: Shut down on August 27, 2023, as part of efforts to “right-size” operations.</li>
  <li>Cathay Cineplex at AMK Hub: Closed after June 30, 2024, with the space slated for repurposing for civic and community uses.</li>
  <li>Cathay Cineplex at West Mall: Ceased operations on February 20, 2025, due to lease expiry.</li>
</ul>

<p>Despite these setbacks, cinema operators are exploring strategies such as mergers and diversifying offerings to adapt to the evolving entertainment landscape and sustain their presence in Singapore.</p>

<h3 id="how-are-cinemas-in-singapore-adapting-to-attract-more-customers">How are cinemas in Singapore adapting to attract more customers?</h3>

<p>Cinemas in Singapore have been getting creative to lure audiences back. Here’s how they’re adapting:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Luxury Experiences – Cinemas like Golden Village Gold Class and Shaw Theatres Lumiere offer plush recliners, gourmet dining, and even blankets to elevate your movie night.</li>
  <li>Themed Screenings &amp; Events – The Projector regularly hosts nostalgic movie marathons, cult classic nights, and themed parties that feel more like social events than traditional screenings.</li>
  <li>Enhanced Tech &amp; Screens – IMAX, Dolby Atmos, and 4DX experiences are being pushed hard to remind viewers that their home TV just isn’t the same.</li>
  <li>Food Upgrades – Some cinemas are going beyond popcorn, offering restaurant-quality meals, bubble tea, and even cocktails.</li>
  <li>Loyalty Perks &amp; Memberships – Chains like GV Movie Club and Shaw Theatres’ membership programs offer discounts, free tickets, and priority bookings to keep regulars coming back.</li>
  <li>Alternative Content – Cinemas are screening live sports, concerts, and even gaming events to broaden their audience base.</li>
  <li>Private Screenings &amp; Rentals – For those who prefer a more exclusive experience, some cinemas now allow you to book entire halls for parties or private viewings.</li>
</ul>

<p>From cozy blankets to bubble tea with your blockbuster, Singapore’s cinemas are doing their best to make sure you leave your couch once in a while.</p>

<h3 id="what-is-the-projector-and-what-makes-it-special">What is ‘The Projector’ and what makes it special?</h3>

<p>The Projector is Singapore’s indie cinema gem — a far cry from your typical mall movie theater. Known for its retro vibe and eclectic lineup, The Projector screens everything from arthouse films and cult classics to international indie hits and local productions.</p>

<h3 id="what-makes-the-projector-special">What makes The Projector special?</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Unique Atmosphere – With vintage decor, mismatched seats, and a laid-back vibe, it feels more like a cool hangout spot than a sterile cinema.</li>
  <li>Curated Film Selection – They specialize in offbeat, thought-provoking films — perfect for movie buffs who crave something different from Hollywood blockbusters.</li>
  <li>Themed Events &amp; Parties – From drag shows to karaoke nights and themed movie screenings, The Projector doubles as a lively social space.</li>
  <li>Food &amp; Drinks – You can grab craft beer, cocktails, and gourmet snacks — none of that dry popcorn-only business.</li>
  <li>Community Vibes – With regular talks, workshops, and indie film festivals, it’s a hotspot for creatives and film enthusiasts alike.</li>
</ul>

<p>Check it out!</p>

<h3 id="why-should-you-support-your-local-cinema-in-singapore">Why should you support your local cinema in Singapore?</h3>

<p>Not really a reason tbh. Just watch netflix instead.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Singapore" /><category term="entertainment" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cinemas in Singapore are more than just a place to catch the latest blockbuster — they’re practically a national pastime. They were at least.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/cinema.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/cinema.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Singapore’s Guide to the NBA: How to Follow Games, Scores &amp;amp; Playoffs</title><link href="/singapore-nba/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Singapore’s Guide to the NBA: How to Follow Games, Scores &amp;amp; Playoffs" /><published>2025-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-nba</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-nba/"><![CDATA[<p>The NBA may not be Singapore’s national obsession, but basketball still has a loyal following here.</p>

<p>Whether you’re checking NBA scores, keeping up with NBA standings, or planning your week around the NBA schedule, there’s no shortage of ways to stay updated. Fans eagerly follow the NBA Playoffs and NBA Finals, while the NBA All-Star Game gives everyone an excuse to watch players show off (even more than usual). From catching the latest NBA news to searching for an NBA live stream at odd hours, Singaporeans have found ways to stay connected to the game. And if all that isn’t enough, there are even local courts where you can attempt your own version of an NBA highlight—just with a little less dunking.</p>

<h3 id="is-basketball-popular-in-singapore">Is basketball popular in Singapore?</h3>

<p>Basketball has a decent following in Singapore, especially with the NBA’s global appeal. While it’s not as big as football, local courts stay busy, and big NBA events like the NBA Playoffs and NBA Finals always draw attention.</p>

<h3 id="why-do-singaporeans-like-watching-basketball--watching-the-nba">Why do Singaporeans like watching basketball / watching the NBA?</h3>

<p>Singaporeans like watching basketball and the NBA because:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Fast-paced action – Non-stop movement, dunks, and buzzer-beaters keep things exciting.</li>
  <li>Star players – Global icons like LeBron James, Stephen Curry, and Giannis make the game entertaining.</li>
  <li>NBA drama – Trades, rivalries, and off-court stories add to the entertainment.</li>
  <li>Big events – The NBA Playoffs, NBA Finals, and NBA All-Star Game bring high-stakes action.</li>
  <li>Easy to watch – With NBA live streams and highlights online, it’s accessible anytime.</li>
  <li>Streetball culture – Many Singaporeans play casually, so watching the pros is inspiring.</li>
  <li>Betting and fantasy leagues – Some follow the game for wagers or fantasy basketball fun.</li>
  <li>Global influence – The NBA’s marketing ensures its presence everywhere, including Singapore.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="top-nba-teams-that-singaporean-support">Top NBA teams that Singaporean support</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Los Angeles Lakers – One of the most iconic teams in NBA history, with a legacy from Magic Johnson to Kobe Bryant and now LeBron James. Their championships and Hollywood appeal make them a global favorite.</li>
  <li>Golden State Warriors – The team that revolutionized basketball with Stephen Curry’s insane three-pointers. Their dominance in the 2010s made them one of the most popular franchises worldwide, including in Singapore.</li>
  <li>Chicago Bulls – Even though their last championship was in 1998, Michael Jordan’s influence keeps the Bulls relevant. The “Jordan effect” means they still have loyal fans decades later.</li>
  <li>Miami Heat – The LeBron James-Dwyane Wade-Chris Bosh “Big Three” era made them a top team to follow. Their tough, no-nonsense playing style under coach Erik Spoelstra continues to attract fans.</li>
  <li>Boston Celtics – The most successful NBA franchise in terms of total championships (tied with the Lakers). Their mix of history, passionate fanbase, and young stars like Jayson Tatum keeps them in the spotlight.</li>
  <li>Brooklyn Nets – Once a struggling franchise, they gained serious attention when they stacked their team with superstars like Kevin Durant, Kyrie Irving, and James Harden (even if it didn’t quite work out).</li>
  <li>Milwaukee Bucks – Giannis Antetokounmpo turned the Bucks into a powerhouse, proving that a small-market team can win championships. Singaporean fans appreciate his work ethic and dominance.</li>
  <li>Phoenix Suns – The Suns gained a new wave of fans with their recent success, led by Devin Booker and Kevin Durant. Their fast-paced offense makes them an exciting team to watch.</li>
  <li>Dallas Mavericks – Luka Dončić has made the Mavericks a must-watch team, bringing back memories of Dirk Nowitzki’s legendary run. His flashy style of play keeps fans entertained. Too bad he’s no longer there.</li>
  <li>Denver Nuggets – The defending champions (thanks to Nikola Jokić) have won over fans with their efficient, unselfish play. Jokić’s unique style as a dominant but humble superstar is a refreshing change.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="where-do-you-watch-nba-in-singapore">Where do you watch NBA in Singapore</h3>

<p>Here’s where you can watch NBA games in Singapore:</p>

<ul>
  <li>NBA League Pass – The official streaming service for live and on-demand NBA games. Best for hardcore fans who want every game.</li>
  <li>StarHub &amp; Singtel TV – Both offer NBA broadcasts, usually covering key games and playoffs.</li>
  <li>MeWatch – Sometimes carries NBA content, though availability varies.</li>
  <li>YouTube &amp; Social Media – Official NBA highlights and live game snippets are available for free.</li>
  <li>Sports Bars &amp; Pubs – Places like Mischief (Esplanade) and Harry’s Bar sometimes show NBA games, especially during the NBA Playoffs and NBA Finals.</li>
  <li>Community Screens – Some malls and event spaces air major games (mainly the NBA Finals).</li>
  <li>Reddit &amp; Alternative Streams – Not the most legal option, but let’s just say some fans get creative.</li>
</ul>

<p>With Singapore’s time zone, games are often in the morning, so finding a live crowd outside of big events can be tricky.</p>

<h3 id="when-are-nba-games-on">When are NBA games on?</h3>

<p>NBA game timings in Singapore (SGT, GMT+8):</p>
<ul>
  <li>Regular Season: Most games start between 8 AM – 12 PM (Singapore time).</li>
  <li>Weekend Games: Some start earlier, around 7 AM, especially on Sundays.</li>
</ul>

<p>NBA Playoffs: Timings are similar but may vary depending on matchups.
NBA Finals: Typically held in the morning (8–10 AM SGT) in June.
NBA All-Star Game: Usually airs around 9–10 AM SGT in February.</p>

<p>Since the NBA is based in the U.S., games are scheduled according to U.S. time zones, meaning Singapore fans often have to wake up early or catch replays. And then there are the global games of course</p>

<h3 id="when-is-the-nba-all-star-game">When is the NBA all star game?</h3>

<p>The NBA All-Star Game usually takes place in mid-February during the NBA season’s break. For 2025, it’s expected to be held around February 16–17 (Singapore time), though the exact date may vary. Since it’s a prime-time U.S. event, Singapore viewers can typically catch it live in the morning (around 9–10 AM SGT).</p>

<h3 id="where-can-you-check-nba-scores">Where can you check NBA scores?</h3>

<p>You can check NBA scores in Singapore through these platforms:</p>
<ul>
  <li>NBA App – The official app for live scores, stats, and game updates.</li>
  <li>ESPN – Provides real-time scores, standings, and detailed analysis.</li>
  <li>Yahoo Sports – Great for live scores, highlights, and news.</li>
  <li>Google Search – Simply type “NBA scores” for instant results.</li>
  <li>Bleacher Report – Covers scores with added commentary and insights.</li>
  <li>X (formerly Twitter) – Follow NBA accounts for live updates.</li>
  <li>SofaScore / FlashScore – Excellent for detailed stats and timelines.</li>
</ul>

<p>For the fastest updates, the NBA App or Google are your best bets.</p>

<h3 id="what-other-nba-games-are-there-beyond-the-usual-league-format">What other NBA games are there beyond the usual league format?</h3>

<p>Beyond the regular NBA season, there are several special events and formats that keep basketball fans entertained:</p>

<ul>
  <li>NBA All-Star Game – A mid-season exhibition game where the league’s top stars face off. Includes events like the 3-Point Contest and Slam Dunk Contest.</li>
  <li>NBA Play-In Tournament – Held just before the NBA Playoffs, where lower-seeded teams compete for the final playoff spots.</li>
  <li>NBA Playoffs – The intense, high-stakes knockout tournament that leads to the NBA Finals.</li>
  <li>NBA Finals – The championship series that determines the season’s winner.</li>
  <li>NBA Summer League – An off-season tournament where rookies and younger players showcase their skills.</li>
  <li>NBA Cup (In-Season Tournament) – A newer competition with a cup-style format during the regular season, adding extra excitement to mid-season matchups.</li>
  <li>FIBA Events &amp; Olympic Games – While not NBA-exclusive, many NBA stars compete internationally in these tournaments.</li>
</ul>

<p>NBA Rising Stars invitational will also be in Singapore!</p>

<h3 id="where-can-you-play-basketball-in-singapore">Where can you play basketball in Singapore?</h3>

<p><u>Public Courts (Free &amp; Accessible)<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>Our Tampines Hub – Spacious outdoor courts with solid facilities.</li>
  <li>Bishan-Ang Mo Kio Park – Scenic surroundings with well-maintained courts.</li>
  <li>Commonwealth Crescent Court – Popular with casual players and local talent.</li>
  <li>Jurong West Sports Centre – Features multiple courts with good lighting.</li>
  <li>Bedok North Street 3 Court – Great for late-night games.</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Indoor Courts (Paid but Weatherproof)<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>ActiveSG Sports Halls – Affordable and available across Singapore.</li>
  <li>The Cage @ Kallang – Multi-sport facility with indoor courts.</li>
  <li>OCBC Arena (Singapore Sports Hub) – Professional indoor court for serious ballers.</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Community Centres (CCs)<u></u></u></p>

<p>Many CCs have indoor or sheltered basketball courts open to the public — check your nearest CC for availability.</p>

<p><u>Schools &amp; Universities<u></u></u></p>

<p>Some institutions allow public bookings for their basketball courts outside school hours.</p>

<p>For casual games, public courts are your best bet — just bring a ball and you’ll likely find a pickup game in progress!</p>

<h3 id="are-there-any-local-singapore-basketball-leagues">Are there any local Singapore basketball leagues?</h3>

<p>Singapore has several local basketball leagues for various skill levels:</p>
<ul>
  <li>National Basketball League (NBL) – Singapore’s top-tier basketball competition featuring competitive teams and skilled players.</li>
  <li>Women’s National Basketball League (WNBL) – The female counterpart to the NBL, showcasing top local talent.</li>
  <li>Community Basketball League (CBL) – A grassroots league for youth and amateur players.</li>
  <li>ActiveSG Basketball Academy Leagues – Designed for juniors and developing players.</li>
</ul>

<p>Stay active!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Singapore" /><category term="sports" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The NBA may not be Singapore’s national obsession, but basketball still has a loyal following here.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/nba.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/nba.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Why is Singapore So Hot? Understanding the Humid Climate &amp;amp; How to Stay Cool</title><link href="/singapore-hot-weather/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why is Singapore So Hot? Understanding the Humid Climate &amp;amp; How to Stay Cool" /><published>2025-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-hot-weather</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-hot-weather/"><![CDATA[<p>Why is Singapore so hot? If you’ve ever stepped outside and felt like you were swimming through the air, you’re not alone.</p>

<p>Singapore’s hot weather is a year-round affair, thanks to its location near the equator, high humidity, and complete lack of seasons—yes, it’s summer all the time. But how does Singapore’s climate compare to other hot countries, and is there a risk of temperatures going even higher in the future? Before you start planning a personal air-conditioning bubble, we’ll explore why Singapore is so humid, how hot it gets across different months, and some crazy ideas to keep the country cool. And if you’re already melting, check out our previous article for the best tips and tricks to survive Singapore’s never-ending heatwave.</p>

<h3 id="how-hot-does-singapore-get-across-months">How hot does Singapore get across months?</h3>

<p>Singapore is consistently hot year-round, with average temperatures hovering between 24°C to 34°C (75°F to 93°F). Rainfall varies by month, but thanks to the country’s humid tropical climate, expect frequent showers no matter when you visit. Here’s a month-by-month breakdown:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <table>
      <tbody>
        <tr>
          <td>January: 24°C – 31°C</td>
          <td>Rainy, part of the Northeast Monsoon season</td>
        </tr>
      </tbody>
    </table>
  </li>
  <li>
    <table>
      <tbody>
        <tr>
          <td>February: 25°C – 32°C</td>
          <td>Slightly drier but still humid</td>
        </tr>
      </tbody>
    </table>
  </li>
  <li>
    <table>
      <tbody>
        <tr>
          <td>March: 25°C – 33°C</td>
          <td>Hotter, with increasing afternoon showers</td>
        </tr>
      </tbody>
    </table>
  </li>
  <li>
    <table>
      <tbody>
        <tr>
          <td>April: 26°C – 34°C</td>
          <td>One of the hottest months, frequent thunderstorms</td>
        </tr>
      </tbody>
    </table>
  </li>
  <li>
    <table>
      <tbody>
        <tr>
          <td>May: 26°C – 34°C</td>
          <td>Peak heat, very humid, thunderstorms common</td>
        </tr>
      </tbody>
    </table>
  </li>
  <li>
    <table>
      <tbody>
        <tr>
          <td>June: 26°C – 33°C</td>
          <td>Start of the Southwest Monsoon, occasional haze</td>
        </tr>
      </tbody>
    </table>
  </li>
  <li>
    <table>
      <tbody>
        <tr>
          <td>July: 25°C – 32°C</td>
          <td>Slightly cooler but still warm, passing showers</td>
        </tr>
      </tbody>
    </table>
  </li>
  <li>
    <table>
      <tbody>
        <tr>
          <td>August: 25°C – 32°C</td>
          <td>Hot and humid, with some monsoon rain</td>
        </tr>
      </tbody>
    </table>
  </li>
  <li>
    <table>
      <tbody>
        <tr>
          <td>September: 25°C – 32°C</td>
          <td>Rain increases slightly, still warm</td>
        </tr>
      </tbody>
    </table>
  </li>
  <li>
    <table>
      <tbody>
        <tr>
          <td>October: 25°C – 32°C</td>
          <td>Start of the second monsoon season, wetter</td>
        </tr>
      </tbody>
    </table>
  </li>
  <li>
    <table>
      <tbody>
        <tr>
          <td>November: 24°C – 31°C</td>
          <td>Frequent rain, cooler evenings</td>
        </tr>
      </tbody>
    </table>
  </li>
  <li>
    <table>
      <tbody>
        <tr>
          <td>December: 24°C – 30°C</td>
          <td>Rainiest month, slightly more bearable temperatures</td>
        </tr>
      </tbody>
    </table>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>So, whether it’s January or June, Singapore’s heat is relentless—but at least there’s air-conditioning everywhere.</p>

<h3 id="why-is-singapore-so-hot">Why is Singapore so hot?</h3>

<p>Singapore is so hot because it sits almost directly on the equator, meaning the sun is practically overhead all year long. Unlike places with four seasons, Singapore doesn’t get a break—no winter, no cool autumn breeze, just endless summer. The country’s high humidity (often above 80%) makes it feel even hotter, trapping heat like a sticky, invisible blanket. Plus, urbanization and the heat island effect from all the concrete and buildings make things worse, keeping the city warm even at night. And if you’re hoping for a sudden cold spell—sorry, the only ice you’ll find is in your bubble tea.</p>

<h3 id="why-does-singapore-not-have-seasons">Why does Singapore not have seasons?</h3>

<p>Same reasons as above. Singapore doesn’t have seasons because it’s located near the equator, where the sun’s position and temperature stay consistent year-round.</p>

<h3 id="how-does-singapores-temperatures-rank-versus-other-hot-countries">How does Singapore’s temperatures rank versus other hot countries?</h3>

<p>Singapore is consistently hot, but it’s not the hottest place on Earth. Compared to desert regions like Death Valley, USA (up to 56.7°C) or Kuwait (over 50°C in summer), Singapore’s 34°C max might seem mild. However, what makes Singapore unbearable is the humidity, which pushes the heat index (feels-like temperature) past 40°C. Among tropical cities, Singapore ranks alongside Jakarta, Bangkok, and Kuala Lumpur, but its urban heat island effect makes it feel hotter than many of them, especially at night. So while you won’t fry an egg on the pavement, you’ll definitely sweat through your shirt in minutes.</p>

<h3 id="tips-to-stay-cool-in-the-heat">Tips to stay cool in the heat</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Wear light, breathable clothing – Stick to loose, moisture-wicking fabrics like cotton or linen to stay comfortable.</li>
  <li>Stay hydrated – Drink plenty of water (or iced kopi, no judgment) to prevent dehydration and overheating.</li>
  <li>Seek air-conditioning – Malls, MRT stations, and underground walkways are your best friends in Singapore’s heat.</li>
  <li>Avoid the midday sun – The sun is strongest between 11 AM – 3 PM, so plan outdoor activities in the morning or evening.</li>
  <li>Use cooling products – Carry a portable fan, cooling wipes, or even a mist spray to survive Singapore’s never-ending sauna.</li>
</ul>

<p>Check out our <a href="https://fromhktosg.github.io/singapore-weather/">previous article</a> to learn more about these tips and tricks.</p>

<h3 id="is-there-a-risk-of-temperatures-going-higher-in-the-future-in-singapore">Is there a risk of temperatures going higher in the future in Singapore?</h3>

<p>Singapore’s temperatures are expected to rise due to climate change and urbanization. Global warming is pushing up temperatures worldwide, and Singapore’s urban heat island effect (all that concrete trapping heat) makes it worse. The government projects that by 2100, average temperatures could rise by 4°C, meaning 35°C+ days could become the norm. Increased humidity will also make the “feels-like” temperature even more unbearable. So yes, it’s already hot—but the future might be even hotter.</p>

<h3 id="what-would-cause-higher-temperatures-in-singapore">What would cause higher temperatures in Singapore?</h3>

<p>Higher temperatures in Singapore would be caused by a mix of climate change and urbanization. Global warming is driving up temperatures worldwide, leading to more extreme heat. The urban heat island effect—where concrete, glass, and asphalt trap and radiate heat—makes Singapore even warmer, especially at night. Deforestation in and around the region also reduces natural cooling, while increasing carbon emissions from industries and transport worsen the problem. And if that’s not enough, rising sea levels could lead to more humid conditions, making the heat feel even more unbearable.</p>

<h3 id="how-can-singapore-best-adapt-for-higher-temperatures">How can Singapore best adapt for higher temperatures?</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Increase green spaces – Plant more trees, create green roofs, and develop more parks to cool the environment.</li>
  <li>Implement cooling infrastructure – Use reflective surfaces, smart water features, and energy-efficient materials in urban design.</li>
  <li>Promote energy-efficient buildings – Encourage sustainable architecture to reduce heat absorption and lower energy consumption.</li>
  <li>Expand public transportation – Reduce car usage and lower emissions through better, more accessible public transit.</li>
  <li>Improve water management – Enhance drainage and flood prevention systems to cope with extreme weather.</li>
  <li>Invest in climate-resilient technologies – Focus on innovations that help mitigate the effects of heat and climate change.</li>
  <li>Educate the public – Raise awareness on sustainable practices and how to adapt to the changing climate.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="crazy-ideas-to-keep-singapore-cool">Crazy ideas to keep Singapore cool</h3>

<p>Here are some crazy (but maybe genius) ideas to keep Singapore cool:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Giant air-conditioned domes – Just cover the whole city like Gardens by the Bay and blast the AC. Problem solved.</li>
  <li>Floating icebergs in Marina Bay – Tug some ice from Antarctica and let it melt slowly for a natural cooling effect.</li>
  <li>Underground Singapore 2.0 – Build an entire underground city where it’s always cool, and never step outside again.</li>
  <li>Massive misting systems – Turn every lamppost into a fine mist sprayer so stepping outside feels like walking through a cooling cloud.</li>
  <li>Heat-reflecting skyscrapers – Cover buildings in reflective materials to bounce heat away—bonus if they double as giant solar panels.</li>
  <li>Artificial rain-on-demand – Control the clouds and make it rain whenever temperatures hit unbearable levels.</li>
  <li>Citywide ice baths – Free public ice baths at MRT stations—because desperate times call for refreshing measures.</li>
</ul>

<p>Some of these may sound ridiculous, but hey, Singapore already air-conditions its bus stops, so anything is possible!</p>

<p>What do you guys think?</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Singapore" /><category term="weather" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why is Singapore so hot? If you’ve ever stepped outside and felt like you were swimming through the air, you’re not alone.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/hot.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/hot.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Ramadan 2025 in Singapore: Best Bazaars &amp;amp; Traditions Explained</title><link href="/singapore-ramadan/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ramadan 2025 in Singapore: Best Bazaars &amp;amp; Traditions Explained" /><published>2025-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-ramadan</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-ramadan/"><![CDATA[<p>Ramadan 2025 in Singapore is more than just a month of fasting—it’s a time of spiritual reflection, community gatherings, and, of course, legendary iftar buffets and Ramadan bazaars.</p>

<p>From sunrise to sunset, Muslims abstain from food, drink, and, yes, even that morning coffee, while the rest of Singapore tiptoes around their fasting colleagues. But before Ramadan even begins, there’s a whole list of things not to do—think indulgent feasting and last-minute guilt trips to repent for the year’s snacks. Once it starts, expect bustling mosques, late-night prayers, and the city’s most vibrant food markets popping up in Geylang Serai and beyond. Whether you’re looking for the best places to break your fast or just wondering what makes Ramadan in Singapore so special, here’s everything you need to know.</p>

<h3 id="what-is-ramadan">What is Ramadan?</h3>

<p>Ramadan is the holiest month in Islam, observed by Muslims worldwide through fasting, prayer, and reflection. From sunrise to sunset, those fasting abstain from food, drink, and other physical needs as a way of strengthening their faith and practicing self-discipline. It’s not just about skipping lunch—Ramadan is also a time for charity, community, and deep spiritual connection. Nights are filled with special prayers called taraweeh, and once the sun sets, families and friends gather for iftar (the meal to break the fast), often with dates and a feast that almost makes up for the day’s hunger. In Singapore, Ramadan is marked by lively bazaars, packed mosques, and an overall sense of togetherness—plus, a sudden surge in sales of sweet drinks and fried snacks.</p>

<h3 id="when-is-ramadan-in-singapore">When is Ramadan in Singapore?</h3>

<p>Ramadan in Singapore for the year 2025 is expected to begin on Sunday, March 2, and conclude on Tuesday, March 31. These dates may vary slightly depending on the sighting of the moon, which traditionally marks the start and end of the Islamic lunar months. During this period, Muslims in Singapore will observe fasting from dawn (Fajr) until sunset (Maghrib), engaging in increased prayers and reflection. The end of Ramadan is celebrated with Eid al-Fitr, a festive occasion marked by communal prayers, feasting, and the giving of charity.</p>

<h3 id="what-can-you-not-do-before-ramadan">What can you not do before Ramadan?</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Overindulging in food and drinks – Binge-eating like it’s your last meal on earth won’t make fasting any easier.</li>
  <li>Ignoring missed fasts from the previous year – If you still have qada (missed fasts) to make up, now’s the time—not halfway through Ramadan.</li>
  <li>Skipping spiritual preparation – Ramadan isn’t just about avoiding food; it’s about self-reflection. Maybe don’t wait until Day 1 to start praying more.</li>
  <li>Leaving bad habits unchecked – Whether it’s smoking, excessive screen time, or gossiping, breaking habits before Ramadan makes the transition smoother.</li>
  <li>Not setting realistic Ramadan goals – Planning to read the entire Quran in a month but haven’t touched it all year? Maybe set achievable goals instead.</li>
  <li>Forgetting to stock up on essentials – Avoid last-minute grocery panic by prepping dates, prayer mats, and whatever snack you’ll be craving at iftar.</li>
  <li>Ignoring charity opportunities – Ramadan is about giving, so start thinking about zakat and donations early.
Not fixing your sleep schedule – Taraweeh prayers and suhoor will mess up your routine—better to start adjusting now.</li>
</ul>

<p>In short, don’t wait until Ramadan starts to get into the right mindset. A little preparation goes a long way!</p>

<h3 id="what-can-you-not-do-during-ramadan">What can you not do during ramadan?</h3>

<p>During Ramadan, there are a few clear don’ts to keep in mind:</p>
<ul>
  <li>No eating or drinking from dawn to sunset – Yes, even water.</li>
  <li>No smoking or chewing gum – Your breath will survive (hopefully).</li>
  <li>No marital intimacy during fasting hours</li>
  <li>No swearing, gossiping, or lying – A spiritual cleanse, not just a food one.</li>
  <li>No skipping prayers – Fasting isn’t just about hunger; prayer is key.</li>
</ul>

<p>Basically, it’s about self-control—physically, mentally, and spiritually!</p>

<h3 id="how-is-ramadan-celebrated-in-singapore">How is Ramadan celebrated in Singapore?</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Community iftar events – Mosques and organizations host mass iftars, offering free meals to break fast together.</li>
  <li>Late-night shopping – Many halal eateries and markets extend their hours to cater to those breaking fast late.</li>
  <li>Volunteer-driven food distributions – Groups distribute free porridge (bubur Ramadan) and food packs to those in need.</li>
  <li>Increased religious talks and Quran recitations – Mosques organize lectures and recitation sessions for spiritual enrichment.</li>
  <li>Special Ramadan promotions – Restaurants, malls, and brands roll out festive discounts and Ramadan-exclusive deals.</li>
  <li>Hari Raya preparation rush – The last few weeks see a shopping frenzy as families buy clothes, decorations, and festive treats for Eid.</li>
</ul>

<p>Ramadan in Singapore isn’t just about fasting—it’s a season of giving, gathering, and gearing up for Hari Raya!</p>

<h3 id="what-do-you-eat-during-ramadan-in-singapore">What do you eat during Ramadan in Singapore?</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Dates and water – The classic way to break fast, following tradition and for a quick energy boost.</li>
  <li>Bubur Ramadan (porridge) – A comforting, free staple often distributed by mosques.</li>
  <li>Nasi Briyani – Fragrant rice with spiced meat, a popular hearty meal after a long day of fasting.</li>
  <li>Ayam Percik – Grilled, marinated chicken with a rich, smoky coconut sauce.</li>
  <li>Mee Rebus – Yellow noodles in a thick, flavorful gravy, perfect for replenishing energy.</li>
  <li>Murtabak – A stuffed, pan-fried roti filled with minced meat, egg, and onions.</li>
  <li>Ramly Burger – A must-have street food item, especially from Ramadan bazaars.</li>
  <li>Goreng Pisang (fried banana fritters) – A crispy, sweet snack perfect for post-iftar munching.</li>
  <li>Teh Tarik and Bandung – Sweet, milky drinks that are crowd favorites during Ramadan.</li>
  <li>Kuih-muih (traditional Malay desserts) – Small, colorful treats like Ondeh-Ondeh and Kueh Lapis to end the night on a sweet note.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="which-mosques-can-i-visit-during-ramadan-in-singapore-in-2025">Which mosques can I visit during Ramadan in singapore in 2025?</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Sultan Mosque – Kampong Glam</li>
  <li>Masjid Al-Istighfar – Pasir Ris</li>
  <li>Masjid Al-Mukminin – Jurong</li>
  <li>Masjid Darul Ghufran – Tampines</li>
  <li>Masjid An-Nur – Woodlands</li>
  <li>Masjid Kassim – Eunos</li>
  <li>Masjid Abdul Gafoor – Little India</li>
  <li>Masjid Al-Falah – Orchard</li>
  <li>Masjid Assyafaah – Sembawang</li>
  <li>Masjid Hajjah Fatimah – Bugis</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="what-are-the-opening-and-closing-hours-for-mosques-in-singapore-during-ramadan">What are the opening and closing hours for mosques in Singapore during Ramadan?</h3>

<p>Most mosques in Singapore are open daily from 5:00 AM to 10:00 PM, but hours may vary depending on prayer times and events.</p>

<p>During Ramadan, many mosques extend their hours, staying open later for taraweeh prayers and sometimes even until midnight or later for qiyam (night prayers).</p>

<h3 id="what-are-ramadan-bazaars">What are Ramadan bazaars?</h3>

<p>Ramadan bazaars are lively street markets set up during the fasting month, selling a mix of traditional and trendy food, festive decorations, clothing, and accessories for Hari Raya. These bazaars are a big part of the Ramadan experience in Singapore, drawing crowds looking for delicious iftar snacks, last-minute Raya outfits, and a dose of festive atmosphere. Expect a mix of classic Malay dishes like Ramly burgers and otak-otak, alongside viral street food creations that may or may not be worth the hype. The bazaars are usually located near mosques or in popular neighborhoods in the heartlands, running from late afternoon until late at night.</p>

<h3 id="what-to-order-at-a-ramadan-bazaar-in-singapore">What to order at a Ramadan bazaar in Singapore?</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Ramly Burger – Juicy, egg-wrapped burger loaded with sauces. A bazaar staple.</li>
  <li>Murtabak – Flaky flatbread stuffed with spiced meat, onions, and eggs.</li>
  <li>Roti John – Egg and meat-filled baguette, grilled to perfection.</li>
  <li>Kebab Wraps – Spiced meat, fresh veggies, and creamy sauces wrapped in flatbread.</li>
  <li>Ayam Percik – Grilled chicken drenched in spicy coconut sauce.</li>
  <li>Vadai – Savoury Indian fritters, often with shrimp or onion toppings.</li>
  <li>Takoyaki – Japanese-style octopus balls, popular at local bazaars.</li>
  <li>Churros – Crisp, sweet dough sticks coated in cinnamon sugar.</li>
  <li>Durian Puffs – Creamy durian-filled pastries for the adventurous.</li>
  <li>Rainbow Drinks – Bright, layered beverages like Bandung or bubble tea.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="popular-ramadan-bazaars-in-singapore">Popular ramadan bazaars in Singapore</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Geylang Serai Ramadan Bazaar – Geylang</li>
  <li>Kampong Glam Ramadan Bazaar – Kampong Glam</li>
  <li>Joo Chiat Ramadan Bazaar – Joo Chiat</li>
  <li>Bedok Reservoir Ramadan Bazaar – Bedok Reservoir</li>
  <li>Tampines Ramadan Bazaar – Tampines</li>
  <li>Yishun Ramadan Bazaar – Yishun</li>
  <li>Hougang Ramadan Bazaar – Hougang</li>
  <li>Farrer Park Ramadan Bazaar – Farrer Park</li>
</ul>

<p>Geylang Serai is the iconic one - go check it out for a fun night. Ramadan Mubarak!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Singapore" /><category term="holiday" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ramadan 2025 in Singapore is more than just a month of fasting—it’s a time of spiritual reflection, community gatherings, and, of course, legendary iftar buffets and Ramadan bazaars.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/bazaar.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/bazaar.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>