<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2025-02-01T10:31:42+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">From HK to SG</title><entry><title type="html">Guide to Singapore airport lounges</title><link href="/singapore-airport-lounge/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Guide to Singapore airport lounges" /><published>2025-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-airport-lounge</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-airport-lounge/"><![CDATA[<p>Airport lounges are the magical sanctuaries that separate the well-prepared traveler from the unfortunate souls battling for a seat near the boarding gate, especially in Singapore.</p>

<p>These exclusive spaces offer everything from plush seating and free-flowing snacks to showers and even nap pods—because nothing says “I’m winning at travel” like dozing off in a private suite while others scramble for overpriced coffee. But not all lounges are created equal; some require a premium credit card, an expensive membership, or simply flying in business class (which, let’s be honest, most of us dream about but rarely book). Of course, there’s also a hierarchy within lounges—economy class travelers with access get the basics, while business class lounges serve up gourmet meals and champagne, just to remind you that there’s a whole other world beyond economy. In this guide, we’ll explore how to get into these lounges, the different memberships available, a list of Changi Airport’s best options, the top airport lounges globally, and a few truly special ones that take luxury to another level.</p>

<h3 id="what-are-airport-lounges">What are airport lounges?</h3>

<p>Airport lounges are private spaces within airports designed to offer travelers a more comfortable and exclusive experience away from the chaos of the main terminal. Depending on the lounge, you might get access to plush seating, complimentary food and drinks, high-speed Wi-Fi, showers, and even nap rooms—basically, everything you wish the airport had but only a select few can enjoy. Some lounges cater specifically to business and first-class passengers, while others allow access through memberships, credit card perks, or one-time passes. The goal? To make waiting for a flight feel less like an endurance test and more like a VIP experience. Of course, not all lounges are created equal—some are a paradise of luxury, while others barely offer more than a quiet place to sit and a bowl of instant noodles.</p>

<h3 id="benefits-of-using-airport-lounges">Benefits of using airport lounges</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Comfortable Seating – No more fighting for a spot near the charging station or sitting on the floor next to your suitcase.</li>
  <li>Free Food &amp; Drinks – Skip the overpriced airport restaurants and enjoy complimentary meals, snacks, and sometimes even champagne.</li>
  <li>Wi-Fi &amp; Workspaces – Reliable internet and quiet areas make it easier to work (or pretend to work while watching Netflix).</li>
  <li>Showers &amp; Nap Areas – Freshen up before your next flight or take a quick nap instead of dozing off in an uncomfortable terminal chair.</li>
  <li>Less Crowded &amp; More Relaxing – Escape the noisy crowds, crying babies, and endless boarding announcements for some much-needed peace and quiet.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="how-do-you-get-access-to-airport-lounges">How do you get access to airport lounges?</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Fly Business or First Class – The easiest (but priciest) way to get into a lounge—premium cabin tickets usually come with automatic access.</li>
  <li>Frequent Flyer Status – Airlines reward their elite-status travelers with lounge access, even if they’re flying economy.</li>
  <li>Credit Card Perks – High-end credit cards (like AMEX Platinum or those linked to Priority Pass) often include free lounge access.</li>
  <li>Lounge Memberships – Programs like Priority Pass, DragonPass, or airline-specific memberships grant lounge entry worldwide for an annual fee.</li>
  <li>One-Time Lounge Passes – Some lounges sell single-entry passes, letting you pay for access without needing a membership or premium ticket.</li>
  <li>Pay-Per-Use Lounges – Independent lounges in many airports allow walk-in guests who are willing to pay for a few hours of comfort.</li>
  <li>Airline Day Passes – Airlines like United and Delta sell one-time lounge passes, typically priced between $50–$75.</li>
  <li>Corporate Travel Perks – Some companies provide lounge access as part of their employee travel benefits (because business trips should feel less like work).</li>
  <li>Redeemed with miles or loyalty program milestone rewards – Some loyalty programs or airlines provide rewards or redemption opportunities for lounge access</li>
  <li>Bundled with Flight Packages – Some travel agencies and booking platforms include lounge access as a perk when purchasing certain flight deals.</li>
  <li>Friends &amp; Family Guests – If you’re traveling with someone who has lounge access, they might be able to bring you in as a guest—time to befriend a frequent flyer.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="different-airport-lounge-memberships">Different airport lounge memberships</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Priority Pass – One of the most popular lounge memberships, offering access to over 1,300 lounges worldwide, often included with premium credit cards in Singapore.</li>
  <li>DragonPass – A growing competitor to Priority Pass, providing access to lounges, dining discounts, and airport services, with some Singapore banks offering it as a perk.</li>
  <li>LoungeKey – Similar to Priority Pass but linked to select Singapore-issued credit cards, allowing access to a curated list of lounges.</li>
  <li>Airline-Specific Memberships – Many airlines offer paid lounge programs, including:</li>
  <li>Singapore Airlines KrisFlyer Gold Lounge Access – For KrisFlyer Elite Gold members and Star Alliance Gold travelers.</li>
  <li>Cathay Pacific Marco Polo Club – Higher-tier members enjoy access to Cathay Pacific lounges, including those at Changi Airport.</li>
  <li>United Club – Unlimited access to United lounges for an annual fee, with access to Star Alliance lounges, including at Changi.</li>
  <li>American Airlines Admirals Club – Lounge access for a yearly subscription or eligible credit cardholders, with partner lounge access in Singapore.</li>
  <li>American Express Centurion Lounge Membership – Exclusive to AMEX Platinum and Centurion cardholders, offering premium lounges, including Plaza Premium lounges at Changi Airport.</li>
  <li>Plaza Premium Lounge Pass – Independent lounge operator with pay-per-use and membership options, widely available in Singapore’s Changi Airport.</li>
  <li>Collinson Group Lounge Memberships – Includes programs like Lounge Pass and Lounge Club, providing access to select lounges, including in Singapore.</li>
  <li>Premium Credit Cards in Singapore – Many high-end credit cards offer complimentary or discounted lounge access, such as:</li>
  <li>AMEX Platinum &amp; Centurion – Free access to Centurion Lounges, Priority Pass, and other premium lounges, including in Singapore.</li>
  <li>Visa Infinite &amp; Mastercard World Elite – Some variations from Singapore banks offer LoungeKey or Priority Pass membership.</li>
  <li>Citi Prestige &amp; UOB Visa Infinite Metal Card – Comes with Priority Pass membership and additional travel perks at Changi Airport lounges.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="difference-between-business-class-and-economy-class-lounge">Difference between business class and economy class lounge,</h3>

<p>Access Criteria</p>
<ul>
  <li>Business Class Lounge – Reserved for Business Class and First Class passengers, as well as elite frequent flyers with Star Alliance Gold status.</li>
  <li>Economy Class Lounge (KrisFlyer Gold Lounge) – Only available to KrisFlyer Elite Gold and Star Alliance Gold members flying in Economy or Premium Economy. No access for regular Economy passengers.</li>
</ul>

<p>Quality of Food &amp; Drinks</p>
<ul>
  <li>Business Class Lounge – Offers a buffet with a variety of hot meals, gourmet snacks, and a selection of wines, champagne, and cocktails.</li>
  <li>Economy Class Lounge – More basic food options, usually limited to sandwiches, salads, instant noodles, and soft drinks (no champagne here).</li>
</ul>

<p>Seating &amp; Ambience</p>
<ul>
  <li>Business Class Lounge – Spacious, elegant seating with more privacy, comfortable lounge chairs, and a quieter atmosphere.</li>
  <li>Economy Class Lounge – More crowded, fewer seating options, and a less exclusive feel.</li>
</ul>

<p>Amenities &amp; Services</p>
<ul>
  <li>Business Class Lounge – Private shower suites, business workstations, and better relaxation areas. Some locations even have barista-made coffee.</li>
  <li>Economy Class Lounge – Basic showers, simple seating, and fewer premium services—just enough for a quick refresh.</li>
</ul>

<p>Location &amp; Space at Changi Airport</p>
<ul>
  <li>Business Class Lounge (SilverKris Lounge) – Larger, more luxurious, with separate areas for First Class and Business Class travelers.</li>
  <li>Economy Class Lounge (KrisFlyer Gold Lounge) – Smaller, fewer facilities, and doesn’t feel quite as “exclusive” compared to the SilverKris Lounge.</li>
</ul>

<p>In short, Singapore Airlines’ Business Class lounge experience is designed for luxury and comfort, while the Economy lounge is more of a functional waiting space for loyal frequent flyers. If you’re looking for champagne, gourmet meals, and premium seats—you’ll need a Business Class ticket (or at least a higher-status membership).</p>

<h3 id="list-of-lounges-in-changi-airport">List of lounges in Changi Airport</h3>

<p>Here’s a ranking of the lounges in Changi Airport, from best to worst (based on amenities, comfort, and exclusivity):</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>The Private Room (Singapore Airlines First Class)
Exclusive to Singapore Airlines First Class passengers, The Private Room offers a private, ultra-luxurious experience with a-la-carte dining, fine wines, and personal service, all in a serene, intimate setting. It is the ultimate in lounge luxury at Changi.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Cathay Pacific Lounge (Marco Polo Club)
A well-appointed lounge with a selection of food, drinks, and comfortable seating. It’s spacious, quieter than other lounges, and offers decent amenities, though not as luxurious as the SilverKris Lounge.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>British Airways Lounge
A cozy lounge offering a selection of food and beverages, with comfortable seating and a calm atmosphere. It’s a solid option, though it doesn’t compare to the more luxurious offerings in Changi, like the SilverKris Lounge or The Private Room.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>SilverKris Lounge (Singapore Airlines Business &amp; First Class)
The best lounge for Business Class and First Class travelers (who don’t have access to The Private Room). It offers luxurious seating, gourmet meals, premium bar service, private shower suites, and excellent views of the runway. There are separate sections for Business and First Class passengers, making it a top-tier experience.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>KrisFlyer Gold Lounge (Singapore Airlines Economy &amp; KrisFlyer Gold Members)
Tailored for KrisFlyer Elite Gold and Star Alliance Gold members flying in Economy or Premium Economy. It’s functional but lacks the exclusivity and food variety of the SilverKris Lounge. Still, it offers comfortable seating and snacks.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Qantas Lounge
Comfortable but simpler than others, the Qantas Lounge offers decent food, barista-made coffee, and good seating. The ambience is relaxing, but it lacks some of the luxury and variety of other lounges.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>SATS Premier Lounge
A decent lounge with basic amenities, including buffet food, drinks, and comfortable seating. It’s a good option for travelers with access, but the quality and variety of food are more limited compared to higher-ranked lounges.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Plaza Premium Lounge
A great independent lounge with various locations across Changi, offering comfortable seating, a wide selection of food and drinks, business facilities, and shower rooms. Access can be purchased or gained through memberships like Priority Pass.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<h3 id="best-airport-lounges-in-the-world-that-are-not-in-singapore">Best airport lounges in the world that are not in Singapore</h3>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>The Wing (Cathay Pacific, Hong Kong International Airport)
Known for its sleek design and high-end amenities, The Wing offers a stunning view of the runway, top-notch dining options, private cabanas, and a luxurious first-class experience with exceptional service.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>The Centurion Lounge (Multiple Locations, American Express)
With access available to American Express Platinum and Centurion cardholders, The Centurion Lounges are famous for their elegant interiors, gourmet food, high-quality drinks, and premium services like spas and shower suites. Locations in New York, London, and Hong Kong stand out.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Qatar Airways Al Mourjan Business Lounge (Hamad International Airport, Doha)
A massive, luxurious lounge with world-class dining, private sleeping pods, shower facilities, and a range of exclusive services. It’s often considered one of the best business-class lounges in the world.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Emirates First Class Lounge (Dubai International Airport)
Exclusively for First Class passengers, this lounge offers à la carte dining, a cigar lounge, and private suites. It’s a true indulgence, featuring top-tier luxury and comfort.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Air France La Première Lounge (Charles de Gaulle Airport, Paris)
The epitome of French luxury, La Première offers exquisite food, private cabins, a chic atmosphere, and personalized services, including a dedicated concierge. This lounge is exclusive to First Class passengers flying on Air France.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Singapore Airlines SilverKris Lounge (Multiple Locations)
While we’ve covered its Singapore version, the lounges in major airports like London and Hong Kong maintain the same high standard. With fine dining, comfortable seating, and luxurious amenities, it offers an exceptional experience for Business and First Class passengers.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Lufthansa First Class Terminal (Frankfurt Airport, Germany)
Exclusive to First Class passengers, this lounge includes private security screening, luxury dining, a cigar lounge, and personalized service from beginning to end. It’s an entire experience of lavishness, offering comfort and privacy.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>British Airways Concorde Room (London Heathrow Airport)
Designed exclusively for First Class passengers, this lounge has plush seating, gourmet food, fine wine, and exceptional service. The Concorde Room remains a standout due to its upscale atmosphere and exclusive amenities.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>What’s your favourite airport lounge? Let me know!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Singapore" /><category term="airport" /><category term="lounge" /><category term="travel" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Airport lounges are the magical sanctuaries that separate the well-prepared traveler from the unfortunate souls battling for a seat near the boarding gate, especially in Singapore.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/lounge.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/lounge.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Guide to Airline Alliances in Singapore</title><link href="/singapore-airline-alliances/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Guide to Airline Alliances in Singapore" /><published>2025-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-airline-alliances</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-airline-alliances/"><![CDATA[<p>If you’ve ever stared at your frequent flyer miles and wondered if you’re actually getting anything out of them, welcome to the world of airline alliances. This is a must-know for your upcoming <a href="https://fromhktosg.github.io/singapore-flights/">vacations</a>!</p>

<p>In Singapore, where Changi Airport is basically a five-star hotel with runways, picking the right airline alliance can make or break your travel perks. The big three—Star Alliance, Oneworld, and SkyTeam—each promise elite treatment, but only if you’re loyal enough (or fly enough to justify your existence to them). We’ll break down what each alliance offers, from lounge access to priority boarding, and whether they’re actually worth your commitment. And, of course, we’ll answer the golden question: which airline alliance should you really be pledging your miles to in Singapore?</p>

<h3 id="what-are-airline-alliances">What are airline alliances?</h3>

<p>Airline alliances are partnerships between multiple airlines that allow them to share routes, services, and benefits for passengers. Instead of each airline operating independently, they team up to offer perks like easier flight connections, shared frequent flyer miles, and access to airport lounges across different carriers. The three major global airline alliances—Star Alliance, Oneworld, and SkyTeam—essentially function as VIP clubs, giving travelers better treatment if they stick to the same network. For airlines, it means cost savings and a wider global reach; for passengers, it means you might actually get a decent layover experience instead of sprinting through an unfamiliar airport. In Singapore, where Changi Airport is already a traveler’s paradise, the right airline alliance can make your journeys even smoother—or at least slightly less exhausting.</p>

<h3 id="deep-dive-into-top-3-airline-alliances">Deep dive into top 3 airline alliances</h3>

<p><u>Star Alliance – The OG of Airline Alliances<u></u></u></p>

<p>Founded: 1997
Why It Matters: Star Alliance is the largest and oldest airline alliance, formed when five airlines decided they liked each other enough to team up. Today, it has the most airline members and the widest global coverage. Singapore Airlines (SIA) is a key member, meaning Star Alliance perks are highly relevant for travelers in Singapore.</p>

<p>Current Airline Partners: 26 members, including:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Singapore Airlines (Singapore)</li>
  <li>Lufthansa (Germany)</li>
  <li>United Airlines (USA)</li>
  <li>ANA (All Nippon Airways) (Japan)</li>
  <li>Thai Airways (Thailand)</li>
  <li>Turkish Airlines (Turkey)</li>
  <li>Swiss International Air Lines (Switzerland)</li>
  <li>Air Canada (Canada)
(and many more covering over 190 countries)</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Oneworld – The Premium Traveler’s Choice<u></u></u></p>

<p>Founded: 1999
Why It Matters: Oneworld was built for business travelers who care about premium perks and seamless connections. It’s smaller than Star Alliance but focuses on quality over quantity, with Cathay Pacific (Hong Kong) and Qantas (Australia) being key players in the region.</p>

<p>Current Airline Partners: 13 members, including:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Qantas (Australia)</li>
  <li>British Airways (UK)</li>
  <li>American Airlines (USA)</li>
  <li>Cathay Pacific (Hong Kong)</li>
  <li>Japan Airlines (JAL) (Japan)</li>
  <li>Finnair (Finland)</li>
  <li>Qatar Airways (Qatar)
(plus others with strong intercontinental coverage)</li>
</ul>

<p><u>SkyTeam – The Underdog That’s Still in the Game<u></u></u></p>

<p>Founded: 2000
Why It Matters: SkyTeam was the last of the three major alliances to form and often feels like the “third choice” for frequent flyers. It has strong coverage in Europe and Asia, but fewer premium perks compared to the other two. However, its focus on airlines from China and the Middle East makes it a decent option for specific routes.</p>

<p>Current Airline Partners: 18 members, including:</p>
<ul>
  <li>KLM (Netherlands)</li>
  <li>Air France (France)</li>
  <li>Korean Air (South Korea)</li>
  <li>China Eastern Airlines (China)</li>
  <li>Delta Air Lines (USA)</li>
  <li>Vietnam Airlines (Vietnam)</li>
  <li>Garuda Indonesia (Indonesia)
(and others, with strong regional ties in Europe and Asia)</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="what-are-the-star-alliance-tiers-and-benefits-would-you-get">What are the Star alliance tiers and benefits would you get?</h3>

<p><u>Star Alliance Tiers and Benefits<u></u></u></p>

<p>Star Alliance offers two elite status tiers: Star Alliance Silver and Star Alliance Gold. These are earned through your frequent flyer status with individual member airlines—so if you’re flying Singapore Airlines, for example, your KrisFlyer Elite Silver or PPS Club status translates into Star Alliance perks.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Star Alliance Silver – The “Nice Try” Tier</li>
</ol>

<p>This is the lower-tier status, and, well… don’t expect much. The benefits are minimal, and you’ll still feel like a regular passenger most of the time.
Benefits:
✅ Priority waitlisting – If your flight is fully booked, you might get a seat before non-status passengers. Might.
✅ Priority standby – If you need to change your flight last-minute, you may get a better spot on the waitlist.</p>

<p>What’s missing?
❌ No lounge access
❌ No priority check-in or boarding
❌ No extra baggage allowance</p>

<ol>
  <li>Star Alliance Gold – The “Finally, Some Respect” Tier</li>
</ol>

<p>This is where things get better. Star Alliance Gold is the real reason people chase status—it actually gives you perks that make traveling less of a hassle.</p>

<p>Benefits:
✅ Lounge access – Free access to over 1,000 Star Alliance lounges worldwide, no matter what cabin class you’re flying. (Yes, even if you’re in economy!)
✅ Priority check-in – Use the business class or first-class check-in counters even if you’re flying economy.
✅ Extra baggage allowance – Usually an extra 20kg or one extra piece of luggage (varies by airline).
✅ Priority boarding – Skip the long queue and board early with business and first-class passengers.
✅ Priority baggage handling – Your bags come out first at baggage claim, so you can leave the airport faster.
✅ Priority standby and waitlisting – More likely to get on an earlier or oversold flight.</p>

<p><u>How to Earn Star Alliance Status in Singapore?<u></u></u></p>

<p>For Singapore-based travelers, your best bet is through Singapore Airlines’ KrisFlyer program:</p>
<ul>
  <li>KrisFlyer Elite Silver → Star Alliance Silver (not really worth the effort)</li>
  <li>KrisFlyer Elite Gold or PPS Club/Solitaire PPS Club → Star Alliance Gold (this is the one you want!)</li>
</ul>

<p>If you fly often with Singapore Airlines or other Star Alliance carriers, reaching Gold status can make your trips much smoother. But if you’re stuck at Silver, don’t expect anything more than a pat on the back.</p>

<h3 id="what-are-the-one-world-tiers-and-benefits-would-you-get">What are the One World tiers and benefits would you get?</h3>

<p><u>Oneworld Tiers and Benefits<u></u></u></p>

<p>Oneworld has three elite status tiers: Oneworld Ruby, Sapphire, and Emerald. Unlike Star Alliance, where the lower-tier Silver status is almost useless, Oneworld actually offers decent perks even at the mid-tier levels.
Your Oneworld status is based on your frequent flyer status with member airlines. For example, if you fly Qantas, British Airways, or Cathay Pacific, their elite tiers translate into Oneworld benefits.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Oneworld Ruby – The “Better Than Nothing” Tier
This is the entry-level status, and while it’s not much, at least you get some priority treatment.</li>
</ol>

<p>Benefits:
✅ Business class check-in counters – Even if you’re flying economy, you can skip the long economy check-in lines.
✅ Priority waitlisting – If your flight is full, you might get a seat before non-status passengers.
✅ Priority standby – If you need to change your flight, you get priority over others on the waitlist.</p>

<p>What’s missing?
❌ No lounge access
❌ No priority boarding
❌ No extra baggage allowance</p>

<p><u>How to get Oneworld Ruby in Singapore?<u>
Cathay Pacific Marco Polo Club Silver
Qantas Frequent Flyer Silver</u></u></p>

<ol>
  <li>Oneworld Sapphire – The “Now We’re Talking” Tier
This is the mid-tier status, and it’s where the real benefits start kicking in.</li>
</ol>

<p>Benefits:
✅ Lounge access – Free access to over 600 Oneworld Business Class lounges worldwide, even if you’re flying economy.
✅ Priority check-in – Use business class check-in counters.
✅ Priority boarding – Board early with business class passengers.
✅ Extra baggage allowance – Typically an extra checked bag or extra weight, depending on the airline.
✅ Priority baggage handling – Your bags come out first at baggage claim.</p>

<p>How to get Oneworld Sapphire in Singapore?
Cathay Pacific Marco Polo Club Gold
Qantas Frequent Flyer Gold</p>

<ol>
  <li>Oneworld Emerald – The “Now You’re Basically Royalty” Tier
This is the highest tier, and it gets you nearly the same perks as first-class passengers, no matter what ticket you have.</li>
</ol>

<p>Benefits:
✅ First-class lounge access – You can use first-class lounges, including the famous Qantas First Lounge in Changi Airport.
✅ Priority security and immigration – Some airports have fast-track lanes for Emerald members.
✅ First-class check-in – Skip the lines entirely and check in where actual first-class passengers do.
✅ Priority boarding – Board first, before everyone else.
✅ Extra baggage allowance – More weight or extra checked bags, depending on the airline.
✅ Priority baggage handling – Your bags are among the first to arrive at baggage claim.</p>

<p><u>How to get Oneworld Emerald in Singapore?<u>
Cathay Pacific Marco Polo Club Diamond
Qantas Frequent Flyer Platinum</u></u></p>

<p><u>Is Oneworld Status Worth It in Singapore?<u></u></u></p>

<p>If you travel frequently with Qantas, Cathay Pacific, or Japan Airlines, Oneworld status is worth considering. The real sweet spot is Sapphire, since that gets you lounge access even on economy tickets. But if you’re lucky enough to reach Emerald, you’ll be skipping lines and sipping champagne in first-class lounges while everyone else fights for overhead bin space.</p>

<h3 id="what-are-the-skyteam-tiers-and-benefits-would-you-get">What are the SkyTeam tiers and benefits would you get?</h3>

<p><u>SkyTeam Tiers and Benefits<u></u></u></p>

<p>SkyTeam keeps things simple with just two elite tiers: SkyTeam Elite and SkyTeam Elite Plus. While it doesn’t have as many perks as Oneworld or Star Alliance, SkyTeam still offers some useful benefits—especially if you fly with partners like Korean Air, China Eastern, or Vietnam Airlines from Singapore.</p>

<p>Your SkyTeam status depends on your frequent flyer program. For example, if you fly with Korean Air’s SKYPASS, your elite status gets mapped to SkyTeam’s benefits.</p>

<ol>
  <li>SkyTeam Elite – The “Okay, You Exist” Tier
This is the entry-level status, and while it’s better than nothing, it’s not exactly life-changing.</li>
</ol>

<p>Benefits:
✅ Priority check-in – Use the dedicated SkyTeam Elite check-in counters instead of the long economy lines.
✅ Priority boarding – Board early, though usually after business class and Elite Plus members.
✅ Extra baggage allowance – Usually an extra 10kg or one additional checked bag.
✅ Priority standby and waitlisting – You have a better chance of getting a seat on full flights.</p>

<p>What’s missing?
❌ No lounge access
❌ No priority security or immigration
❌ No priority baggage handling</p>

<p><u>How to get SkyTeam Elite in Singapore?<u>
Korean Air SKYPASS Morning Calm Club
Vietnam Airlines Lotusmiles Gold
China Eastern Eastern Miles Gold</u></u></p>

<ol>
  <li>SkyTeam Elite Plus – The “Finally, Some Real Perks” Tier
This is the top-tier status, and it’s where things start getting comfortable.</li>
</ol>

<p>Benefits:
✅ Lounge access – Free access to 750+ SkyTeam lounges worldwide, even when flying economy.
✅ Priority check-in – Use the business class check-in counters.
✅ Priority boarding – Board earlier than most other passengers.
✅ Extra baggage allowance – Typically an additional checked bag or extra weight.
✅ Priority baggage handling – Your luggage comes out first at baggage claim.
✅ Priority security and immigration – Some airports have fast-track lanes for Elite Plus members.
✅ Guaranteed seat on sold-out flights – On certain fares, they’ll find you a seat even if the flight is full.</p>

<p><u>How to get SkyTeam Elite Plus in Singapore?<u>
Korean Air SKYPASS Morning Calm Premium Club or higher
Vietnam Airlines Lotusmiles Platinum
China Eastern Eastern Miles Platinum</u></u></p>

<p><u>Is SkyTeam Status Worth It in Singapore?<u></u></u></p>

<p>If you fly Korean Air or Vietnam Airlines often, SkyTeam Elite Plus is nice to have for the lounge access and priority treatment. But compared to Star Alliance (with Singapore Airlines) or Oneworld (with Cathay Pacific and Qantas), SkyTeam isn’t as dominant in Singapore. So unless you love flying to Seoul or Shanghai, you might not find this alliance as rewarding.</p>

<h3 id="how-do-you-select-airline-alliances-to-be-a-part-of">How do you select airline alliances to be a part of?</h3>

<p><u>How to Choose the Right Airline Alliance<u></u></u></p>

<p>Picking the right airline alliance isn’t just about collecting miles—it’s about maximizing perks, convenience, and value. Here’s how to decide which one works best for you:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Look at Your Most Frequent Airlines
If you mainly fly Singapore Airlines, Star Alliance is the obvious choice.
If you travel often with Cathay Pacific or Qantas, Oneworld is a better fit.
If you fly to Korea, China, or Vietnam often, SkyTeam might be worth considering.</li>
</ol>

<p>Your alliance choice should align with your home airport and preferred routes.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Compare Lounge Access and Perks</li>
</ol>

<p>Star Alliance Gold: Gets you into over 1,000+ lounges, including KrisFlyer Gold Lounges.
Oneworld Sapphire/Emerald: Business and First Class lounges, even on economy tickets.
SkyTeam Elite Plus: Lounge access, but fewer high-end lounge options compared to Oneworld.</p>

<p>If you value luxury and priority treatment, Oneworld Emerald is the strongest.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Check the Elite Status Benefits That Matter Most</li>
</ol>

<p>Do you want extra baggage? → All alliances offer it, but Star Alliance is the most generous.
Do you care about priority check-in/security? → Oneworld Emerald has the best fast-track benefits.
Do you want guaranteed seats on sold-out flights? → SkyTeam Elite Plus offers this on certain fares.</p>

<p>Are you flying budget airlines a lot? → None of these will help—you’ll need individual airline memberships.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Consider How Easy It Is to Earn and Keep Status</li>
</ol>

<p>Singapore Airlines’ KrisFlyer status resets annually, making it harder to maintain.
Qantas and Cathay Pacific have more flexible status rules with rolling qualification periods.
SkyTeam programs like Korean Air SKYPASS require more long-haul flights to qualify.</p>

<p>If you don’t fly often but want lifetime benefits, some programs (like SKYPASS) offer lifetime elite status.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Think About Redemption Value and Partner Flights</li>
</ol>

<p>Star Alliance has the biggest network (26 airlines), great for long-haul trips.
Oneworld miles are easier to redeem for business and first-class awards.
SkyTeam often has poor redemption availability—using miles for upgrades is harder.</p>

<p>If you travel a lot and want flexibility, Star Alliance gives the most options.</p>

<p>Bottom line: Choose the alliance that matches your travel patterns, gives you the best perks, and has partners that actually fly where you need to go.</p>

<h3 id="which-airline-alliance-is-best-for-singapore">Which airline alliance is best for Singapore?</h3>

<p>Most people in Singapore choose Star Alliance—and it’s not hard to see why. With Singapore Airlines (SQ) as a founding member, Star Alliance dominates Changi Airport, offering the most flights, lounges, and perks. But not everyone starts fresh in Singapore. If you’ve moved here from Hong Kong, Australia, or even Europe, you might already have elite status with Oneworld or SkyTeam, making it harder to switch.</p>

<p>For example, I stuck with Oneworld Sapphire for a long time because of Marco Polo Gold with Cathay Pacific. It gave me lounge access, priority check-in, and extra baggage—perks I didn’t want to give up even after moving to Singapore. Similarly, frequent travelers from Korea or China might find SkyTeam Elite Plus more useful if they still fly with Korean Air or China Eastern often.
So while Star Alliance is the default winner for most Singapore-based flyers, some people keep their Oneworld or SkyTeam loyalty because of past status and travel patterns. The best choice? Stick with what gives you the most perks based on your usual routes and airlines—even if it’s not Star Alliance.</p>

<p>We’ll cover the miles game in a separate note, but remember, the miles and alliance game is a personal choice. Let me know what alliance you all are in</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Singapore" /><category term="airline" /><category term="loyalty" /><category term="miles" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’ve ever stared at your frequent flyer miles and wondered if you’re actually getting anything out of them, welcome to the world of airline alliances. This is a must-know for your upcoming vacations!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/alliance.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/alliance.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Guide to Japan onsen travel</title><link href="/singapore-japan-onsen-tokyo/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Guide to Japan onsen travel" /><published>2025-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-japan-onsen-tokyo</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-japan-onsen-tokyo/"><![CDATA[<p>We know Singaporeans love going to Japan. If you’ve ever dreamed of soaking in a hot spring or onsen while pretending you’re in a serene Japanese ryokan, you’re not alone.</p>

<p>Onsens, Japan’s natural hot springs, aren’t just for relaxation; they’re practically a cultural experience, offering everything from therapeutic benefits to a great excuse to let your mind wander while you sit in glorified boiling water. Whether you’re opting for the traditional full experience in a ryokan or just day-tripping to a local onsen, there’s something about those steamy waters that make you feel like you’re doing something good for your body—even if all you’re really doing is sitting there. From health benefits like improved circulation to the variety of onsens—from public baths to luxurious resort-style ones—there’s something to suit every mood, day or night. So, are there any onsens in Singapore that can compare to Japan’s? Well, let’s just say we might not have Mount Fuji nearby, but there’s always a chance to dip your toes into a little hot water.</p>

<h3 id="what-are-onsens">What are onsens?</h3>

<p>Onsens are natural hot springs found in Japan, created by geothermal activity that heats the water, making it perfect for bathing. These springs are rich in minerals like sulfur, sodium, and calcium, which are believed to have therapeutic effects on the body, helping with ailments like joint pain, skin conditions, and stress. People flock to onsens not just for the healing properties of the water but for the whole experience—taking time to relax, unwind, and connect with nature in a serene environment. Onsens can be found in both public baths and private settings, often nestled in scenic areas like mountains or forests, providing a peaceful escape. Whether you’re soaking in a rustic outdoor bath or indulging in a luxurious resort-style onsen, the practice is deeply woven into Japanese culture.</p>

<h3 id="what-are-ryokans">What are ryokans?</h3>

<p>Ryokans are traditional Japanese inns that offer a unique and immersive cultural experience. Staying in a ryokan is like stepping back in time, where you get to enjoy tatami mat floors, sliding paper doors, and futon beds laid out for you at night. The real draw, though, is the hospitality—often, ryokans include kaiseki meals (a multi-course feast) and access to private onsens, making it an all-in-one retreat. These inns are located in scenic areas, sometimes close to onsens, giving you the perfect mix of relaxation and tradition. It’s the ultimate way to experience Japan’s famous blend of simplicity and elegance, with a touch of “you’ll never want to leave” comfort.</p>

<h3 id="history-of-ryokans-and-onsens">History of ryokans and onsens</h3>

<p>Ryokans and onsens have deep roots in Japanese history, both playing crucial roles in the country’s cultural and social fabric. Ryokans date back to the 8th century during the Nara period, originally serving as resting spots for travelers along Japan’s ancient roads. Over time, these inns evolved into luxurious retreats, offering not only a place to stay but a way to experience traditional Japanese customs, food, and hospitality. On the other hand, onsens have been used for thousands of years, with their therapeutic properties first recognized as early as the 8th century as well. They became especially popular during the Edo period (1603-1868) when people began to frequent them for both health reasons and relaxation. Together, ryokans and onsens have become symbols of Japanese culture, offering both locals and tourists a way to unwind, enjoy nature, and connect with centuries-old traditions.</p>

<h3 id="why-do-people-like-going-to-onsens">Why do people like going to onsens?</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Relaxation – The warm, mineral-rich waters soothe sore muscles and ease tension, offering a calming escape from daily stress. Onsen water temperatures typically range from 38°C to 42°C (100°F to 108°F), providing the perfect balance between comfort and therapeutic warmth.</li>
  <li>Health Benefits – Onsen waters are rich in minerals like sulfur, sodium chloride, and calcium, which are believed to help with a variety of health conditions. Regular soaking can improve blood circulation, alleviate muscle and joint pain, and promote detoxification. Sulfur-rich baths, for instance, are known for their skin-healing properties and can help treat conditions like eczema and psoriasis.</li>
  <li>Nature Immersion – Many onsens are located in scenic areas, allowing bathers to enjoy natural beauty while unwinding. The calming environment is scientifically shown to lower stress hormone levels and promote a sense of overall well-being.</li>
  <li>Cultural Experience – The rituals involved in bathing at an onsen, such as thoroughly cleaning before soaking, offer a unique chance to immerse in Japanese tradition. The process itself encourages mindfulness, which has been linked to reduced anxiety and improved mental health.</li>
  <li>Self-Care – It’s a guilt-free excuse to relax and do nothing, all while feeling like you’re indulging in wellness and rejuvenation. Studies have shown that thermal baths can improve sleep quality and even boost immune function, making an onsen visit feel even more rewarding.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="risks-of-going-to-onsens--when-should-you-not-go-to-an-onsen">Risks of going to onsens / when should you not go to an onsen</h3>

<p>While onsens offer a lot of benefits, there are some risks and situations where it’s best to avoid them:</p>

<ul>
  <li>High-Temperature Sensitivity – If you’re sensitive to heat or have a condition like high blood pressure or heart problems, the hot water can be overwhelming and cause dizziness or fainting. It’s important to listen to your body and avoid prolonged soaking in very hot water.</li>
  <li>Pregnancy – Pregnant women should avoid onsens, especially those with very hot water, as the heat can raise body temperature and potentially harm the fetus. Some onsens have specific pools for expectant mothers, but it’s safest to consult a doctor before going.</li>
  <li>Open Wounds or Skin Infections – If you have open cuts, wounds, or active skin infections like rashes or boils, it’s best to stay out of the onsen. The hot water can irritate wounds and potentially introduce bacteria.</li>
  <li>Alcohol Consumption – Going into an onsen after drinking alcohol can increase the risk of dehydration, overheating, or fainting due to the combination of alcohol and the hot water. It’s better to enjoy your soak when sober.</li>
  <li>Medical Conditions – If you have conditions like diabetes, respiratory issues, or circulatory problems, consult a doctor before entering an onsen, as hot water can exacerbate certain health concerns.</li>
</ul>

<p>As a general rule, always remember to stay hydrated, limit your soaking time, and be mindful of how your body reacts to the heat. If you’re feeling unwell, it’s best to skip the onsen altogether.</p>

<h3 id="etiquettes-of-going-to-an-onsen">Etiquettes of going to an onsen</h3>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Shower First – Always wash and thoroughly rinse your body before entering the onsen. There is generally a designated area with shower stations for this purpose, equipped with stools, handheld showerheads, and soap. This is not only for hygiene but also a sign of respect for other bathers.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Keep Your Hair Out of the Water – If you have long hair, tie it up to avoid it touching the water. Wet hair can transfer dirt and oils into the bath.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Avoid Loud Noise – Keep conversations quiet and respectful. Onsens are meant to be peaceful, relaxing spaces.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>No Diving or Splashing – Don’t splash water or engage in any vigorous movement. Relaxing is key, not swimming or playing around.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Don’t Soak for Too Long – Limit your soak to around 15-20 minutes at a time. Too long can cause overheating and dehydration.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Towels Stay Outside – Bring a small towel for washing, but leave it outside the onsen when you soak. It’s considered impolite to bring it into the water.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>No Photography – Keep your phone and camera away to maintain the peaceful, private nature of the onsen and respect the privacy of others.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Be Respectful of Others’ Space – Onsens can be communal, so be mindful of personal space and avoid crowding other bathers.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Avoid Using Soap in the Bath – Soap should only be used during your pre-bath shower, not in the onsen itself.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Rinse After Soaking – After enjoying the onsen, rinse off any residual minerals from your body. This helps cleanse your skin and closes your pores.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<h3 id="why-do-they-give-you-a-little-face-towel-in-the-onsen">Why do they give you a little face towel in the onsen?</h3>

<p>The little towel given at the onsen serves several practical and cultural purposes:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Use to Wash Your Body in the Shower – You can use the towel to scrub and rinse your body during the pre-bath shower, helping with personal hygiene before entering the onsen. There is generally a designated area with shower stations for this purpose, equipped with stools, handheld showerheads, and soap. This ensures you’re thoroughly clean before soaking in the communal bath.</li>
  <li>Use to Wipe Sweat When in the Hot Bath – While soaking in the onsen, you can place the towel on your head or use it to wipe off sweat. This helps keep you comfortable while relaxing in the hot water.</li>
  <li>Use to Hide Your Body When Walking From One Bath to Another – The towel provides modesty as you move between bath areas. While you don’t bring it into the water, it’s a simple way to cover up while walking between different sections of the onsen.</li>
  <li>Use to Dry Off Before Stepping Back into the Changing Area – After your soak, the towel can be used to gently pat yourself dry before returning to the changing area, ensuring you don’t drip water onto the floor.</li>
</ul>

<p>The towel is a small but essential part of the onsen experience, helping maintain hygiene, respect for others, and adding to the overall cultural tradition.</p>

<h3 id="what-type-of-onsens-are-there">What type of onsens are there?</h3>

<p>There are several types of onsens, each offering a unique experience:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Indoor Onsens (内湯, Uchiyu) – These are located inside buildings and are typically more private. They’re great for colder weather or those who prefer a more controlled environment. Indoor onsens often have beautifully tiled baths and a serene atmosphere.</li>
  <li>Outdoor Onsens (露天風呂, Rotenburo) – These are the iconic onsens that offer natural settings, with views of mountains, forests, or rivers. Soaking in an outdoor onsen, especially in cooler weather, provides a soothing contrast to the heat of the water.</li>
  <li>Private Onsens (貸切風呂, Kashikiri-buro) – These are smaller, more intimate baths that can be reserved for individuals or couples. They provide the experience of an onsen without the crowd, making them perfect for those who prefer privacy.</li>
  <li>Public Onsens (大浴場, Daiyokujou) – These are communal baths, often in large, open spaces where you can enjoy the onsen with other bathers. Public onsens are the most traditional and common in Japan.</li>
  <li>Day Onsens (日帰り温泉, Higaeri Onsen) – These are onsens that you can visit during the day, often included as part of a larger resort or hotel experience. They’re perfect for a relaxing afternoon soak and are sometimes combined with lunch or other wellness activities.</li>
  <li>Night Onsens (夜の温泉, Yoru no Onsen) – Some onsens are particularly magical at night, with tranquil, dimly-lit environments that enhance the sense of peace. Nighttime onsens offer a calm, almost mystical experience, where you can soak under the stars or in a quiet, candlelit room.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="where-are-the-onsens-in-japan">Where are the onsens in Japan?</h3>

<p>Onsens can be found all over Japan, from the snowy mountains of Hokkaido to the tropical islands of Okinawa. They’re such a significant part of Japanese culture that it’s impossible to avoid them—whether you’re in bustling cities or remote villages, you’ll likely come across one. Some famous onsen towns include:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Hakone (箱根) – Just outside Tokyo, Hakone is a popular destination for those looking to enjoy onsens with views of Mount Fuji.</li>
  <li>Beppu (別府) – Located on the island of Kyushu, Beppu is famous for its numerous hot spring resorts, offering a wide variety of bathing experiences.</li>
  <li>Ibusuki (指宿) – Known for its unique sand baths, where you are buried in warm sand while soaking up the therapeutic heat.</li>
  <li>Kusatsu (草津) – One of Japan’s most famous onsen towns, Kusatsu in Gunma Prefecture is known for its high-quality sulfuric waters.</li>
  <li>Gero (下呂) – Gero Onsen, in Gifu Prefecture, is often ranked as one of Japan’s top three onsens, with a charming, traditional town vibe.</li>
</ul>

<p>While these towns are well-known, onsens are found virtually everywhere across the country. Whether you’re near the city or in the countryside, there’s always an onsen waiting to provide relaxation and rejuvenation.</p>

<h3 id="top-onsen-towns-in-japan-near-tokyo">Top onsen towns in Japan near Tokyo</h3>

<p>Here are some top onsens within two hours of Tokyo, offering a mix of convenience and relaxation, all accessible by shinkansen:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Hakone (箱根) – Located about 1 hour from Tokyo, Hakone is the quintessential onsen destination near Tokyo, known for its beautiful views of Mount Fuji and numerous onsen resorts. You’ll find both indoor and outdoor onsens surrounded by lush nature. Accessible via the Odakyu Romancecar or the JR Tōkaidō Shinkansen.</li>
  <li>Izu (伊豆) – About 1.5 to 2 hours from Tokyo, Izu is famous for its seaside onsens and scenic hot spring resorts, where you can enjoy a soak with views of the ocean. Many ryokan (traditional inns) here also offer private onsen experiences. Reachable via the JR Tōkaidō Shinkansen to Atami, then transfer to local trains.</li>
  <li>Kamakura (鎌倉) – Just 1 hour from Tokyo, Kamakura is primarily known for its temples and beaches, but it also has a few hidden onsens. The hot springs here offer a quieter retreat compared to Hakone or Izu. Accessible by JR Yokosuka Line or Enoden.</li>
  <li>Atami (熱海) – Only about 40 minutes from Tokyo, Atami has been a famous onsen town since the Meiji era. You can enjoy baths overlooking the ocean or in peaceful garden settings. Easily accessible via the JR Tōkaidō Shinkansen.</li>
  <li>Minakami (水上) – About 1.5 to 2 hours from Tokyo, Minakami is a great choice for those looking for outdoor and indoor onsens, set amidst the mountains. It’s perfect for soaking after a day of hiking or skiing. Reachable via the JR Jōetsu Shinkansen to + Jōetsu-Myōkō Station, then transfer to a local train.</li>
  <li>Kusatsu (草津) – Located just over 2 hours from Tokyo, Kusatsu is renowned for its sulfur-rich waters and the famous Yubatake (hot water fields) in the center of town. Accessible via the JR Tōkaidō Shinkansen to Takasaki Station, followed by a bus or limited express train to Kusatsu.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="top-100-onsen-ranking-in-japan-and-the-top-5-ryokans">Top 100 onsen ranking in Japan and the top 5 Ryokans</h3>

<p>The Top 100 Ryokan Rankings in Japan is a prestigious list that typically features the finest traditional inns (ryokan) across the country, selected for their exceptional qualities such as service, ambiance, location, and cuisine. This ranking is often compiled by various travel magazines, online platforms, and luxury hospitality organizations like Rurubu, Jalan.net, and The Michelin Guide. However, the full list of Top 100 Ryokan can vary slightly depending on the publication, and there is no single official ranking recognized by all sources.</p>

<p>That being said, here’s a summary of top-ranked ryokan from widely acknowledged sources that often make the cut into these “Top 100” lists. These ryokan are regularly praised for their stunning locations, elegant architecture, luxurious service, and immersion into Japanese culture.</p>

<p>General Criteria for Ranking Top 100 Ryokan:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Location – Scenic beauty, proximity to nature, and access to hot springs (onsen).</li>
  <li>Service – The quality of service, the traditional Japanese concept of omotenashi (hospitality), and guest satisfaction.</li>
  <li>Cuisine – The quality and presentation of kaiseki (multi-course) meals using fresh, seasonal ingredients.</li>
  <li>Architecture and Ambiance – Traditional Japanese architecture, including tatami mats, sliding doors, and design that harmonizes with the environment.</li>
  <li>Private and Public Baths – The variety and quality of onsen baths, including the presence of outdoor baths and private baths.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="notable-top-100-ryokan-in-japan">Notable Top 100 Ryokan in Japan</h3>

<p>Here are some of the best-known and consistently ranked ryokan that often appear in various Top 100 lists:</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Gora Kadan (強羅花壇) – Hakone, Kanagawa
Often seen as one of Japan’s top luxury ryokan, this former imperial family retreat features both public and private onsens, modern amenities, and gorgeous gardens.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Ibusuki Hakusuikan (指宿白水館) – Ibusuki, Kagoshima
Known for its unique sand baths and serene surroundings, Ibusuki Hakusuikan offers one of the most relaxing onsen experiences.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Tawaraya Ryokan (俵屋) – Kyoto
One of the oldest and most historic ryokan in Japan, Tawaraya is often regarded as the epitome of traditional Japanese hospitality, featuring luxurious rooms and gourmet kaiseki cuisine.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Hoshinoya Kyoto (星のや京都) – Kyoto
Set in the beautiful Arashiyama district, this ryokan blends traditional aesthetics with modern luxury, offering private baths and stunning river views.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Kusatsu Hotel (草津ホテル) – Kusatsu, Gunma
Kusatsu is a famous onsen town, and Kusatsu Hotel is regarded for its rich sulfuric waters and healing properties, alongside traditional ryokan comforts.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Yama-no-yu (山の湯) – Gero, Gifu
Located in the renowned Gero Onsen, this ryokan is famous for its scenic beauty, impeccable service, and both indoor and outdoor baths.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Amanemu (アマネム) – Shima, Mie Prefecture
A luxurious resort-style ryokan, known for its exclusive hot spring experiences, private onsen baths, and connection with nature in a beautiful coastal setting.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Kyo-no-ya (京乃家) – Kyoto
A traditional ryokan with a deep historical connection to Kyoto, offering guests a peaceful retreat with private baths, tea ceremonies, and gourmet dining.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Yuzanso (湯山荘) – Hakone, Kanagawa
Set in the famous hot spring town of Hakone, this ryokan offers luxury accommodations with spacious rooms, scenic baths, and outstanding Japanese cuisine.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Ryokan Sumiya Kiho-an (旅館 すみや紀芳庵) – Kusatsu, Gunma
Known for offering a traditional Japanese onsen experience, Ryokan Sumiya Kiho-an features high-end services, private baths, and seasonal delicacies.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p><u>Top 100 Ryokan Features<u></u></u></p>

<p>Beyond the most famous names listed, the Top 100 Ryokan Rankings also feature a range of establishments that offer unique experiences such as:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Private baths (some even with views of Mt. Fuji or lush nature)</li>
  <li>Seasonal experiences such as autumn foliage viewing or cherry blossom season</li>
  <li>Innovative dining: Many top ryokan emphasize kaiseki-style meals, offering a refined multi-course feast based on local seasonal ingredients.</li>
  <li>Holistic wellness: Some of the ryokan cater to wellness tourism, offering traditional healing therapies, massages, and the benefits of sulfuric hot spring baths.</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Finding the Full List<u></u></u></p>

<p>For the full and updated list of the top 100 ryokan, many travel guides, websites, and publications focus on luxury accommodations in Japan. Some places you can check for rankings or inspiration or to book include:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Rurubu (a leading travel guide in Japan)</li>
  <li>Jalan.net (a major Japanese hotel and ryokan booking site)</li>
  <li>The Michelin Guide (select ryokan are awarded stars for their services)</li>
  <li>Travel agencies and blogs (such as Japan National Tourism Organization, Japan Guide, or local tour operators)</li>
</ul>

<p>By consulting these sources, you’ll be able to find a wealth of recommendations, from historic, budget-friendly ryokan to the most lavish 5-star options.</p>

<h3 id="are-there-any-onsens-in-singapore">Are there any onsens in Singapore?</h3>

<p>There are a few onsen experiences in Singapore, though they are not quite as abundant as in Japan. While Singapore doesn’t have natural hot spring resorts like those in Japan, it does have on-the-rise spa centers and wellness facilities that offer similar experiences to what you would find in an onsen. Here are a few places to check out:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Yunomori Onsen &amp; Spa</li>
</ol>

<p>Location: Kallang Wave Mall
This is probably the most authentic onsen experience in Singapore. Yunomori features Japanese-style hot spring baths, including indoor and outdoor baths, a dry sauna, and a mud bath. While the waters aren’t natural hot springs, they provide a very similar relaxation experience.
Special Feature: Their wellness packages include spa treatments, massage, and relaxation therapies.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Samsara Wellness</li>
</ol>

<p>Location: Queen Street
Samsara Wellness offers a unique blend of traditional Japanese onsen and modern wellness services. You can enjoy private onsen experiences along with body treatments that replicate the onsen experience.
Special Feature: They focus on combining natural treatments and relaxation with a Japanese-inspired aesthetic.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Aloha Sea Sports &amp; Onsen</li>
</ol>

<p>Location: East Coast
Although this is primarily a water sports center, they have onsen-style bathing areas in their wellness facilities that allow you to unwind after physical activity.
Special Feature: The onsen baths are designed to help soothe tired muscles and provide relaxation after outdoor activities.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Spa Infinity</li>
</ol>

<p>Location: Orchard Road
While not an onsen per se, Spa Infinity offers experiences inspired by Japanese onsen, featuring a hot bath and relaxation treatments.
Special Feature: It focuses on combining high-tech wellness treatments with Japanese-inspired traditions.</p>

<h3 id="why-arent-there-more-onsens-in-singapore">Why Aren’t There More Onsens in Singapore?</h3>

<p>Singapore’s geological structure doesn’t support natural hot springs, so man-made onsen-like experiences are the closest option for those craving a taste of Japanese culture and relaxation. However, these spa centers do a pretty good job of recreating the onsen ambiance, making them great places for those looking to unwind in a familiar bathhouse atmosphere.
While the onsen culture in Singapore is still developing, these experiences are becoming more popular as people search for unique wellness opportunities in the city. Happy onsen!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Singapore" /><category term="Japan" /><category term="travel" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We know Singaporeans love going to Japan. If you’ve ever dreamed of soaking in a hot spring or onsen while pretending you’re in a serene Japanese ryokan, you’re not alone.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/onsen.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/onsen.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Guide to Singapore Uniqlo shopping</title><link href="/singapore-uniqlo/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Guide to Singapore Uniqlo shopping" /><published>2025-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-uniqlo</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-uniqlo/"><![CDATA[<p>In a country where <a href="https://fromhktosg.github.io/shopping-in-singapore/">shopping malls</a> multiply faster than your laundry pile, Uniqlo has somehow managed to colonize virtually every major retail space in Singapore with its minimalist Japanese fashion empire.</p>

<p>What started as a modest purveyor of basics has evolved into Singapore’s go-to sanctuary for people who want to look put-together without looking like they’re trying too hard (and yes, we’re all guilty of owning at least five of their AIRism shirts). From the endless maze of outlets dotting our tiny island to their suspiciously addictive collaborations that make you question your financial decisions, this guide will walk you through everything you need to know about Singapore’s favorite Japanese casual wear retailer. Whether you’re a Uniqlo veteran who can spot a Heat Tech sale from a mile away, or a newcomer wondering why everyone seems to be wearing the same beige linen shirt, consider this your definitive playbook to mastering the art of Uniqlo shopping in Singapore. Between their strategic store locations that seem to follow you everywhere you go and their prices that make you wonder if you really need to eat this week, let’s dive into the wonderfully predictable world of Uniqlo Singapore.</p>

<h3 id="what-is-uniqlo">What is Uniqlo?</h3>

<p>Uniqlo is a Japanese casual wear brand known for its affordable, high-quality, and minimalist clothing. It specializes in simple, functional designs with innovative fabric technologies like HEATTECH (for warmth), AIRism (for breathability), and Ultra Light Down (for lightweight insulation).</p>

<p><u>History of Uniqlo<u></u></u></p>

<p>Uniqlo was founded in 1949 in Ube, Yamaguchi, Japan, originally as a textiles company called Ogori Shoji. In 1984, it rebranded and opened its first “Unique Clothing Warehouse” in Hiroshima, which was later shortened to Uniqlo. The brand expanded rapidly in Japan and internationally, becoming a global powerhouse under its parent company, Fast Retailing.</p>

<p><u>Uniqlo in Singapore<u></u></u></p>

<p>Uniqlo entered Singapore in 2009, opening its first store at Tampines 1. The brand quickly gained popularity due to its stylish yet practical clothing suited for Singapore’s tropical climate. Today, Uniqlo has more than 20 stores across the island, including flagship locations at Orchard Central and Jewel Changi Airport, as well as a strong online presence.</p>

<h3 id="ut-vs-uniqlo">UT vs Uniqlo</h3>

<p><u>UT vs Uniqlo – What’s the Difference?<u></u></u></p>

<p>Uniqlo is the overall brand, offering minimalist, functional clothing for everyday wear. UT (Uniqlo T-Shirts) is a sub-label that focuses on graphic T-shirts featuring collaborations with artists, pop culture icons, and brands.</p>

<p>Key Differences</p>

<ul>
  <li>Main Focus: Uniqlo specializes in simple, everyday essentials, while UT is all about bold graphic T-shirts.</li>
  <li>Product Range: Uniqlo offers a wide variety of clothing, including T-shirts, jeans, jackets, and innerwear, whereas UT mainly features T-shirts, with occasional sweatshirts and hoodies.</li>
  <li>Style: Uniqlo sticks to minimalist designs with solid colors and classic cuts, while UT embraces pop culture, art, and streetwear aesthetics.</li>
  <li>Collaborations: Uniqlo rarely collaborates outside of functional innovations like HEATTECH and AIRism, but UT frequently partners with brands like Pokémon, Marvel, Studio Ghibli, and artists like KAWS.</li>
  <li>Target Audience: Uniqlo caters to those looking for timeless basics, while UT attracts fans of pop culture, streetwear, and limited-edition designs.</li>
</ul>

<p>UT collections are often limited edition, making them highly sought after, while Uniqlo’s mainline clothing focuses on versatility and longevity.</p>

<h3 id="what-is-uniqlo-to-good-for">What is Uniqlo to good for?</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Affordable Basics – High-quality essentials like T-shirts, jeans, and sweaters at reasonable prices.</li>
  <li>Innovative Fabrics – HEATTECH for warmth, AIRism for breathability, and Ultra Light Down for lightweight insulation.</li>
  <li>Minimalist Style – Simple, versatile designs that work for any wardrobe.</li>
  <li>Comfortable Fit – Well-cut clothing with a focus on ease of movement.</li>
  <li>Seasonal &amp; Collab Drops – Limited-edition collections with brands, artists, and pop culture icons.</li>
</ul>

<p>In my POV, its the best bang for your buck brand in Singapore</p>

<p>My go to list when buying from uniqlo
AIRism T-Shirts – Lightweight, breathable, and perfect for Singapore’s humidity.
HEATTECH Innerwear – A must-have for travel to colder countries.
Ultra Light Down Jacket – Packs easily and provides warmth without bulk.
EZY Ankle Pants – Comfortable, stretchy, and great for both work and casual wear.
Supima Cotton Tees – Soft, durable, and a wardrobe staple.
UT Graphic Tees – Fun collaborations with anime, pop culture, and artists.
Stretch Jeans – Affordable, well-fitted, and long-lasting denim.</p>

<p>Best uniqlo collaborations</p>

<p>JW Anderson – A blend of British heritage and casual wear, featuring bold color blocking, oversized fits, and unique patterns.
KAWS – Iconic streetwear-inspired collections with signature KAWS graphics, including the Companion and BFF characters.
Marimekko – Finnish bold prints meet Uniqlo’s simplicity, creating statement pieces with vibrant patterns.
Hana Tajima – Modest, elegant designs with flowing silhouettes and soft fabrics, perfect for everyday wear.
Ines de la Fressange – Classic Parisian chic with timeless silhouettes and effortless French style.
Louvre Collection – A fusion of art and fashion, with prints inspired by masterpieces housed at the Louvre Museum, offering a cultural and artistic touch to Uniqlo’s minimalist designs.</p>

<p>Don’t bother lining up for these though. They may run out but their resale value is generally not high</p>

<p>Is it hard to add your own collection to UT?</p>

<p>Adding your own collection to Uniqlo’s UT line is actually easier than you might think! Here’s how:
Submit Your Designs – If you have a creative concept, Uniqlo is open to fresh, unique designs. Simply share your work, and if it resonates with their vision, it could be selected for the UT collection.
Collaborate with Uniqlo – Uniqlo frequently partners with artists, designers, and influencers. If your designs have a distinctive flair, reaching out for a collaboration could be your ticket to having your own collection featured.
Leverage Licensing – Got access to iconic art or pop culture references? If you can secure a licensing deal, Uniqlo is known to work with artists and creatives who bring new ideas to their UT collections.
Design and Production Support – Once you’re in, Uniqlo’s teams will help bring your designs to life, making it a smooth, collaborative process to ensure your ideas make it onto their shirts.
How do you return items in uniqlo Singapore
Returning items to Uniqlo is straightforward! Here’s what you need to know:
In-Store Returns:
Bring the item(s) along with the original receipt or proof of purchase.
You can return the item(s) within 30 days of purchase (or within 7 days for sale items).
Items should be in unused condition, with tags still attached.
Online Returns:
Go to the Uniqlo website and log into your account.
Find your order and select the item(s) you want to return.
Uniqlo usually provides a return label, so you can send the items back by mail.
You may have to cover return shipping costs unless the item is defective.
Is Singapore uniqlo cheaper than uniqlo in other countries</p>

<p>Depends. Chose countries with lower GST for a higher chance of a lower price</p>

<p>Uniqlo similar stores</p>

<p>Muji – Minimalist, high-quality basics with a focus on comfort and durability, in line with Uniqlo’s simple aesthetic.
GAP – Classic, well-made basics for everyday wear, offering a similar vibe to Uniqlo in terms of style and affordability.
GU – A sister brand to Uniqlo, GU offers affordable and trendy basics with a younger, fashion-forward twist, while maintaining good quality.
Everlane – A minimalist brand focusing on high-quality materials and transparency, offering clean, simple designs similar to Uniqlo’s core style.
Banana Republic – Known for polished, classic clothing with a bit more sophistication, Banana Republic offers stylish, high-quality basics that are often a bit more refined than Uniqlo’s offerings, but with a similar focus on versatile, well-made pieces.
These stores all offer high-quality basics and stylish, versatile clothing options, making them great alternatives to Uniqlo.
I personally love Uniqlo! Let me know what you guys think</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Singapore" /><category term="clothing" /><category term="shopping" /><category term="malls" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In a country where shopping malls multiply faster than your laundry pile, Uniqlo has somehow managed to colonize virtually every major retail space in Singapore with its minimalist Japanese fashion empire.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/uniqlo.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/uniqlo.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Guide to Chinese New Year Greetings Singapore</title><link href="/singapore-CNY-greetings/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Guide to Chinese New Year Greetings Singapore" /><published>2025-01-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-CNY-greetings</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-CNY-greetings/"><![CDATA[<p>This week in Chinese new year - we wrote about it in an earlier article. Chinese New Year in Singapore isn’t just about feasting and collecting ang baos—it’s also the season of bai nian (拜年), where you visit relatives, exchange auspicious greetings, and try to remember who’s who in the extended family.</p>

<p>It’s a time-honored tradition where people make the rounds, armed with well-rehearsed blessings, hoping for good fortune (or at least a bigger red packet). But what exactly do you say when bai nian? What should you be eating to keep the festive spirit alive? And, most importantly, what unwritten rules should you absolutely not break? This guide will take you through the art of bai nian—from the greetings to the food and customs—so you can navigate the season like a pro (or at least not embarrass yourself).</p>

<h3 id="why-do-people-bai-nian拜年">Why do people ‘bai nian’拜年?</h3>

<p>When it comes to bai nian (拜年), not all visits are created equal—there’s a hierarchy to follow. The most important people on your list? Elders, starting with grandparents, parents, and senior relatives, because filial piety is everything (and also where the best ang baos come from). The first two days of Chinese New Year, Chu Yi (初一) and Chu Er (初二), are reserved for immediate and extended family, as these are the days you honor your elders and keep the family spirit alive. Married couples are next, as they are morally obligated to distribute red packets to the unmarried, which makes them prime targets for strategic visits. Close friends and colleagues also exchange festive greetings, though usually without the monetary incentives. And if you’re really committed, some even bai nian to bosses or business partners, because what better way to start the year than ensuring good office politics and future pay raises?</p>

<p>And then there are the unexpected bai nian interactions—the security guards at your condo or office, the neighborhood kopitiam uncle, and even your regular bubble tea cashier, because why not spread some extra goodwill (or subtly hint at better service for the rest of the year)? Some overachievers even bring mandarin oranges for these encounters, just to flex their festive etiquette.</p>

<h3 id="what-do-people-say-when-bai-nian-your-chinese-new-year-greetings-cheat-sheet">What do people say when ‘bai nian’? Your chinese New Year Greetings cheat sheet</h3>

<p>When you’re bai nian (拜年), it’s all about the greetings. Here’s a list of some of the most common phrases people exchange, depending on who they’re visiting (and whether they’re hoping for good fortune or just ang baos):</p>

<ul>
  <li>新春快乐 (Xīnchūn kuàilè) – Happy New Year! The classic, because everyone likes a fresh start.</li>
  <li>恭喜发财 (Gōngxǐ fācái) – Wishing you wealth and prosperity! The go-to for anyone you want to see more of during the year—especially when it comes to red packets.</li>
  <li>年年有余 (Nián nián yǒu yú) – May you have abundance every year. A lovely sentiment that’s basically a wish for never-ending fortune.</li>
  <li>身体健康 (Shēntǐ jiànkāng) – Wishing you good health. Because let’s face it, you can never have too much of that, especially after all those festive snacks.</li>
  <li>万事如意 (Wànshì rúyì) – May everything go as you wish. A nice all-rounder to wish success in life, work, and, perhaps, a little luck with that lottery ticket.</li>
  <li>大吉大利 (Dà jí dà lì) – Wishing you great luck and great profits. Perfect for anyone who’s in business—or anyone who enjoys a bit of self-interest!</li>
  <li>财源广进 (Cáiyuán guǎng jìn) – May wealth come in from all directions. For those who are really, really hoping for a year of financial windfalls.</li>
  <li>步步高升 (Bù bù gāo shēng) – May you rise higher with each step. Ideal for that cousin who’s still climbing the career ladder, or anyone who enjoys a bit of professional flattery.</li>
  <li>合家欢乐 (Hé jiā huān lè) – Wishing happiness to your entire family. For when you want to keep the peace with everyone in the room—especially those relatives you barely know.</li>
  <li>吉祥如意 (Jíxiáng rúyì) – May good fortune and all things auspicious be with you. The wish you toss around when you want to sound extra formal or impress that auntie who knows how to make all the right moves.</li>
</ul>

<p>These phrases are the key to mastering the fine art of bai nian, ensuring your visits are filled with luck, laughter, and maybe just a bit more red packet generosity. Wait a minute. Here’s more in case you need them!</p>

<p>Here are 10 more Chinese New Year greetings to make sure you’re totally equipped for the festive rounds:</p>
<ul>
  <li>一帆风顺 (Yī fān fēng shùn) – Wishing you smooth sailing. A nice way to wish someone an easy and trouble-free year ahead.</li>
  <li>心想事成 (Xīn xiǎng shì chéng) – May all your wishes come true. A classic that works for anyone, no matter what their “wishes” might be.</li>
  <li>财运亨通 (Cái yùn hēng tōng) – May you have good financial luck. This one’s great for those looking to boost their bank accounts—or subtly nudge the person you’re talking to.</li>
  <li>吉星高照 (Jíxīng gāo zhào) – May the lucky stars shine brightly on you. A stellar (pun intended) greeting to wish someone a year of unshakable fortune.</li>
  <li>大展鸿图 (Dà zhǎn hóng tú) – May your career and ambitions flourish. Best used for the go-getters in your life—those who are constantly chasing after bigger dreams.</li>
  <li>龙马精神 (Lóng mǎ jīng shén) – Wishing you strength and vitality like a dragon or horse. A great way to wish someone energy and resilience in their pursuits.
六六大顺 (Liù liù dà shùn) – Wishing you everything goes smoothly in all aspects of life. You know, just to cover all bases—life, love, work, and whatever else may pop up.</li>
  <li>生意兴隆 (Shēng yì xīng lóng) – May your business prosper. If you’re talking to an entrepreneur or someone with a side hustle, this one’s practically a must.</li>
  <li>天天开心 (Tiāntiān kāixīn) – May you be happy every day. For the people who live for joy and laughter—because who doesn’t want to be happy all year long?</li>
  <li>和气生财 (Hé qì shēng cái) – Harmony brings wealth. A gentle reminder that good relationships and peace in the home can lead to good fortune.</li>
</ul>

<p>With these 20 greetings under your belt, you’ll definitely impress (or at least, mildly entertain) all those you’re visiting for bai nian. And maybe, just maybe, you’ll find yourself the recipient of a well-timed red packet or two.</p>

<p>And how about some snake related ones too?!</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>蛇年大吉 (Shé nián dà jí) – Wishing you great luck in the Year of the Snake.
Perfect for anyone born in the Year of the Snake, or anyone just looking to tie in some snake symbolism for good measure.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>蛇行天下 (Shé xíng tiā xià) – May you conquer the world like a snake slithering through all obstacles.
This one’s for those who aim to glide through life with ease—smooth, like a snake.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>蛇精灵巧 (Shé jīng líng qiǎo) – May you be as clever and resourceful as a snake.
A good greeting for the smart and strategic thinkers in your circle, especially for those who always seem to have a trick up their sleeve.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>蛇年发财 (Shé nián fā cái) – May you make a fortune in the Year of the Snake.
Because if there’s one thing a snake is known for, it’s knowing when to strike—so why not strike big with wealth?</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>如蛇得水 (Rú shé dé shuǐ) – Like a snake finding water, may your endeavors flow effortlessly.
A great one for anyone you want to wish smooth success to, as though they’ve found the perfect path.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>蛇年吉祥 (Shé nián jí xiáng) – May the Year of the Snake bring you auspicious blessings.
A general snake-themed blessing for anyone celebrating the year, perfect for spreading some fortune.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<h3 id="what-do-people-eat-when-bai-nian">What do people eat when bai nian?</h3>

<p>When bai nian (拜年), food is a key part of the celebration, as you can’t just go around wishing people good luck without some delicious treats to back it up. Here’s what you’ll typically find on the table:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Radish Cake (萝卜糕) – A savory steamed cake made from radish and rice flour – Often served in bite-sized squares, it’s a popular dish during Chinese New Year, especially when fried for extra crispiness.</li>
  <li>Taro Cake (芋头糕) – Steamed cake made with taro root – A delicious, soft cake made from taro and rice flour, often served during festive times, symbolizing prosperity and abundance.</li>
  <li>Nian Gao (年糕) – Glutinous rice cake – Symbolizes progress and growth, as the word “nian” sounds like “year” and “gao” sounds like “tall,” meaning “higher year” or “growth.” A staple during Chinese New Year.</li>
  <li>Congee (粥) – Rice porridge – A warming dish often served with different savory toppings, symbolizing abundance and comfort. It’s a great way to start the day of visiting or after a late-night celebration.</li>
  <li>Pineapple Tarts (凤梨酥) – Buttery pastry filled with pineapple jam – These are a sweet treat that symbolizes wealth, as “pineapple” sounds like “prosperity” in Chinese.</li>
  <li>Mandarins (橘子) – Oranges – Widely seen during bai nian, the orange represents good luck and wealth because the Chinese word for orange sounds like “gold.”</li>
  <li>Sweet Cakes (糖果) – A variety of sweet treats like sugar-coated lotus seeds or preserved fruits – Served to guests, these symbolize a sweet life and the hope for good fortune.</li>
</ul>

<p>These dishes aren’t just delicious—they come with all the luck, prosperity, and health you could ask for in the new year. It’s like a feast with benefits! Happy CNY!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Singapore" /><category term="CNY" /><category term="Chinese New Year" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week in Chinese new year - we wrote about it in an earlier article. Chinese New Year in Singapore isn’t just about feasting and collecting ang baos—it’s also the season of bai nian (拜年), where you visit relatives, exchange auspicious greetings, and try to remember who’s who in the extended family.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/greet.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/greet.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Guide to Singapore scam protection</title><link href="/singapore-scam-protection/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Guide to Singapore scam protection" /><published>2025-01-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-scam-protection</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-scam-protection/"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to Singapore, where scammers are working harder than most of us do at our day jobs, turning our little red dot into what feels like a master class in creative criminal enterprises.</p>

<p>While Thailand’s recent surge in tourist-targeting scams has travelers clutching their passports a little tighter, Singapore’s scammers have been keeping themselves just as busy, proving that even our squeaky-clean reputation isn’t enough to keep the fraudsters away. In this guide, we’ll navigate through the jungle of Singaporean scams (from love scams that’ll break your heart and bank account simultaneously, to those suspiciously aggressive bank “officers” who seem more interested in your OTP than your actual banking needs), explore the latest tech-savvy protection measures, and share what to do if you’ve already sent your life savings to that charming person who totally promises they’re a Swedish billionaire (spoiler alert: they’re probably not).</p>

<h3 id="why-are-people-avoiding-travel-to-thailand">Why are people avoiding travel to Thailand?</h3>

<p>The recent decline in travel to Thailand is largely driven by rising safety concerns, particularly related to human trafficking and scam operations. A major issue is the growing presence of criminal syndicates operating near the Myanmar-Thailand border, where victims are lured into fraudulent job offers and subsequently trafficked into scam centers. These scam operations—often referred to as “pig butchering” scams—force victims to engage in fraudulent online activities, such as investment scams or romance scams, primarily targeting people in China and other countries.</p>

<p>The case of Chinese actor Wang Xing has brought significant attention to the dangers of these operations. He was reportedly deceived with a fake acting job in Thailand, only to be kidnapped and transported to Myanmar, where he was forced to participate in a scam targeting Chinese nationals. His case is just one of many instances where unsuspecting individuals, including tourists and job seekers, have fallen victim to human trafficking in the region.</p>

<p>The publicity surrounding this incident has led to widespread fear, particularly among Chinese travelers. As a result, many have canceled their plans to visit Thailand, leading to a sharp decline in chartered flights and hotel bookings. The situation has become so severe that even Chinese travel agencies are reporting a significant drop in demand for Thailand trips, despite the country being one of the most popular travel destinations for Chinese tourists.
This ongoing issue has not only affected Thailand’s tourism industry but has also prompted increased scrutiny from international governments, with some warning their citizens about the risks of traveling to Thailand, especially near border regions. Authorities in China, for example, have ramped up efforts to warn their citizens about fraudulent job scams in Southeast Asia, urging caution when considering employment opportunities abroad.</p>

<h3 id="why-are-there-so-many-scams-these-days-in-singapore">Why are there so many scams these days in Singapore?</h3>

<p>Scams have become increasingly common in Singapore due to a mix of technological advancements, social engineering tactics, and global crime syndicates taking advantage of unsuspecting victims. Here are some key reasons why scams are on the rise:</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Increased Digital Connectivity
Singapore has one of the highest internet penetration rates in the world, making it easy for scammers to reach victims through messaging apps, emails, and social media. With almost everyone connected online, the opportunities for fraud have multiplied.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Rise of AI and Deepfake Technology
Scammers are now using AI-powered tools to create convincing deepfake videos, voice impersonations, and fake documents. This makes scams—especially those involving fake authorities, job offers, and investment schemes—much more believable.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Social Engineering and Psychological Manipulation
Many scams today rely on psychological tricks to create a sense of urgency, fear, or excitement. Whether it’s a fake delivery scam, a phishing email from “your bank,” or a romance scam, fraudsters exploit emotions to get victims to act without thinking.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Global Crime Syndicates Targeting Singapore
Many scams originate from overseas criminal syndicates, especially from countries like China, Myanmar, Cambodia, and the Philippines. These groups run large-scale scam operations, targeting Singaporeans with fake investment opportunities, phishing links, and e-commerce scams.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Easy Access to Personal Data
Data breaches and leaks have made personal information more accessible to scammers. With just a phone number, they can launch highly targeted scams, making fake calls from banks, government agencies, or delivery companies seem more legitimate.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Increase in Digital Payments and E-Commerce
The shift to cashless transactions has opened up new scam opportunities. Fake online stores, PayNow/PayLah! payment scams, and fraudulent QR codes have made it easier for scammers to steal money instantly.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Lack of Awareness and Cybersecurity Hygiene
Despite government efforts to raise awareness, some people still fall for scams because they don’t recognize warning signs. Clicking on suspicious links, sharing OTPs, or believing too-good-to-be-true job offers continue to be common mistakes.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Weak Enforcement in Scam Hotspots
Many scammers operate from jurisdictions where law enforcement is weak or corrupt. This makes it difficult for Singaporean authorities to track them down or recover stolen money, allowing scams to continue at large scales.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Work-From-Home and Online Job Scams
Since the pandemic, more people have been looking for online jobs, and scammers have taken full advantage. Fake job listings promising high pay for minimal work have scammed many Singaporeans into making upfront payments or laundering money unknowingly.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Increasing Use of Telegram and WhatsApp for Illicit Activities
Scammers often use encrypted messaging apps like Telegram and WhatsApp to operate anonymously. Many scams involve fake investment groups, Ponzi schemes, and phishing attempts, making it harder for authorities to track down the perpetrators.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<h3 id="what-type-of-scams-are-there-in-singapore">What type of scams are there in Singapore?</h3>

<p>Scams in Singapore come in many forms, evolving constantly to trick unsuspecting victims. Here are the most common types of scams you should watch out for:</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Phishing Scams
Scammers send fake emails, SMS, or WhatsApp messages pretending to be from banks, government agencies, or delivery companies. These messages often contain fake links that steal your personal data or banking details.
Example: A fake “DBS security alert” asking you to verify your account via a link.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Banking &amp; OTP Scams
Victims receive calls or messages from fake bank officers asking for OTPs (One-Time Passwords) or login details. Once given, scammers drain the victim’s account.
Example: A scammer pretends to be from OCBC, claiming your account is compromised and needs OTP verification.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>E-Commerce Scams
Fake online stores or sellers on platforms like Carousell, Shopee, and Facebook Marketplace trick buyers into paying for products that never arrive.
Example: A “cheap” iPhone listing on Carousell that disappears after payment.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Job Scams
Scammers offer fake online jobs that promise easy money for simple tasks, like boosting social media likes or reviewing products. Victims are asked to transfer money upfront to unlock “higher commissions”—which never come.
Example: A Telegram job offer that claims you can earn “$300 a day” by liking YouTube videos.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Love &amp; Romance Scams
Fraudsters build relationships with victims online, usually through dating apps or social media, and eventually ask for money due to a “family emergency” or “investment opportunity.”
Example: A Tinder match from overseas who suddenly needs money for a “business deal.”</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Investment Scams
Scammers promise high returns with little risk through fake crypto, forex, or stock market investments. These scams often use fake testimonials and social media ads.
Example: A “crypto trading expert” on Instagram guarantees 500% returns if you send money to their “investment account.”</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Fake Kidnapping Scams
Victims receive calls claiming a loved one has been kidnapped, demanding ransom money. Sometimes, scammers use AI voice deepfakes to make it more convincing.
Example: A scammer calls saying they have kidnapped your child, but your child is actually safe at school.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Fake Delivery Scams
You receive an SMS or WhatsApp message from “SingPost” or “DHL” saying your package is delayed. Clicking the link installs malware that steals your banking details.
Example: A fake “Your parcel is on hold, please update delivery info” message with a phishing link.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Government Impersonation Scams
Scammers pose as ICA, SPF, or MOM officers, claiming you have legal issues or visa problems. They demand money to “settle” the issue.
Example: A fake ICA officer calls, saying your residency status is at risk unless you transfer $5,000.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Fake Loan Scams
Scammers pose as licensed moneylenders, offering quick loans with “low interest.” After victims apply, they are asked to pay upfront “processing fees” before disappearing.
Example: A fake loan ad on Facebook offering “instant approval” but requiring a deposit first.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Social Media &amp; Telegram Scams
Fraudsters impersonate your friends or join Telegram groups, promoting fake deals, jobs, or investments. Many scams involve Ponzi schemes where early investors get fake profits.
Example: A Telegram group claims to offer “guaranteed” profits through “US stock signals.”</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Charity &amp; Donation Scams
Fake charities ask for donations via WhatsApp, social media, or door-to-door visits, claiming to help disaster victims or sick children.
Example: A scammer pretends to raise funds for an “orphanage in Myanmar,” but the money goes straight into their pocket.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Rental Scams
Scammers post fake rental listings on PropertyGuru or Facebook, asking for deposits before viewing the unit. The “landlord” disappears after receiving payment.
Example: A too-good-to-be-true condo rental at $1,500/month that requires an upfront deposit to “secure” the place.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>WhatsApp Hijacking Scams
Fraudsters trick you into giving your WhatsApp verification code, then hijack your account to scam your contacts.
Example: A “friend” asks for your WhatsApp code, claiming they sent it to you by mistake.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Ponzi &amp; Pyramid Schemes
These scams promise big returns if you recruit more people. Money flows up the chain, but eventually, the scheme collapses, leaving late joiners with nothing.
Example: A “crypto mining” program where you earn by recruiting others—until it vanishes.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<h3 id="how-to-watch-out-for-scams-in-singapore">How to watch out for scams in Singapore?</h3>

<p>Scammers are getting more sophisticated in Singapore, but you can protect yourself by staying alert and following these key precautions:</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Verify Before You Click
Never click on links from unknown SMS, emails, or WhatsApp messages.
If a bank, government agency, or delivery company contacts you, check their official website or call their hotline directly.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Be Skeptical of Too-Good-To-Be-True Deals
If an online seller offers a luxury bag, iPhone, or rental unit at a ridiculously low price, it’s likely a scam.
Check reviews and seller ratings on platforms like Carousell and Facebook Marketplace.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Protect Your Banking Details
No bank or government agency will ask for your OTP, PIN, or login credentials over the phone or through email.
Use digital banking apps instead of SMS for transaction alerts, as scammers can spoof messages.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Use Official Apps &amp; Platforms
Download ScamShield, an anti-scam app developed by the Singapore Police Force.
Avoid unofficial third-party payment methods—use secured platforms like PayNow, GrabPay, or credit cards for protection.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Watch Out for Fake Job Offers
If a Telegram or WhatsApp message offers “easy online jobs” with high returns, it’s likely a scam.
Real companies don’t ask for upfront payments or require you to “unlock higher commissions” by depositing money.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Be Wary of “Friend” Messages Asking for Money
If a friend or family member suddenly asks for urgent money via WhatsApp, call them to verify.
Scammers hijack accounts and impersonate victims to trick their contacts.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Check Before Donating
Fake charities exploit disasters and tragedies to trick people into donating.
Verify with official sources like the Commissioner of Charities (charities.gov.sg).</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Avoid Investment &amp; Crypto Scams
High returns with “no risk” is always a scam.
Check the MAS Investor Alert List to see if a company is unregulated or flagged.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Be Cautious of Rental &amp; Property Deals
Never pay a deposit before viewing the property and meeting the agent in person.
Use licensed property agents listed on CEA’s (Council for Estate Agencies) website.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Report &amp; Stay Updated
Follow ScamAlert.sg and SPF’s anti-scam advisories.
If you suspect a scam, report it to the Anti-Scam Hotline at 1800-722-6688 or through police e-services.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>By staying cautious and verifying before taking action, you can avoid falling victim to scams in Singapore.</p>

<h3 id="what-apps--protections-can-you-do-to-avoid-scams-in-singapore">What apps / protections can you do to avoid scams in Singapore?</h3>

<p>To protect yourself from scams in Singapore, you can use several apps, tools, and best practices:</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>ScamShield (By Singapore Police Force &amp; NCPC)
Automatically filters scam calls and SMS.
Regularly updated with scam numbers from police reports.
Available on iOS and Android.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Singpass App
Secure your government logins with biometric authentication.
Prevents unauthorized access to sensitive personal data.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>ScamAlert.sg
Run by NCPC, this website provides the latest scam alerts.
Allows you to report and verify potential scams.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Bank &amp; Payment Apps
Enable transaction notifications to monitor suspicious activities.
Use mobile banking apps instead of SMS OTPs, as scammers can spoof SMS messages.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Google Safe Browsing &amp; URL Checkers
Use Google Safe Browsing (Google Transparency Report) to check suspicious links.
Browser extensions like Bitdefender TrafficLight help block phishing websites.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Spam &amp; Call Blockers
iOS and Android allow call blocking; activate “Silence Unknown Callers” (iPhone) or use Google’s Call Screening (Android).
Third-party apps like Truecaller help identify and block scam numbers.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<h3 id="best-practices-to-protect-yourself">Best Practices to Protect Yourself</h3>

<p>✔ Enable 2FA (Two-Factor Authentication) on banking, social media, and shopping accounts.
✔ Use strong, unique passwords for each account; consider using a password manager.
✔ Turn on automatic software updates for security patches on phones and apps.
✔ Verify unknown contacts—if a friend or company requests money, confirm directly before transferring funds.
✔ Disable international transactions on your bank cards unless needed.</p>

<p>These tools and habits significantly reduce your risk of falling for scams in Singapore. Stay alert and always verify before clicking or sending money.</p>

<h3 id="what-to-do-if-you-fall-for-a-scam-in-singapore">What to do if you fall for a scam in Singapore?</h3>

<p>If you fall for a scam in Singapore, act quickly to minimize your losses and increase your chances of recovering your money. Here’s what you should do:</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Secure Your Finances Immediately
✔ Call Your Bank – Report unauthorized transactions and request to freeze your account or card if needed.
✔ Enable Transaction Alerts – Monitor for further suspicious activity.
✔ Reset Passwords &amp; 2FA – Change login credentials for affected banking, email, or shopping accounts.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Report the Scam
✔ Lodge a Police Report – File a report via Police e-Services or visit the nearest police station.
✔ Report to ScamShield &amp; ScamAlert.sg – Helps authorities track and warn others.
✔ Inform Your Bank &amp; Credit Card Provider – Some banks can help reverse fraudulent transactions if reported early.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Minimize Further Damage
✔ Contact Singpass Helpdesk (If Involved) – If your personal details were stolen, call +65 6335 3533 to prevent identity fraud.
✔ Check if Your Data is Compromised – Use sites like Have I Been Pwned to see if your details were leaked.
✔ Warn Friends &amp; Family – Scammers might impersonate you to target others.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Be Wary of Recovery Scams
✔ Avoid Paying “Scam Recovery” Services – Scammers often pose as fake agencies promising to retrieve your money for a fee.
✔ Follow Official Channels – Only work with your bank and the police.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>Time is crucial in scam cases—report and take action immediately to prevent further losses. Don’t be scammed!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Singapore" /><category term="tech" /><category term="apps" /><category term="scam" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to Singapore, where scammers are working harder than most of us do at our day jobs, turning our little red dot into what feels like a master class in creative criminal enterprises.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/scam.webp" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/scam.webp" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Guide to running shoes in Singapore</title><link href="/singapore-running-shoes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Guide to running shoes in Singapore" /><published>2025-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-running-shoes</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-running-shoes/"><![CDATA[<p>Running: the activity we love to hate but can’t seem to quit, especially when it comes to sweating through Singapore’s tropical heat.</p>

<p>Whether you’re chasing <a href="https://fromhktosg.github.io/sports-singapore/">fitness goals</a>, a personal best, or just running away from your problems (figuratively, of course), it turns out this daily grind does wonders for your body—science says so. But let’s not forget the unsung heroes of every runner’s journey: the shoes that take the pounding. From cross-country terrains to casual park jogs, there’s a dizzying array of running shoes tailored for every style and purpose. And with brands like Adidas, Hoka, Nike, and Brooks battling it out, picking the best pair might just be the most exhausting part of your fitness journey.</p>

<h3 id="why-do-people-like-running-in-singapore">Why do people like running in Singapore?</h3>

<p>People in Singapore seem to enjoy running for a mix of reasons, ranging from practical to personal (and occasionally questionable). For one, it’s a convenient way to stay fit without needing a gym membership—just lace up your shoes and step outside. The scenic running paths, like East Coast Park and Marina Bay, provide stunning views that almost make you forget you’re sweating buckets in 30°C humidity. Some people enjoy the sense of accomplishment, whether it’s completing a 5K or just surviving the first kilometer without collapsing. And let’s not overlook the social aspect—Singapore’s running clubs and marathons make it feel less like exercise and more like a community event where everyone’s suffering together.</p>

<h3 id="what-does-running-once-a-day-help-with-on-a-scientific-angle">What does running once a day help with on a scientific angle?</h3>

<p>Running once a day isn’t just about looking good in your workout gear; it actually brings some impressive scientific benefits, backed by stats. It can reduce the risk of cardiovascular disease by up to 30%, according to research from the British Journal of Sports Medicine, as it strengthens your heart and improves blood circulation. Regular running also releases endorphins—those magical “feel-good” chemicals—which is why 82% of runners report improved moods after their workouts. It burns about 100 calories per mile on average, making it a great way to maintain a healthy weight while strengthening bones and improving muscle tone. Plus, studies show that people who exercise regularly, including running, are 60% less likely to experience anxiety or depression, proving that a daily jog is essentially a mental health booster on top of everything else.</p>

<h3 id="best-running-paths-in-singapore">Best running paths in Singapore</h3>

<p>Here’s a breakdown of some of the best running paths in Singapore, sorted by geographic area:</p>

<p><u>Central<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>Marina Bay Sands to Gardens by the Bay: A scenic route featuring waterfront views, Supertrees, and Singapore’s iconic skyline.</li>
  <li>Singapore Botanic Gardens: A UNESCO World Heritage Site with lush greenery and well-paved paths for runners.</li>
  <li>Fort Canning Park: A historic park with challenging uphill routes for those looking to add some elevation.</li>
</ul>

<p><u>East<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>East Coast Park: The ultimate beachfront running trail, stretching over 15 km, with sea breezes to keep you company.</li>
  <li>Bedok Reservoir Park: A calm, circular 4.3 km loop surrounded by water, perfect for interval training or leisurely runs.</li>
</ul>

<p><u>West<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>Jurong Lake Gardens: A peaceful spot with scenic boardwalks and running trails, ideal for nature lovers.</li>
  <li>Bukit Batok Nature Park: A quieter park with hilly terrain for a good cardio workout.</li>
</ul>

<p><u>North<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>Lower Seletar Reservoir Park: A tranquil route by the water, with shaded paths and a jetty for a post-run cool-down.</li>
  <li>Admiralty Park: A mix of natural and urban trails, with some paths running through mangroves.</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Northeast<u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li>Punggol Waterway Park: A scenic riverside route with well-maintained paths and lush landscaping.</li>
  <li>Coney Island: A rustic, unpaved trail for a slightly more adventurous running experience.</li>
</ul>

<p>These paths cater to all levels, from casual joggers to serious marathon trainers, so you’ll find your perfect match no matter where you’re located.</p>

<h3 id="top-types-of-running-shoes-and-when-to-use-them">Top Types of Running Shoes (And When to Use Them)</h3>

<p>Neutral Running Shoes: Best for runners with a natural gait and minimal pronation.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Features: Balanced cushioning, flexibility, and lightweight designs.</li>
</ul>

<p>Stability Running Shoes: Ideal for overpronators (feet roll inward excessively while running).</p>
<ul>
  <li>Features: Added arch support and structured midsoles for better alignment.</li>
</ul>

<p>Trail Running Shoes: Perfect for off-road adventures on trails, mud, or rocky terrain.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Features: Aggressive tread, reinforced durability, and water resistance.</li>
</ul>

<p>Cushioned/Maximalist Running Shoes: Great for long-distance runners or those needing extra comfort.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Features: Maximum shock absorption and soft midsoles to reduce joint impact.</li>
</ul>

<p>Racing Flats/Sprint Shoes: Designed for speed, whether it’s a sprint or a race day.</p>
<ul>
  <li>Features: Lightweight, minimal cushioning, and fast responsiveness.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="criteria-for-rating-running-shoes">Criteria for rating running shoes</h3>

<ol>
  <li>Comfort</li>
</ol>

<p>How the shoe feels during short and long runs, including padding and fit.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Cushioning</li>
</ol>

<p>The level of shock absorption to protect joints and provide a smooth ride.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Durability</li>
</ol>

<p>How well the shoe holds up over time, especially with frequent use.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Traction</li>
</ol>

<p>Grip quality on various surfaces, from pavements to trails.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Support</li>
</ol>

<p>Arch support and stability features to match different running gaits.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Weight</li>
</ol>

<p>How light or heavy the shoe feels, impacting speed and fatigue levels.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Breathability</li>
</ol>

<p>Airflow and material quality to keep feet cool and prevent blisters.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Price-to-Performance Ratio</li>
</ol>

<p>Whether the shoe’s features justify its price for casual or serious runners.</p>

<h3 id="running-shoe-brands-and-sub-brands">Running Shoe Brands and Sub-Brands</h3>

<p><u>Adidas<u></u></u></p>

<p>Ultraboost: Known for its plush cushioning and responsive feel, perfect for long-distance runs.
Adizero: Lightweight and fast, designed for performance and speed, ideal for competitive runners.
Solar: Offers a balance of comfort and stability, suitable for everyday runners.
Terrex: Built for trail running with durable materials and extra grip for tough terrains.</p>

<p><u>Hoka<u></u></u></p>

<p>Clifton: Cushioned, lightweight shoes with a soft ride, designed for road runners.
Bondi: Known for its maximalist cushioning, ideal for runners seeking ultimate comfort on long runs.
Speedgoat: Trail-specific shoes that provide exceptional grip and stability for off-road runs.
Mach: Lightweight with responsive cushioning, built for speed and efficiency on both road and track.
Arahi: Stability shoes offering structured support without sacrificing cushioning, perfect for overpronators.</p>

<p><u>Nike<u></u></u></p>

<p>Air Zoom Pegasus: Versatile and durable, ideal for both beginners and experienced runners looking for a reliable shoe.
ZoomX Vaporfly: High-performance shoes built for elite runners, designed for speed with a lightweight, responsive feel.
React Infinity: Known for its soft cushioning and stability, making it great for injury prevention.
Wildhorse: A rugged trail running shoe with a durable upper and aggressive tread for off-road adventures.</p>

<p><u>On<u></u></u></p>

<p>Cloudrunner: Designed for comfort and support, offering a smooth, cushioned ride for daily runs.
Cloudflow: Lightweight and responsive, built for runners who want speed and agility on their runs.
Cloudboom: Performance-oriented shoes focused on long-distance races and marathons with added propulsion.
Cloudultra: A trail running shoe offering maximum cushioning and durability for tough outdoor runs.</p>

<p><u>Asics<u></u></u></p>

<p>Gel-Kayano: Stability shoes with gel cushioning for a smooth, supportive ride, ideal for overpronators.
Gel-Nimbus: Known for its plush cushioning and neutral support, great for long-distance road runners.
GT-2000: Stability shoes with a focus on support and durability for long-term performance.
Gel-Venture: Affordable trail shoes with excellent grip and protection for off-road running.</p>

<p><u>New Balance<u></u></u></p>

<p>Fresh Foam 1080: Provides superior cushioning for long runs, ideal for runners seeking comfort and protection.
FuelCell: A performance-focused shoe with responsive cushioning, designed for speed and agility.
Fresh Foam More: Maximalist cushioning for a plush, soft feel on long runs or recovery days.
Hierro: A durable trail shoe with aggressive tread and superior cushioning for rough terrain.</p>

<p><u>Brooks<u></u></u></p>

<p>Ghost: Neutral running shoes with balanced cushioning, ideal for both beginners and experienced runners.
Adrenaline GTS: Stability shoes that offer reliable support and cushioning for runners with mild to moderate overpronation.
Glycerin: Offers plush cushioning for a soft, comfortable ride, great for long runs or recovery days.
Cascadia: A trail shoe with a rugged design, providing traction and stability for off-road adventures.</p>

<h3 id="best-running-shoes-ranked">Best running shoes ranked</h3>

<p>Based on our criteria -</p>

<ol>
  <li>Nike ZoomX Vaporfly Next%</li>
</ol>

<p>Pro: Exceptional speed and energy return, perfect for elite runners.
Con: Expensive and not as durable for everyday use.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Hoka One One Clifton 9</li>
</ol>

<p>Pro: Maximal cushioning offers a soft, comfortable ride for long runs.
Con: Can feel bulky for those preferring a lighter shoe.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Adidas Ultraboost 23</li>
</ol>

<p>Pro: Superior comfort with responsive Boost cushioning for daily use.
Con: Slightly heavier than other neutral shoes.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Brooks Ghost 15</li>
</ol>

<p>Pro: Well-balanced cushioning and responsiveness for a smooth run.
Con: Lacks the extreme cushioning some runners prefer for long-distance events.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Asics Gel-Nimbus 25</li>
</ol>

<p>Pro: Excellent cushioning and support for long runs and marathons.
Con: Can feel stiff for some users out of the box.</p>

<ol>
  <li>New Balance Fresh Foam 1080v12</li>
</ol>

<p>Pro: Soft, cushioned feel perfect for long distances.
Con: Less responsive than some lighter, faster models.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Hoka One One Speedgoat 5</li>
</ol>

<p>Pro: Excellent traction and durability for trail runners.
Con: Heavier and less flexible compared to road shoes.</p>

<ol>
  <li>On Cloudflow</li>
</ol>

<p>Pro: Lightweight and responsive, ideal for speed and short runs.
Con: Not as cushioned for long-distance or recovery runs.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Adidas Adizero Adios Pro 3</li>
</ol>

<p>Pro: Designed for performance, offering a quick and responsive ride for race days.
Con: Expensive and not ideal for daily or recovery runs.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Brooks Adrenaline GTS 23</li>
</ol>

<p>Pro: Great stability shoe for overpronators with reliable support.
Con: Can feel too firm for those seeking plush cushioning.</p>

<h3 id="where-do-you-buy-running-shoes-in-singapore">Where do you buy running shoes in Singapore?</h3>

<p>In Singapore, there are several great places to buy running shoes, catering to different preferences and budgets. Here are some top spots:</p>

<p><u>Nike Stores (e.g., Nike Orchard)<u></u></u></p>

<p>Offers a wide variety of Nike running shoes, including performance-focused models like the Nike ZoomX Vaporfly and the Nike Air Zoom Pegasus.</p>

<p><u>adidas Stores (e.g., adidas Suntec City)<u></u></u></p>

<p>Known for shoes like Ultraboost and Adizero, adidas provides great options for both casual runners and elite athletes.</p>

<p><u>Hoka Store (e.g., Hoka at VivoCity)<u></u></u></p>

<p>Specializes in maximalist shoes like Clifton and Bondi, perfect for runners seeking comfort and cushioning.</p>

<p><u>Tangs (e.g., Tangs Orchard)<u></u></u></p>

<p>A department store that carries running shoes from major brands like Asics, Nike, and New Balance, often with seasonal discounts.</p>

<p><u>Decathlon (multiple locations)<u></u></u></p>

<p>Budget-friendly options with a wide range of running shoes for beginners and casual runners, featuring brands like Kalenji and Domyos.</p>

<p><u>Running Lab<u>
The new fancy place with expert recommendations</u></u></p>

<p>Each of these stores usually offers personalized fitting services to help you find the right pair based on your running style and preferences.</p>

<p>Remember, comfort is key. What’s your favourite running pair? Let me know!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Singapore" /><category term="shopping" /><category term="running" /><category term="shoes" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Running: the activity we love to hate but can’t seem to quit, especially when it comes to sweating through Singapore’s tropical heat.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/run.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/run.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Guide to Jewel Changi Airport Singapore</title><link href="/singapore-jewel-airport/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Guide to Jewel Changi Airport Singapore" /><published>2025-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-jewel-airport</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-jewel-airport/"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to Singapore’s Jewel Changi Airport, a revolutionary mall-airport hybrid featuring top attractions like the Rain Vortex waterfall, premium shops, acclaimed restaurants, and a unique floor plan that rivals other shopping destinations in Singapore.</p>

<p>While most airports are content with basic amenities like places to sit and wait for your flight, Jewel decided to go full Singapore-style extra with an indoor forest, countless shopping options, and enough restaurants to make you consider intentionally missing your connection. Beyond just being a mall with a fancy water feature, this glass-domed marvel actually houses some genuinely impressive attractions that’ll have you planning future layovers in Singapore (yes, really), though there are plenty of alternative malls if you somehow get bored of watching water fall from the sky inside a building.</p>

<h3 id="what-is-jewel-airport">What is Jewel airport?</h3>

<p>Jewel Changi Airport is a massive lifestyle and entertainment complex connected to Singapore Changi Airport. Located at Terminal 1, with direct access from Terminals 2 and 3, it’s a mixed-use development featuring shopping, dining, attractions, and even a hotel. ewel Changi Airport was officially opened on April 17, 2019. The project took about four years to build, with construction starting in 2014. It was designed to enhance Changi Airport’s appeal as a top aviation hub while also serving as a lifestyle destination for both travelers and locals.</p>

<h3 id="what-is-jewels-floor-plan">What is Jewel’s floor plan?</h3>

<p>Jewel Changi Airport has ten floors—five above ground (L1 to L5) and five basement levels (B1 to B5). Here’s a general breakdown of its floor plan:</p>

<p>Above-Ground Levels</p>

<ul>
  <li>L5: Canopy Park (Sky Nets, Hedge Maze, Mirror Maze, Discovery Slides, Foggy Bowls)</li>
  <li>L4: Dining, premium lifestyle stores, and the entrance to the Canopy Park</li>
  <li>L3: Shopping, casual dining, and entertainment options</li>
  <li>L2: More retail stores and restaurants, featuring international and local brands</li>
  <li>L1: The Rain Vortex (centerpiece waterfall), main shopping atrium, and airport access</li>
</ul>

<p>Basement Levels</p>

<ul>
  <li>B1: Food court (Five Spice), supermarkets, everyday retail stores</li>
  <li>B2 to B4: Parking spaces and service areas</li>
  <li>B5: Airport utilities and restricted areas</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="top-attractions-in-jewel">Top attractions in Jewel</h3>

<p>Top Attractions in Jewel Changi Airport</p>

<ul>
  <li>HSBC Rain Vortex – The world’s tallest indoor waterfall (40 meters), cascading through Jewel’s glass dome. At night, it transforms into a mesmerizing light and sound show, making it a must-see spectacle. Best viewed from various vantage points across multiple floors.</li>
  <li>Shiseido Forest Valley – A massive indoor garden filled with over 900 trees and palms, waterfalls, and meandering trails that offer a peaceful escape. The cool temperature and natural setting make it a great place for a relaxing stroll before or after a flight.</li>
  <li>Canopy Park – A sprawling 14,000 sqm recreational space on the top level featuring:</li>
  <li>Discovery Slides – A sculptural slide and art installation in one.</li>
  <li>Foggy Bowls – Mist-filled play areas designed for kids to enjoy a dreamy, cloud-like experience.</li>
  <li>Petal Garden – A floral wonderland that changes with the seasons, displaying vibrant flowers in full bloom.</li>
  <li>Manulife Sky Nets – Two thrilling experiences for those seeking adventure:</li>
  <li>Bouncing Net – A giant suspended net where you can leap and feel like you’re walking on air.</li>
  <li>Walking Net – A transparent, suspended net that lets you walk high above the ground with stunning views of Jewel’s indoor landscape.</li>
  <li>Hedge Maze &amp; Mirror Maze –
Hedge Maze – Singapore’s largest indoor hedge maze, offering a fun and challenging path with an observation deck at the center for a bird’s-eye view of the intricate design.
Mirror Maze – A dazzling labyrinth of mirrors and optical illusions that makes for a fun and slightly mind-bending experience.</li>
  <li>Changi Experience Studio – An interactive digital attraction showcasing the history and innovations of Changi Airport. Visitors can play airport-themed games, experience a flight simulation, and learn about the technology behind one of the world’s best airports.</li>
  <li>Changi Airport Control Tower Viewing Deck – While not an official attraction, many visitors enjoy finding a spot to admire the control tower from within Jewel, especially at night when it’s beautifully illuminated.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="top-shops-in-jewel">Top shops in Jewel</h3>

<p>Jewel Changi Airport is home to some stellar retail spots. Here’s a look at a few top ones:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Nike Unite – A massive store with exclusive collections and an impressive range of running and athleisure gear, perfect for fitness enthusiasts.</li>
  <li>Apple Store – The flagship location offers a hands-on experience with the latest Apple products and hosts Today at Apple sessions, featuring workshops and tutorials.</li>
  <li>Adidas – Offering a sleek selection of Ultraboost, Adizero, and other high-performance shoes, plus a full range of apparel and accessories for athletes.</li>
  <li>Pokemon Center Singapore – The region’s only official Pokémon store, packed with collectibles like plush toys, trading cards, and limited-edition items that every Pokémon fan will adore.</li>
  <li>Lego Certified Store – A must-visit for LEGO lovers, this store has exclusive sets, build-your-own mini-figures, and fun interactive displays.</li>
  <li>Zara – With one of the largest Zara stores in Singapore, you can shop a wide variety of stylish clothes for men, women, and kids.</li>
</ul>

<p>Unfortunately, there aren’t a lot of luxury good stores so dont expect anything.</p>

<h3 id="top-restaurants-in-kewel">Top restaurants in Kewel</h3>

<p>Here’s my list of top dining options at Jewel Changi Airport:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Shake Shack – Known for its ShackBurgers, crinkle-cut fries, and milkshakes, offering tasty American fast-casual dining. It’s a pretty one too at Jewel and right near the entrance</li>
  <li>TWG Tea – A luxurious tea salon with an extensive selection of premium teas, paired with pastries, scones, and light bites—perfect for a refined afternoon tea experience.</li>
  <li>Crystal Jade – Offering high-quality Chinese cuisine, including dim sum, noodles, and signature dishes in a warm and welcoming setting.</li>
  <li>ArtesanIQ – A gourmet café serving a range of artisanal dishes, from fresh salads and sandwiches to pastries and specialty coffees, perfect for a light yet satisfying meal.</li>
  <li>Burger &amp; Lobster – A must-visit for seafood lovers, this spot specializes in juicy burgers and fresh lobster dishes, served in a stylish, relaxed atmosphere.</li>
  <li>Jumbo Seafood – Famous for its Singaporean-style seafood, especially chili crab and black pepper crab, this is the place to indulge in flavorful local seafood.</li>
  <li>Violet Oon – A celebration of Peranakan cuisine, offering dishes like laksa, satay, and rendang, all in a beautiful setting.</li>
  <li>The Coffee Academics – A specialty coffee shop serving artisanal brews and a selection of breakfast and brunch options, ideal for coffee aficionados.</li>
</ul>

<p>With these options, Jewel offers a delightful variety of dining experiences, ranging from local flavors to international favorites.</p>

<h3 id="special-hacks-to-jewel">Special hacks to Jewel</h3>

<p>Here are a few of my secrets -</p>

<ul>
  <li>Skip the tourist crowds by visiting the Rain Vortex before 11 AM or after 9 PM, when the lighting makes the waterfall somehow even more dramatic and your Instagram photos won’t be photobombed by a hundred other smartphones.</li>
  <li>Early birds can take advantage of the early check-in counters up to 24 hours before your flight – drop off your luggage, grab your boarding pass, and enjoy a baggage-free shopping spree without that awkward roller suitcase bumping into everything.</li>
  <li>For those who appreciate a touch of luxury (without the luxury price tag), the Changi Lounge in Jewel offers pay-per-use access with showers, nap pods, and buffet spreads – perfect for refreshing between shopping sessions or when you’re pretending your flight isn’t delayed.</li>
  <li>If you’re visiting during Singapore’s notorious rain showers, use the air-conditioned link bridges from terminals 1, 2, or 3 to reach Jewel – you’ll stay dry and get some bonus plane-spotting opportunities along the way.</li>
  <li>Save money on airport food by heading to the basement level’s Food Hall, where you’ll find local favorites at much more reasonable prices than the fancy restaurants upstairs (though you might still need to take out a small loan for that famous pepper crab).</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="alternative-malls-in-singapore">Alternative malls in Singapore</h3>

<p>If you’re looking for alternatives to Jewel Changi Airport, here are a few other great malls in Singapore:</p>

<ul>
  <li>ION Orchard – A luxury shopping hub on Orchard Road, featuring high-end brands, a wide variety of dining options, and stunning architecture. Perfect for a glamorous shopping experience.</li>
  <li>Marina Bay Sands Shoppes – A waterfront shopping destination with a range of luxury brands, upscale dining, and entertainment options, including the famous floating gondolas in the canals.</li>
  <li>VivoCity – One of the largest malls in Singapore, offering a mix of retail, dining, and entertainment, including a rooftop Sky Park and an extensive range of stores catering to all budgets.</li>
  <li>The Paragon – A premium shopping mall in Orchard Road, known for its selection of designer brands, fine dining, and wellness services.</li>
  <li>Takashimaya – Located at Ngee Ann City, this Japanese department store offers a wide range of fashion, beauty, and lifestyle products, alongside several delicious dining spots.</li>
  <li>Suntec City – A massive mall in the Marina Centre area, with a diverse selection of stores, dining options, and entertainment, including an impressive array of international brands.</li>
  <li>Bugis Junction – Known for its vibrant atmosphere, Bugis Junction offers an eclectic mix of fashion, beauty, and lifestyle stores, as well as a range of food options.</li>
  <li>Plaza Singapura – A family-friendly mall located along Orchard Road, offering a mix of affordable retail, entertainment, and dining options. Great for casual shopping trips.</li>
</ul>

<p>For more details on this, you can see my previous <a href="https://fromhktosg.github.io/shopping-in-singapore/">article</a>. Happy shopping at Jewel!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Singapore" /><category term="mall" /><category term="shopping" /><category term="restaurants" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to Singapore’s Jewel Changi Airport, a revolutionary mall-airport hybrid featuring top attractions like the Rain Vortex waterfall, premium shops, acclaimed restaurants, and a unique floor plan that rivals other shopping destinations in Singapore.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/jew.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/jew.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Guide to Ikea in Singapore</title><link href="/singapore-ikea-furniture/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Guide to Ikea in Singapore" /><published>2025-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-ikea-furniture</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-ikea-furniture/"><![CDATA[<p>IKEA – the Swedish furniture giant that somehow convinces us flat-packed chaos is a life skill we all need. With its maze-like stores, budget-friendly meatballs, and those adorable blue-and-yellow tote bags, IKEA has built an empire in Singapore that’s as iconic as the MRT.</p>

<p>But how did this furniture juggernaut make its way here, and more importantly, why do we willingly brave crowds to snag a BILLY bookcase or a FÖRNUFTIG air purifier? In this guide, we’ll dive into IKEA’s quirky history, the locations in Singapore, what’s worth tossing into your oversized shopping bag, and which seasonal treats make it all the more tempting. Plus, we’ll throw in some alternatives for those rare moments when you decide to cheat on IKEA.</p>

<h3 id="what-is-ikea">What is Ikea?</h3>

<p>IKEA is the world’s most famous flat-pack furniture brand, known for turning the mundane act of furnishing a home into a worldwide phenomenon. Founded in Sweden in 1943, IKEA is short for Ingvar Kamprad (its founder), Elmtaryd (his family farm), and Agunnaryd (his hometown)—because even the name had to be complicated. Despite its global presence, the company remains privately owned, operating under a complex structure designed to reinvest profits into the business. The company offers affordable, Scandinavian-style furniture, quirky home goods, and decor designed to make your space look chic without emptying your bank account. But it’s not just about the furniture; IKEA stores are an experience, complete with sprawling showrooms, a maze-like floor plan (escape if you can), and a food court serving their famous meatballs and other Swedish delights. Love it or dread it, IKEA is where practicality meets design—with a side of Allen wrenches and “some assembly required” warnings.</p>

<p>IKEA’s journey to Singapore began in 1978, marking its first venture into Southeast Asia. Starting small, IKEA initially operated in Sixth Avenue, offering a limited selection of Scandinavian furniture that intrigued locals with its simplicity and practicality. As the brand gained traction, it moved to bigger premises at Alexandra Road in 1984, becoming a household name synonymous with affordable, stylish home solutions. This flagship store introduced Singaporeans to its now-iconic showroom concept, flat-pack furniture, and the unique art of assembling it with an Allen wrench. Fast forward to 2006, IKEA expanded eastward with its largest store in Tampines, catering to the growing demand for chic yet functional furniture—and perhaps also testing how far Singaporeans are willing to travel for a plate of Swedish meatballs.</p>

<p>In 2021, IKEA brought its magic even closer to heartland shoppers with the opening of a smaller store in Jurong at Jem mall. Unlike its sprawling counterparts, the Jurong outlet focuses on convenience, catering to time-strapped Singaporeans with curated displays and more compact shopping spaces. Together, Alexandra, Tampines, and Jurong make up IKEA’s trio of stores in Singapore, each offering the brand’s signature blend of Scandinavian design, affordable pricing, and the thrill of navigating its maze-like layouts. Whether you’re stocking up on BILLY bookcases or indulging in seasonal treats, IKEA’s presence in Singapore has become more than just a shopping destination—it’s a quintessential part of the local lifestyle.</p>

<h3 id="why-do-people-like-ikea-and-what-is-ikea-really-good-for-in-singapore">Why do people like Ikea and what is Ikea really good for in Singapore?</h3>

<p>People love IKEA for its unique ability to make home furnishing feel accessible, stylish, and, most importantly, affordable. In Singapore, where space is often limited, IKEA’s functional and space-saving designs are a lifesaver for city living. The brand’s flat-pack concept means you can fit an entire wardrobe into your car (if you’ve mastered the art of Tetris) and save money by assembling it yourself—whether it ends in triumph or tears. Beyond the products, IKEA is an experience: wandering through its maze-like showrooms, dreaming up new home ideas, and rewarding yourself with Swedish meatballs at the end. It’s also a go-to for families, with its kid-friendly areas, easy parking, and a place to pick up everything from furniture to snacks in one trip.</p>

<p>In Singapore, IKEA excels at providing affordable solutions for small spaces, from multifunctional furniture to clever storage systems. Its minimalist Scandinavian aesthetic is perfect for those who want their homes to look Instagram-ready without hiring an interior designer. It’s also great for last-minute seasonal decorations, thanks to its constant stream of new arrivals. Whether you’re furnishing your first rental, upgrading your HDB flat, or just need a reason to eat meatballs, IKEA has carved out a niche as a one-stop-shop for practical, stylish living.</p>

<h3 id="whats-there-to-buy-in-ikea">What’s there to buy in Ikea?</h3>

<p>IKEA offers a wide range of products categorized to cover almost every aspect of home furnishing and decor. Here are the main categories:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Furniture: Everything from beds, sofas, and dining tables to wardrobes, shelves, and outdoor furniture.</li>
  <li>Home Decor: Rugs, mirrors, curtains, and lighting to add personality and style to your space.</li>
  <li>Kitchen and Dining: Cookware, tableware, kitchen accessories, and even entire modular kitchen systems.</li>
  <li>Storage Solutions: Boxes, baskets, cabinets, and organizers for decluttering every room.</li>
  <li>Bedroom Essentials: Mattresses, bedding, pillows, and wardrobes to help you sleep (and store) in comfort.</li>
  <li>Bathroom Accessories: Towels, shower curtains, and storage for toiletries.</li>
  <li>Children’s Items: Kids’ furniture, toys, and decor designed for little ones.</li>
  <li>Workspace Essentials: Desks, chairs, and accessories for your home office.</li>
  <li>Textiles: Cushions, blankets, and covers to add warmth and color.</li>
  <li>Food: Swedish delights, including meatballs, snacks, and frozen products from the food market.</li>
</ul>

<p>From big-ticket items to small accessories, IKEA’s got it all under one massive roof—or three, in Singapore’s case.</p>

<h3 id="some-popular-items-in-ikea-by-product-name">Some popular items in Ikea by product name</h3>

<p>Here’s a list of popular IKEA items by product name that Singaporeans can’t seem to get enough of:</p>

<ul>
  <li>BILLY Bookcase – The ultimate storage solution for books, decor, and more.</li>
  <li>MALM Bed Frame – A sleek, minimalist bed frame with built-in storage options.</li>
  <li>POÄNG Armchair – An iconic, comfortable chair perfect for relaxing.</li>
  <li>LACK Coffee Table – Simple, affordable, and versatile for any living room.</li>
  <li>HEMNES Series – Timeless wooden furniture for bedrooms and living spaces.</li>
  <li>KLIPPAN Sofa – A compact, budget-friendly sofa that fits in small spaces.</li>
  <li>TROFAST Storage – A modular storage system great for organizing kids’ toys.</li>
  <li>RÅSKOG Utility Cart – A multi-functional rolling cart for kitchens, bathrooms, or workspaces.</li>
  <li>FÖRNUFTIG Air Purifier – Affordable and stylish air purifier for cleaner air at home.</li>
  <li>KALLAX Shelf Unit – A versatile shelving system for storage and display.</li>
</ul>

<p>These items are staples in many Singaporean homes, combining functionality, design, and affordability.</p>

<h3 id="what-does-ikea-singapore-offer-in-seasonal-moments">What does Ikea singapore offer in seasonal moments?</h3>

<p>IKEA Singapore knows how to make each season feel special with festive offerings and decor to match the occasion.</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>For Chinese New Year, IKEA transforms its stores with vibrant red and gold decorations, floral arrangements like pussy willows, and festive tableware to brighten your reunion dinners. They also offer exclusive seasonal items like Chinese New Year-themed home accessories, lucky decor, and sweet treats in their food market, such as pineapple tarts and cookies—perfect for gifting or enjoying with family.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>During Christmas, IKEA brings out a selection of Scandinavian-inspired decor, including artificial trees, wreaths, ornaments, and twinkling lights to help you create a cozy holiday atmosphere. The food market serves up seasonal delights like gingerbread cookies and Swedish glögg (mulled wine), adding a taste of Christmas traditions to your home.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>For Hari Raya, IKEA offers practical solutions for preparing your home for open houses, with stylish storage and organizing options for the post-celebration cleanup. You’ll also find festive textiles and decorations in vibrant colors, perfect for brightening up your living space during the holiday.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>For Deepavali, IKEA caters to the festive spirit with colorful textiles, candles, and home decor items to add warmth and vibrancy to your celebrations. Their range of lighting and decor pieces is perfect for creating a cozy, inviting atmosphere for family and friends during this special time.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>With each seasonal moment, IKEA Singapore goes beyond just decor, offering a mix of products and food items that help make every celebration feel complete. Whether you’re hosting a grand reunion dinner or simply enjoying a quiet holiday at home, IKEA ensures you’ll find something to suit every festive need.</p>

<h3 id="what-does-ikea-have-for-chinese-new-year-2025">What does Ikea have for Chinese New Year 2025?</h3>

<p>For Chinese New Year 2025, IKEA Singapore is celebrating the Year of the Snake with its exclusive FÖSSTA festive collection, available in-store and online from January 20, 2025. The FÖSSTA collection brings a vibrant touch to your home, offering a range of festive items designed to add warmth and style to your celebrations.</p>

<p>FÖSSTA Collection Highlights:</p>
<ul>
  <li>FÖSSTA LED Lantern: A battery-operated red lantern to add a warm glow to your home.</li>
  <li>FÖSSTA Duvet Cover and Pillowcases: A pomegranate and yellow set to brighten your bedroom.</li>
  <li>FÖSSTA Organiser: A red organiser to keep your space tidy and festive.</li>
  <li>FÖSSTA Bowl: A light green bowl with a petal design, perfect for serving treats.</li>
  <li>FÖSSTA Chopsticks: A set of four red chopsticks to complement your dining experience.</li>
</ul>

<p>What food should you order in Singapore Ikea?</p>

<p>Here’s an updated list of must-try food items to order at IKEA Singapore:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Swedish Meatballs – The iconic dish, served with creamy mashed potatoes and lingonberry sauce.</li>
  <li>IKEA Hotdog – A budget-friendly, delicious hotdog that’s perfect for a quick bite.</li>
  <li>Swedish Chicken Wings – Flavorful wings with a unique Swedish twist.</li>
  <li>IKEA Ice Cream – A sweet treat at an unbeatable price. Choose from vanilla, chocolate, or the soft-serve cone.</li>
  <li>Salmon Fillet – A healthy option with a light and flavorful taste.</li>
  <li>Cinnamon Buns – Fresh, warm, and sprinkled with sugar, they make for the perfect dessert.</li>
  <li>Daim Cake – A deliciously crunchy and creamy cake with pieces of Daim candy.</li>
  <li>Lamb Shank (Seasonal) – A hearty, tender lamb shank, perfect for seasonal feasts.</li>
  <li>Lobster (Seasonal) – A luxurious seafood treat, available during special seasons.</li>
</ul>

<p>These dishes provide a variety of options, from quick bites to indulgent meals, all at IKEA’s signature affordability.</p>

<h3 id="what-are-the-alternatives-to-ikea">What are the alternatives to Ikea?</h3>

<p>Here’s a list of alternatives to IKEA in Singapore for when you want something different or simply want to explore <a href="https://fromhktosg.github.io/furniture/">other furniture</a> and homeware options:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Castlery – A local brand offering stylish, mid-century modern furniture with a focus on quality and design.</li>
  <li>HipVan – An online furniture store with affordable, trendy pieces and free delivery above a certain amount.</li>
  <li>FortyTwo – A budget-friendly online platform with a wide range of furniture, decor, and even appliances.</li>
  <li>Muji – For minimalistic Japanese designs, Muji offers sleek furniture and practical home items with a calm aesthetic.</li>
  <li>Courts – A one-stop shop for furniture, electronics, and home appliances, with many physical locations.</li>
  <li>Harvey Norman – A great option for both furniture and household electronics with frequent promotions.</li>
  <li>Journey East – Specializing in vintage, reclaimed, and sustainable furniture with a unique, eco-friendly edge.</li>
  <li>Taylor B Fine Design – Perfect for those seeking luxury furniture with an eclectic mix of styles.</li>
  <li>Hock Siong &amp; Co. – A treasure trove of pre-loved and vintage furniture for a more sustainable choice.</li>
  <li>Urban Outfitters Home (via ASOS) – While not local, their quirky home decor pieces can be shipped to Singapore for something truly different.</li>
</ul>

<p>Whether you’re looking for affordable options, sustainable picks, or high-end luxury, Singapore has plenty of alternatives to cater to all tastes and budgets! Check out our previous furniture article for more details.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Singapore" /><category term="ikea" /><category term="furniture" /><category term="shopping" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[IKEA – the Swedish furniture giant that somehow convinces us flat-packed chaos is a life skill we all need. With its maze-like stores, budget-friendly meatballs, and those adorable blue-and-yellow tote bags, IKEA has built an empire in Singapore that’s as iconic as the MRT.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/ike.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/ike.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Guide to 2025 Chinese Dramas in Singapore</title><link href="/singapore-chinese-dramas-2025/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Guide to 2025 Chinese Dramas in Singapore" /><published>2025-01-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/singapore-chinese-dramas-2025</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-chinese-dramas-2025/"><![CDATA[<p>Chinese dramas—whether binge-watched on weekends or sneakily consumed during office lunch breaks—seem to hold a special place in the hearts of Singaporeans</p>

<p>For the uninitiated, Chinese TV dramas are a rich tapestry of sweeping romances, intense palace intrigues, and occasionally questionable CGI. But why do Singaporeans love them so much? Maybe it’s the nostalgia of seeing familiar Asian values, or maybe it’s the sheer joy of watching 50 episodes of dramatic misunderstandings unfold. From historical epics to modern urban tales, these dramas span categories that cater to every taste—and yes, they’re just a click away on various streaming platforms. Let’s dive into the top Chinese dramas of 2024 and the early favorites of 2025.</p>

<h3 id="what-are-chinese-tv-dramas">What are Chinese TV dramas?</h3>

<p>Chinese TV dramas, often called C-dramas, are television series produced in China, known for their diverse storylines, rich cultural elements, and highly addictive plots. These shows come in various genres, from sweeping historical epics (xianxia and wuxia fantasies) to modern urban romances and slice-of-life comedies. They often feature intricate storytelling, stunning costumes, and an ability to drag viewers into an emotional rollercoaster for 30 to 60 episodes—or more, if the producers get too ambitious. While some dramas are rooted in Chinese history and folklore, others reflect contemporary societal themes with a touch of melodrama. Whether you’re here for the jaw-dropping palace betrayals or a painfully slow-burn love story, there’s a C-drama for everyone.</p>

<h3 id="why-do-singaporeans-like-chinese-tv-dramas">Why do Singaporeans like Chinese TV dramas?</h3>

<p>Singaporeans love Chinese TV dramas partly because of their stunning casts, led by actresses who are practically walking perfection. Actresses like Zhao Lusi 赵露思 and Yang Zi 杨紫 bring both charm and relatability, making it easy for viewers to root for their characters—or binge entire seasons just for their performances. Male leads like Xiao Zhan 肖战 and Wang Yibo 王一博 also play a big role, with their brooding looks and on-screen charisma driving fans wild. Their flawless appearances, coupled with impeccable acting skills, often leave viewers swooning or aspiring to their beauty and fashion choices. Watching these actors and actresses light up the screen gives Singaporeans an irresistible mix of escapism, admiration, and just the right dose of fangirling that keeps them hooked on C-dramas.</p>

<h3 id="types-of-chinese-tv-dramas">Types of Chinese TV dramas</h3>

<p>Chinese TV dramas come in a variety of genres, each catering to different tastes and moods. Here’s a quick rundown:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Historical Dramas (古装剧) – Set in ancient times, featuring royal court intrigue, epic battles, and elaborate costumes (e.g., Story of Yanxi Palace 《延禧攻略》).</li>
  <li>Fantasy Dramas (玄幻剧) – Often featuring mythical creatures, magic, and gods, like Eternal Love 《三生三世十里桃花》 (xianxia, anyone?).</li>
  <li>Wuxia Dramas (武侠剧) – Focused on martial arts heroes and their chivalrous journeys (e.g., The Legend of the Condor Heroes 《射雕英雄传》).</li>
  <li>Modern Romance (现代爱情剧) – Set in contemporary times, with relatable characters and love stories (e.g., Go Go Squid! 《亲爱的，热爱的》).</li>
  <li>Slice-of-Life Dramas (生活剧) – Depict everyday struggles and family relationships (e.g., A Little Reunion 《小欢喜》).</li>
  <li>Crime and Mystery (悬疑剧) – Filled with suspense, detectives, and thrilling storylines (e.g., Day and Night 《白夜追凶》).</li>
  <li>Youth and School Dramas (青春校园剧) – Focus on first loves, friendship, and growing up (e.g., A Love So Beautiful 《致我们单纯的小美好》).</li>
  <li>Business and Workplace Dramas (职场剧) – Highlight corporate rivalries, start-ups, and ambition (e.g., Ode to Joy 《欢乐颂》).</li>
  <li>War and Patriotism (战争剧) – Focus on historical conflicts or national pride (e.g., The Disguiser 《伪装者》).</li>
  <li>Sci-Fi (科幻剧) – A smaller but growing genre, featuring futuristic themes (e.g., Three-Body 《三体》).</li>
</ul>

<p>With such a variety, it’s no wonder Singaporeans always find something to binge!</p>

<h3 id="where-can-you-watch-chinese-tv-dramas-in-singapore">Where can you watch Chinese TV dramas in Singapore?</h3>

<p>In Singapore, watching Chinese TV dramas is almost too easy, thanks to the abundance of streaming platforms and TV channels. Here’s where you can tune in:</p>

<ul>
  <li>iQIYI (爱奇艺) – A top streaming service for C-dramas, offering both free and VIP options. Think of it as Netflix, but with more palace intrigue.</li>
  <li>Viu – Popular for Korean content, but it also streams many trending Chinese dramas with subtitles. (Bonus: It’s user-friendly and affordable!)</li>
  <li>WeTV (腾讯视频国际版) – Run by Tencent, it’s great for xianxia and wuxia fans looking for HD drama perfection.</li>
  <li>YouTube – Several Chinese TV channels, like CCTV and Mango TV, post full episodes of dramas legally (yes, really).</li>
  <li>Netflix – Limited selection but high quality, featuring global hits like The Untamed 《陈情令》 and Eternal Love 《三生三世十里桃花》.</li>
  <li>Mediacorp Channel 8 – Good old TV still airs Chinese dramas, for those who enjoy a dose of nostalgia and nightly cliffhangers.</li>
  <li>Disney+ – Surprisingly, they’ve been adding Chinese dramas, like Delicacies Destiny 《珍馐记》, to their growing library.</li>
  <li>HBO GO – Has a small but premium collection of Chinese dramas for fans of critically acclaimed shows.</li>
  <li>Bilibili (哔哩哔哩) – Perfect for a younger crowd, with some quirky and popular C-dramas available for free streaming.</li>
</ul>

<p>From your smartphone to your flat-screen TV, there’s no shortage of ways to get your C-drama fix. The real challenge? Deciding which platform has your favorite Zhao Lusi series. And then there are the streaming sites…</p>

<h3 id="top-chinese-dramas-of-2024">Top chinese dramas of 2024</h3>

<p>Here’s my list of top Chinese dramas of 2024, with plot summaries:</p>

<ol>
  <li>My Journey to You 《云之羽》</li>
</ol>

<p>Plot: A skilled assassin infiltrates a noble clan to complete a dangerous mission, only to find love, betrayal, and hidden truths.
Lead Actress: Yu Shuxin 虞书欣
Lead Actor: Zhang Linghe 张凌赫</p>

<ol>
  <li>Fireworks of My Heart 《我的人间烟火》</li>
</ol>

<p>Plot: A firefighter and a doctor, childhood sweethearts with a rocky past, reunite and rediscover their love amidst danger and duty.
Lead Actress: Yang Yang 杨洋
Lead Actor: Wang Churan 王楚然</p>

<ol>
  <li>Destined 《长风渡》</li>
</ol>

<p>Plot: A street-smart woman and a reserved scholar navigate an arranged marriage, learning to trust and love each other in turbulent times.
Lead Actress: Bai Jingting 白敬亭
Lead Actor: Song Yi 宋轶</p>

<ol>
  <li>Lost You Forever 《长相思》</li>
</ol>

<p>Plot: A princess disguises herself as a healer, hiding her royal identity while caught in a love triangle and fighting for her kingdom.
Lead Actress: Yang Zi 杨紫
Lead Actor: Zhang Wanyi 张晚意</p>

<ol>
  <li>The Longest Promise 《玉骨遥》</li>
</ol>

<p>Plot: A teacher-disciple romance unfolds amidst political power struggles, forbidden love, and heartbreaking sacrifices in a fantasy kingdom.
Lead Actress: Ren Min 任敏
Lead Actor: Xiao Zhan 肖战</p>

<ol>
  <li>Till the End of the Moon 《长月烬明》</li>
</ol>

<p>Plot: A demon lord falls in love with a righteous woman sent back in time to prevent him from destroying the world.
Lead Actress: Bai Lu 白鹿
Lead Actor: Luo Yunxi 罗云熙</p>

<ol>
  <li>Hidden Love 《偷偷藏不住》</li>
</ol>

<p>Plot: A girl with a longtime crush on her brother’s best friend gets her chance at romance as they cross paths again as adults.
Lead Actress: Zhao Lusi 赵露思
Lead Actor: Chen Zheyuan 陈哲远</p>

<ol>
  <li>The Love You Give Me 《你给我的喜欢》</li>
</ol>

<p>Plot: A woman reunites with her first love, now a single father, and they rekindle their romance while navigating co-parenting and old wounds.
Lead Actress: Wang Yuwen 王玉雯
Lead Actor: Wang Ziqi 王子奇</p>

<p>These dramas brought everything from heartfelt romances to epic fantasy battles, satisfying every kind of viewer.</p>

<h3 id="top-chinese-dramas-of-2025-so-far">Top chinese dramas of 2025 so far</h3>

<p>Here’s the updated list of top Chinese dramas released in 2025 from January till today’s date:</p>

<ol>
  <li>白月梵星</li>
</ol>

<p>Lead Actor: Ao Rui Peng (敖瑞鹏)
Lead Actress: Bai Lu (白鹿)
Plot Summary: A mystical tale set in a world where stars dictate destinies. The story follows a young woman caught in a love triangle between two celestial beings while navigating the complex world of the gods.</p>

<ol>
  <li>國色芳華</li>
</ol>

<p>Lead Actor: Yang Zi (杨紫)
Lead Actress: Li Xian (李现)
Plot Summary: A historical romance set in the Qing dynasty, this drama follows a talented woman who rises from obscurity to become a prominent figure in the imperial court, facing love, betrayal, and power struggles.</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>大奉打更人
Lead Actor: Wang He Di (王鹤棣)
Lead Actress: Tian Xi Wei (田曦薇)
Plot Summary: A period drama set in the ancient city of Da Feng, where a group of vigilantes works to uncover dark secrets and fight corruption in a land on the brink of war.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>异人之下之决战！碧游村</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>Lead Actor: Peng Yu Chang (彭昱畅)
Lead Actress: Wang Ying Lu (王影璐)
Plot Summary: Set in a world of supernatural beings, two powerful individuals face off in a high-stakes battle for control of the mysterious and enigmatic Biyou Village, which holds the secret to unimaginable power.</p>

<ol>
  <li>相思令 《相思令》
Lead Actor: Song Wei Long (宋威龙)
Lead Actress: Angelababy (杨颖)
Plot Summary: A heart-wrenching love story set against the backdrop of ancient China, where two lovers separated by political conflicts try to reunite, navigating betrayal, heartache, and sacrifices.</li>
</ol>

<p>Check these out! We’ll cover kdramas another time but enjoy these in the meanwhile.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Singapore" /><category term="TV" /><category term="chinese dramas" /><category term="actress" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chinese dramas—whether binge-watched on weekends or sneakily consumed during office lunch breaks—seem to hold a special place in the hearts of Singaporeans]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/drama.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/drama.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>