<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="zh"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="zh" /><updated>2023-09-02T01:12:38+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">From HK to SG | Expat Living Guide in Singapore</title><entry><title type="html">Furniture buying guide for Singapore expats and locals</title><link href="/furniture/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Furniture buying guide for Singapore expats and locals" /><published>2023-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/zh/furniture</id><content type="html" xml:base="/furniture/"><![CDATA[<p>Looking to furnish your newly bought home? From modern designer boutiques to charming vintage stores, Singapore offers a diverse range of furniture options for every taste and budget. So, whether you’re looking to furnish your new apartment, redecorate your home, or simply want to indulge in some retail therapy, here’s a guide to where to buy furniture.</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/zh/assets/images/ikea.jpg" alt="Ikea" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>Good ol’ Ikea</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<h4 id="signature-furniture-stores">Signature furniture stores</h4>

<p>If you’re in the market for some designer furniture, look no further than the hip neighborhood of <a href="https://fromhktosg.github.io/neighbourhood/">Tiong Bahru</a>. Here, you’ll find a range of stylish boutiques offering modern and contemporary furniture designs. At <a href="https://www.grafunkt.com/">Grafunkt</a>, you’ll find sleek, minimalist pieces that blend form and function seamlessly. Meanwhile, at <a href="https://www.thecommunelife.com/">Commune</a>, you’ll find a range of chic and affordable furniture made from sustainable materials. For a touch of Japanese charm, head over to <a href="https://www.muji.com/sg/products/list/Furniture%20and%20Interior">Muji</a>, where you’ll find simple and elegant furniture designs that are both stylish and functional.</p>

<p>If you’re on a budget, don’t despair. Singapore is also home to a range of value furniture stores. One such store is <a href="https://www.ikea.com/sg/en/?gclid=EAIaIQobChMIt8SC-Ly__gIVVnV9Ch1SwAhGEAAYASAAEgLBdfD_BwE&amp;gclsrc=aw.ds">IKEA</a>, which needs no introduction. At IKEA, you’ll find a range of affordable furniture pieces that are both stylish and functional. Alternatively, head over to <a href="https://www.furnituresg.com.sg/">FurnitureSG</a>, where you’ll find a range of affordable furniture options that are perfect for furnishing your new home.</p>

<p>For those who prefer a more vintage aesthetic, Singapore also has a range of charming vintage stores. At <a href="https://www.hocksiong.com.sg/">Hock Siong &amp; Co.</a>, you’ll find a range of unique vintage furniture pieces, as well as quirky vintage decor and accessories. Last but not least, the <a href="http://www.tanboonliat.com/">Tan Boon Liat building</a>. The Tan Boon Liat Building is a commercial building located in the Outram area of Singapore. It is known as a hub for furniture showrooms and interior design businesses. The building has a rich history, having been built in the 1930s and originally serving as a warehouse for Chinese goods. In recent years, it has become a popular destination for those looking to shop for furniture, with a wide range of options available from high-end designer pieces to more affordable selections. Some of these stores require reservations ahead of time so remember to call in advance!</p>

<p>If you’re ok with second hand, Carousel is the way to go, though make sure your seller is an honest fella.</p>

<h4 id="what-to-watch-out-for-when-buying-furniture">What to watch out for when buying furniture</h4>

<ul>
  <li>Quality - Make sure that the furniture you are purchasing is made of high-quality materials and is built to last. Look for solid wood construction (especially for wardrobes), sturdy joints, and high-quality finishes.</li>
  <li>Comfort - Test out chairs, sofas, sofa beds, and mattresses to make sure that they are comfortable and provide adequate support.</li>
  <li>Size and Scale - When buying furniture, it’s important to consider the size and scale of the piece in relation to the room it will be placed in. A large, bulky sofa may look great in a showroom, but it may overwhelm a small living room. Make sure that the furniture you are purchasing fits the space and complements the other pieces in the room.</li>
  <li>Functionality - Consider how the furniture will be used and whether it is functional for your needs. For example, if you have children or pets, you may want to opt for furniture that is easy to clean and durable. If you work from home, you may need a desk or office chair that provides adequate support for long periods of sitting.</li>
  <li>Price - Price is always a consideration when making a purchase, but it’s important to balance price with quality. While you may be tempted to opt for cheaper furniture, it may end up costing you more in the long run if it needs to be replaced frequently. Consider investing in higher-quality pieces that will last for years to come.</li>
  <li>Delivery and Assembly - Finally, consider the logistics of getting the furniture to your home. Make sure that the store offers delivery and assembly services and factor these costs into your budget</li>
  <li>Vibe - Make sure your furniture pieces complement each other. Getting an ID can always help with this</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="my-favourite-places-to-buy-furniture">My favourite places to buy furniture</h4>

<p>My furniture combination arises from these stores. Most if not all of these do delivery and assembly so no need to fret if you cannot wield a screwdriver.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Castlery - simple and modern</li>
  <li>Crate and barrel - quality furniture at mid to aspirational price points (now closed in Apr 2023)</li>
  <li>Harvey Norman - surprising discovery given its usually associated with electronic products. Harvey Norman does provide a solid selection of furniture and often throws in bulk purchasing discounts</li>
  <li>Ikea - good ol’ Ikea. The mecca of furniture stores. No one can deny their affordability and tasty swedish meatballs</li>
</ul>

<p>What are your favourite furniture places? Let me know in the comments below on where you bought your new coffee table, dining table or cabinets. Like and subscribe to follow me on more essentials of Singapore content.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Shopping" /><category term="Furniture" /><category term="Singapore" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Looking to furnish your newly bought home? From modern designer boutiques to charming vintage stores, Singapore offers a diverse range of furniture options for every taste and budget. So, whether you’re looking to furnish your new apartment, redecorate your home, or simply want to indulge in some retail therapy, here’s a guide to where to buy furniture.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/ikea.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/ikea.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Guide to the best Singapore neighbourhoods to live in</title><link href="/neighbourhood/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Guide to the best Singapore neighbourhoods to live in" /><published>2023-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/zh/neighbourhood</id><content type="html" xml:base="/neighbourhood/"><![CDATA[<p>Singapore is a bustling city-state with a diverse range of neighborhoods, each with its own unique features and attractions. Whether you’re a family with children, a young professional, or a retiree, there’s a neighborhood in Singapore that’s perfect for you. In this guide, we’ll take a look at the best neighborhoods to live in Singapore, what makes them stand out, and why they’re great places to call home. We’ll take an expat lens to this article given we’re assuming locals are already living in their existing family homes.</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/zh/assets/images/skyline.jpg" alt="skyline" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>Singapore skyline at night</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<h4 id="factors-to-consider-when-selecting-a-neighbourhood">Factors to consider when selecting a neighbourhood</h4>

<p>Reminder - this is largely dependent on your individual needs, preferences, and lifestyle</p>
<ol>
  <li>Proximity to work or school: Saves time and money on transportation</li>
  <li>Cost of living: The closer to the city center, the more expensive it’ll be. Determine your budget and look for neighborhoods that fit within your financial means</li>
  <li>Amenities and facilities: Consider the amenities and facilities that are important to you, such as <a href="https://fromhktosg.github.io/grocery/">grocery stores</a>, hawker centers, shopping malls, tennis courts and parks. Look for neighborhoods that offer easy access to the amenities and facilities that you need</li>
  <li>Transportation options: Closer to the MRT, more expensive it is. However, it makes commuting around the city more convenient and efficient</li>
  <li>Lifestyle and culture: Consider the vibe and atmosphere of the neighborhood to determine whether it is a good fit for your lifestyle and interests</li>
</ol>

<h4 id="how-does-singapore-classify-their-neighbourhoods">How does Singapore classify their neighbourhoods?</h4>

<p>There are a total of 28 districts in Singapore, numbered from 1 to 28. Directionally, districts 1 to 10 are in more central areas, whilst the higher numbers are more near the outskirts.</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/zh/assets/images/districts.jpg" alt="districts" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>Districts of Singapore</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<h4 id="popular-neighbourhoods-to-live-in">Popular neighbourhoods to live in</h4>

<p>On to the main course -</p>

<p><u> District 01 / 2 - Raffles Place, Marina, Tanjong Pagar <u></u></u></p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/zh/assets/images/tjp.jpg" alt="tjp" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>Source - Discover Tanjong Pagar</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>The Raffles Place Tanjong Pagar area is a bustling neighborhood in the heart of Singapore’s Central Business District (CBD). It’s in close proximity to Marina Bay Sands, several museums and galleries and the Merlion.</p>

<p>Pros:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Prime location to CBD and sightseeing spots</li>
  <li>Excellent transportation with the green and red train lines intercrossing. Plenty of buses to this area too</li>
  <li>High-end living close to luxurious shopping centers, five-star hotels and fine-dining restaurants</li>
  <li>Vibrant nightlife - plenty of bars and clubs</li>
</ul>

<p>Cons:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Not child friendly</li>
  <li>Limited space (reflected by a smaller number of condos there)</li>
  <li>Hustle and bustle on weekdays, dead on weekends</li>
  <li>Can be quite a touristy area</li>
  <li>Expensive (though not as pricey as Orchard)</li>
  <li>Lack of greenery - it’s primarily a concrete jungle</li>
</ul>

<p><u> District 15 - Joo Chiat, Marina Parade, Katong <u></u></u></p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/zh/assets/images/ecp.jpg" alt="ecp" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>Source - Time Out</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>Aka East Coast. The East Coast of Singapore refers to the eastern coastal region of the island nation. The area I’m most referring to is the Marina parade area near the beginning of East Coast park versus anything more in land i.e Geylang / Paya Lebar, or out further east i.e. Siglap.</p>

<p>Pros:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Beautiful beaches and parks</li>
  <li>Vast open spaces with larger size condos and bungalows. This is the primary reason for many</li>
  <li>Rich cultural heritage - cute architectural neighbourhoods nearby</li>
</ul>

<p>Cons:</p>
<ul>
  <li>High cost of living. The area ain’t cheap but PSF will still be slightly better than CBD / Orchard</li>
  <li>A little further from the city center, though a MRT line will be built in this region</li>
</ul>

<p><u> District 03 - Tiong Bahru, Alexandra, Queenstown <u></u></u></p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/zh/assets/images/tb.jpg" alt="tb" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>Source - Qantas</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>Tiong Bahru is a residential neighborhood in the central region of Singapore, located just a few kilometers from the city center. It is known for its unique architecture, art deco buildings, and vibrant street life. The neighborhood has a rich history, dating back to the 1920s, and was one of the first housing estates in Singapore. It was built to provide affordable housing for the working-class, and many of the original low-rise buildings still stand today. Tiong Bahru is a mix of old and new, with charming pre-war shophouses and modern high-rise apartments. It has become a trendy and hipster destination in recent years, with plenty of independent boutiques, cafes, and art galleries popping up. The Alexandra and Queenstown area are both fantastic living spots too, with a more residential vibe and cheaper rental prices.</p>

<p>Pros:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Hipster</li>
  <li>Still accessible to cbd</li>
  <li>Greenery areas</li>
  <li>Shophouse options versus condos</li>
  <li>Compared to some other central districts, District 3 offers more affordable housing options</li>
  <li>More peaceful / residential</li>
</ul>

<p>Cons:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Can be a little boring</li>
  <li>HDB-heavy (a concern for some)</li>
</ul>

<p><u> District 09 - Orchard Road, River Valley <u></u></u></p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/zh/assets/images/orchard.jpg" alt="orchard" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>Source - Edgeprop</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>This area is known for its high-end shopping malls, luxury apartments, and proximity to the Central Business District. It is a popular area for expats who want to live in the heart of the city and enjoy a luxurious lifestyle. River Valley is also a part of this district. With open spaces, convenience to CBD and international schools, River Valley is a popular expat living area.</p>

<p>Pros:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Lux - no further description required</li>
  <li>Likely capital preservation for property in the region</li>
  <li>Close to the largest shopping malls</li>
</ul>

<p>Cons:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Pricy - expect PSFs of 3.5K+</li>
</ul>

<p><u> District 10 - Bukit Timah, Holland, Balmoral <u></u></u></p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/zh/assets/images/hollandvillage.jpg" alt="holland" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>Source - 99.co</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>Holland Village is a trendy and vibrant neighborhood that is popular with expats. It offers a range of restaurants, bars, and cafes, as well as easy access to transportation. Popular condos include D’Leedon and Leedon Green. Bukit Timah is a little more northwest to Holland Village, and has a quaint neighbourhood mostly with bungalows. Perfect for that expat life.</p>

<p>Pros:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Prestigious schools (Singapore Chinese Girls’ School, Methodist Girls’ School, and Anglo-Chinese School)</li>
  <li>Expansive greenery and proximity to nature</li>
  <li>Quiet and peaceful</li>
  <li>Feels prestigious</li>
</ul>

<p>Cons:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Pricy</li>
  <li>Bungalow heavy so limited condo options</li>
  <li>A little further from central</li>
</ul>

<p>Personally, I value open space, greenery, a more quiet lifestyle and proximity to the city. Hence, the districts above are <strong>ranked based on my preference of least preferred to best preferred</strong>. That being said, all of these districts are fantastic locations to live in.</p>

<h4 id="what-about-the-heartlands">What about the Heartlands?</h4>

<p>The “heartlands” in Singapore generally refer to the residential estates located outside the city center. These are neighborhoods where many Singaporeans live, work, and go about their daily lives. The heartlands are known for their HDB flats (public housing apartments) and amenities such as hawker centers, community centers, parks, and shopping malls. Some of the more well-known heartland areas in Singapore include Ang Mo Kio, Bedok, Bukit Batok, Jurong East, Tampines, Toa Payoh, Woodlands and Yishun.</p>

<p>Pros:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Lower cost of living: Housing in the heartlands, especially HDB flats, is generally more affordable than in the city center. This can translate to lower living expenses and more savings</li>
  <li>Strong sense of community: The heartlands are known for their close-knit communities and friendly neighbors. Living in the heartlands can provide a sense of belonging and community spirit, which can be particularly beneficial for families with children or seniors</li>
  <li>Access to amenities and facilities: The heartlands have many amenities and facilities such as hawker centers, community centers, parks, and shopping malls. These offer convenient access to everyday necessities, as well as opportunities for leisure and recreation</li>
  <li>Good transportation connections: While the heartlands are further away from the city center, they are well-connected to public transportation, including MRT trains and buses. This makes commuting to work or school relatively easy and convenient</li>
  <li>Diverse cultural experiences: Singapore’s heartlands are home to a diverse mix of cultures and communities, each with their own unique character and traditions. Living in the heartlands can offer opportunities to experience and appreciate this cultural richness</li>
</ul>

<p>Cons:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Distance from the city center: The heartlands are located further away from the city center, so if you work or study in the central business district (CBD), you may have to factor in longer commuting times and transportation costs</li>
  <li>Lack of nightlife: While the heartlands have their own amenities, they may not offer as many options for entertainment and nightlife compared to the city center. If you enjoy going out and socializing, living in the heartlands may not be the best option for you</li>
  <li>HDB heavy. Personally not a problem for me but I know folks who care</li>
</ul>

<p>Overall, the heartlands of Singapore can offer a comfortable and affordable way of life, with access to all the amenities and facilities needed for daily living. It can be an ideal option for those who prioritize community, convenience, and value for money.</p>

<p>Whether you’re looking for a bustling shopping district, a laid-back expat enclave, a historic neighborhood with unique character, or a peaceful residential area surrounded by greenery, Singapore has a neighborhood that’s perfect for you. By exploring the top areas in Singapore, you’ll be able to find the best places to call home in this vibrant city-state. Which Singapore neighborhood do you live in and why? Subscribe now so you won’t miss out on the next post.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Neighbourhoods" /><category term="Living" /><category term="Housing" /><category term="Singapore" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Singapore is a bustling city-state with a diverse range of neighborhoods, each with its own unique features and attractions. Whether you’re a family with children, a young professional, or a retiree, there’s a neighborhood in Singapore that’s perfect for you. In this guide, we’ll take a look at the best neighborhoods to live in Singapore, what makes them stand out, and why they’re great places to call home. We’ll take an expat lens to this article given we’re assuming locals are already living in their existing family homes.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/skyline.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/skyline.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Guide to buying the Perfect Diamond Ring in Singapore… at 10% Off</title><link href="/diamond/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Guide to buying the Perfect Diamond Ring in Singapore… at 10% Off" /><published>2023-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/zh/diamond</id><content type="html" xml:base="/diamond/"><![CDATA[<p>Congratulations! You’re ready to take the plunge and propose to the love of your life. But before you get down on one knee, there’s one important thing you need to do: buy an engagement ring.</p>

<p>Purchasing a diamond ring is no easy feat, especially in Singapore. It’s a high expense item in an industry with plenty of marketing BS. No worries though - with a little planning and research from this guide, you can find the perfect ring for your special someone.</p>

<h4 id="your-5-steps-in-buying-the-right-ring">Your 5 steps in buying the right ring</h4>

<ol>
  <li>Set your budget</li>
  <li>Understand her requirements</li>
  <li>Research online</li>
  <li>Shop together in-store</li>
  <li>Buy alone, potentially abroad</li>
</ol>

<h5 id="step-1-set-your-budget">Step 1: Set your budget</h5>

<p>Setting a budget helps narrow down your options and avoid overspending.</p>

<p>The budget for an engagement ring is a highly personal decision and can vary greatly depending on individual circumstances. Some people may choose to spend several months’ salary on an engagement ring, while others may opt for a less expensive ring or even choose to forgo a ring altogether. You usually hear the benchmark of ‘spending 3 months of your salary’, which can be very low or very high depending on how much you earn.</p>

<p>Ultimately, the most important factor is to choose a ring that reflects your love and commitment to your partner, and fits comfortably within your overall financial plan. It’s important to prioritize your financial stability and avoid overspending on a ring, especially if it could lead to financial stress in the future. Communication with your partner about expectations and preferences can also help ensure that you both feel comfortable with the budget and the ring you ultimately choose.</p>

<h5 id="step-2-understand-her-diamond-requirements">Step 2: Understand her diamond requirements</h5>

<p>Here’s a top tip every man should know - there’s an inverse relationship between surprising your lady with a ring and getting the ring that she wants. I’m in the camp of ‘getting it right’ given I’ll be spending a hefty sum. This means asking all the right questions beforehand, researching online for inspiration and going into the store for further exploration and fitting. The element of surprise that you should fall back on is the proposal itself versus what the ring looks like.</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/zh/assets/images/surprise.jpg" alt="Surprise" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>Surprise versus getting it right</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>As part of understanding what she wants, here’s my list of seven ultimate questions to make sure you’re hitting her requirements</p>
<ol>
  <li>Does she want a diamond?</li>
  <li>Does she want a natural or lab diamond?</li>
  <li>Does the brand of the ring matter?</li>
  <li>Does she want to design her own ring?</li>
  <li>What are her 4C, shape and setting expectations? (more on that below)</li>
  <li>Can she tell the difference between the 4Cs, i.e. between a D and H in colour?</li>
  <li>What is her ring size?</li>
</ol>

<p>Let’s unpack some of these.</p>

<p><u> Diamond or something else <u></u></u></p>

<p>Diamonds are a classic and traditional choice for engagement rings, but other gemstones can offer unique and beautiful alternatives. Some popular gemstones for engagement rings include sapphires, emeralds, and rubies. These stones are known for their vibrant colors and can add a pop of color and personality to an engagement ring.</p>

<p><u> Natural vs lab diamond <u></u></u></p>

<p>TLDR - there’s not a huge difference between the two appearance wise. I’d recommend buying a lab diamond if your partner is ok with it given it’s much cheaper.</p>

<p>Lab-grown diamonds are created in a laboratory setting by replicating the conditions that result in the formation of natural diamonds. They are made up of the same material as natural diamonds, which is pure carbon arranged in a crystalline form. Natural diamonds, are formed over millions of years deep in the earth’s mantle under intense heat and pressure. They are mined from the earth and can vary in quality and size depending on where they were formed. Both types of diamonds have the same physical and chemical properties and can be virtually identical to the naked eye. Lab-grown diamonds are MUCH cheaper than natural diamonds (up to 4X) less than natural diamonds of the same quality and size. Please don’t buy a moissanite or some cubic zirconia. Your partner deserves better than that.</p>

<p><u> 4Cs <u></u></u></p>

<p>Carat weight - This refers to the weight of the diamond and is often the most well-known of the 4Cs. One carat is equal to 0.2 grams, and diamonds are typically sold in fractions of a carat. Carat usually ranges from 0.5 to 2.5, with inflection price points at 1, 1.2, 1.5, 2. For example, a 1 carat diamond is disproportionately pricier than a 0.95 carat diamond given its nice rounded number.</p>

<p>Cut - The cut refers to how well a diamond has been cut and shaped to maximize its brilliance, fire, and overall beauty. A well-cut diamond will reflect light and sparkle more than a poorly cut diamond, even if the other 3Cs are the same. Cut grades range from excellent to very good to good, fair then poor. Ignore marketing BS that says your diamond has a heart and arrow pattern (example) - all excellent cut diamonds will naturally have this.</p>

<p>Color - This refers to how colorless or “white” a diamond is. The less color a diamond has, the more valuable it is. Diamonds are graded on a scale from D (colorless) to Z (light yellow or brown). Aim for something in the range of D to H for a less yellowish diamond.</p>

<p>Clarity - This refers to the presence or absence of blemishes or inclusions, which are internal or external flaws in the diamond. Diamonds with fewer inclusions and blemishes are considered more valuable. The acceptable range I see is between Fl and VS2.</p>

<p>Whilst cut and carat may be more visible to the naked eye, clarity and colour is not. Check if your partner can tell the difference as a tier in colour or clarity can mean the difference in a few hundred or a thousand dollars. More on this later, but it shows the importance of knowing what factors can be traded off whilst working with your budget.</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/zh/assets/images/clarity.jpg" alt="clarity" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>Source - vrai</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p><u> Setting and shape <u></u></u></p>

<p>When it comes to choosing a ring shape and setting, there are many options available. Here are some of the most popular ring shapes and settings:</p>

<p>Ring shapes:</p>
<ol>
  <li>Round - This is the most popular and classic diamond shape, known for its brilliant sparkle and versatility.</li>
  <li>Princess - This square-shaped diamond is also popular and has a modern look with sharp corners and brilliant sparkle.</li>
  <li>Cushion - This diamond shape has rounded corners and is known for its vintage-inspired look and romantic feel.</li>
  <li>Emerald - This rectangular diamond shape has long facets that create a “hall of mirrors” effect and a sophisticated, elegant look.</li>
  <li>Oval - This diamond shape is similar to round but has an elongated shape that can make fingers appear longer and more slender.</li>
</ol>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center"><img src="/zh/assets/images/ringshape.jpg" alt="Shape" /></th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center"><em>Source - Diamonds Factory</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>A ring setting is the part of a ring that holds the gemstone in place. It is typically made of metal (such as gold, platinum, or silver) and may feature prongs, bezels, or other types of clasps to secure the gemstone. The setting can play a big role in the overall look and feel of a ring. For example, a simple and classic prong setting can highlight the beauty of a center diamond, while a more intricate and ornate setting can add character and personality to a ring. Each luxury brand has their signature setting so be sure to check them out!</p>

<h4 id="step-3-research-online">Step 3: Research online</h4>

<p>To ease into the subject with your partner, I’d recommend first starting off with online research, whether that’s looking at jewelry sites or taking a peak at your friend’s engagement ring photos. Take the chance to feel out what she likes and make a mental note of it.</p>

<h4 id="step-4-shop-together-in-store">Step 4: Shop together in-store</h4>

<p>Alongside the traditional jewelry powerhouses, more and more boutique / local brands have popped up.</p>

<p><u> Local Singaporean brands <u></u></u></p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://shop.leehwajewellery.com/">Lee Hwa Jewelry</a>: Around since 1970 and is one of the largest fine jewelry retailers in Singapore. They offer a wide range of jewelry pieces, from traditional to contemporary designs</li>
  <li><a href="https://www.skjewellery.com/">SK Jewellery</a>: Affordable and trendy jewelry pieces that are perfect for everyday wear. They offer a range of designs, from minimalist to statement pieces.</li>
  <li><a href="https://www.jannpaul.com/">Jann Paul</a>: JannPaul’s signature product is the “Super Ideal Cut” diamond, which is cut to perfection using precise mathematical calculations to maximize the diamond’s brilliance, fire, and scintillation</li>
  <li><a href="https://love-and-co.com/">Love and Co</a>: One of Love &amp; Co.’s signature product is the “LVC Promise Diamond,” which is a diamond that has a special inscription on the girdle of the diamond. This inscription is only visible under a special magnifying glass and serves as a symbol of the couple’s promise to each other</li>
  <li><a href="https://www.carat55.com/">Carat 55</a>: Carat 55 offers a personalized service where customers can work with their team of expert designers to create unique and custom-made jewelry pieces.</li>
</ul>

<p>These brands have a mix of lab / natural diamonds at various price points, and are great value options. The quality of the diamond may vary but you’ll still be able to get top end stuff if you select the right rock.</p>

<p><u> International brands <u></u></u></p>

<p>These brands may cost up to 3-6X more than the local brands listed above. You’ll be paying a premium for the guarantee of a quality diamond, stellar craftsmanship and brand prestige.</p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="https://www.cartier.sg/">Cartier</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.harrywinston.com/en/fine-jewelry/engagement-rings?gclid=EAIaIQobChMIv8mu6Iyt_gIVfZlmAh0WRAYAEAAYASAAEgKsbPD_BwE">Harry Winston</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.vancleefarpels.com/sg/en/home.html">VCA</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.tiffany.sg/?omcid=ppc-sg_google_brand-core&amp;utm_medium=cpc-sg&amp;utm_source=google-paid&amp;utm_campaign=ao-search&amp;utm_content=brand+core+TiffanyT&amp;gclid=EAIaIQobChMIgMTT8Iyt_gIV2iQrCh0hqwuYEAAYASAAEgJ18vD_BwE">Tiffany</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.graff.com/sg-en/home/?gclid=Cj0KCQjwlumhBhClARIsABO6p-w5b0AmVNO2uXQV8Q4bGQozOQ09Fois3oMdctfhhq34nd0UrsFgngcaAmLYEALw_wcB">Graff</a></li>
</ul>

<p>Each brand has its own rich history and heritage. Cartier has been around since 1847 and has a long history of creating iconic jewelry pieces for royalty and celebrities. Harry Winston is known for its high-quality diamonds and has been a favorite of celebrities for decades. VCA was founded in 1906 and is known for its unique and intricate jewelry designs. Tiffany has been around since 1837 and is known for its iconic blue box and classic designs. Graff is a relatively newer brand, founded in 1960, but has quickly gained a reputation for its exceptional diamonds and innovative designs. Note - DeBeers is no longer in Singapore but you can always order them online. Chopard does exist but selection is limited.</p>

<p>Try these brands on! As much as similar designs exist amongst them, the emotional feeling for each ring differs.</p>

<p><strong>How pricing works</strong></p>

<p>For local brands - <a href="https://www.jannpaul.com/diamond-price-guide">here’s</a> a pricing guide from Jann paul that I really like. For a 1 carat diamond ring price, lab grown will be around $3500 SGD and natural will be around $10000 SGD.</p>

<p>For international brands, pricing really varies. However, I can give you the directional economics behind pricing for one of these international boutiques</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Change in carat</strong>: +0.01CT → $200 SGD</li>
  <li><strong>Change in clarity</strong>: +1 range in clarity (VS1 to VVS2) → $700 SGD</li>
  <li><strong>Change in colour</strong>: +1 in colour (H to G) → $3K SGD</li>
  <li><strong>Change in metal</strong>: Rose Gold / Yellow Gold to Platinum Gold → $600 SGD</li>
</ul>

<p>Again, these are factors you can trade off to best fit the ideal ring in your budget.</p>

<p><u> Resale value of diamond rings <u></u></u></p>

<p>I would not bank on it reselling for the same amount, unless you’re buying a high quality diamond from an international brand. Overall, the resale value of a diamond can range anywhere from 20% to 60% of its retail value, depending on the factors mentioned above. It’s always a good idea to get an appraisal from a reputable diamond dealer or jeweler to get an accurate estimate of the resale value of your diamond.</p>

<h4 id="step-5-buy-alone">Step 5: Buy alone</h4>

<p>First off, I recommend buying the diamond alone to maintain the surprise factor and to keep the price of the ring under wraps. Second, I recommend buying the diamond outside of Singapore if you are buying from one of the international brands. Prices are generally the same internationally, but tax refunds will allow you to save up to 12% (country dependent) of total price. Say you are looking to buy a SGD $30,000 ring. Instead of buying it in Singapore, buying it in Paris will cost you $26,400 instead. That’s $3,600 in savings. You can totally fly to Paris for the weekend, pick up the ring and fly back to Singapore and you’ll still be spending less than buying in town! Even if you declare and pay 7% GST when you bring the ring back to Singapore, you are getting a 5% discount. Always buy abroad if you have the option. It’ll make your expensive ring feel like an affordable ring.</p>

<hr />

<p>In conclusion, buying a diamond ring can be a significant decision that requires careful consideration. It is essential to understand the different aspects of diamond quality. Whether purchasing an engagement ring or a piece of jewelry for a special occasion, it is crucial to work with a reputable jeweler who can provide guidance and advice on selecting the perfect diamond ring. With proper research and a clear understanding of your needs and budget, buying a diamond ring can be a memorable and meaningful experience that will bring joy and happiness for years to come. I know I loved my ring shopping journey.</p>

<p>I hope this guide is helpful to provide a glimpse into ring buying in Singapore. Let me know if you have other ring shopping tactics. In case you missed my last <a href="https://fromhktosg.github.io/grocery/">post</a>, I talked about best places to buy gorceries in Singapore. Subscribe now so you won’t miss out on the next post.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Shopping" /><category term="Diamonds" /><category term="Proposal" /><category term="Singapore" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Congratulations! You’re ready to take the plunge and propose to the love of your life. But before you get down on one knee, there’s one important thing you need to do: buy an engagement ring.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/diamond.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/diamond.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">新加坡的最佳雜貨店和超市 - 基本知識、精品店和我的價值購物策略</title><link href="/grocery/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="新加坡的最佳雜貨店和超市 - 基本知識、精品店和我的價值購物策略" /><published>2023-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/zh/grocery</id><content type="html" xml:base="/grocery/"><![CDATA[<p>嘿，大家好！今天我們要來聊一聊新加坡的必去雜貨店和超市，以及我選購特定雜貨的心得。在開始之前，我要先坦白，我可是超市迷。我特別喜歡在國外逛各種不同的超市，所以今天的主題讓我非常興奮，希望你也能感受到同樣的興奮。</p>

<h4 id="新加坡的糧食來源">新加坡的糧食來源</h4>
<p>首先，讓我們了解一下新加坡是如何獲得食物的。作為一個小島國家，新加坡高度依賴進口來確保食品供應。事實上，新加坡有高達90%的食品是進口的。馬來西亞是新加坡的主要食品供應國之一，因為它與新加坡相鄰。儘管新加坡正在積極尋求多元化的食品供應國家，並發展本地食品生產能力，但全球經濟和地緣政治因素總是會直接影響到食品供應和價格（例如，如果馬來西亞禁止出口雞肉，將對新加坡造成什麼影響？）。順帶一提，我幾乎不可能在新加坡找到一個像樣的番茄，除非它們是高級的有著藤蔓的番茄。</p>

<h4 id="超市大戰">超市大戰</h4>
<p>現在，讓我們來談談新加坡的超市巨頭們。這裡有四家主要的超市連鎖店：Fairprice、Cold Storage、Sheng Shiong和Giant。每家超市連鎖店都有他們自己的忠誠計劃和信用卡合作夥伴關係，所以當你去購物時，記得要留意這些優惠，以便最大化你的價值回饋。</p>

<p><u>Fairprice<u>
首先，我們來談談Fairprice。這是新加坡最大的零售商，擁有大約100家分店，是新加坡全國職工總會（NTUC）的合作社。如果要在香港找一個相似的超市，那就是Parknshop。</u></u></p>
<ul>
  <li>Fairprice有幾個主要的分店：</li>
  <li>Fairprice / fairprice shop（這是他們的常規超市）</li>
  <li>Fairprice Xtra（這個超市有食品和家居用品）</li>
  <li>Fairprice Xpress（通常位於埃克森石油加油站）</li>
  <li>Fairprice Finest（這個分店價格較高，但提供更多進口產品，感覺更高檔）</li>
  <li>Warehouse club（這是新加坡版的Costco。但老實說，除非你住在它的附近，否則不太值得去，而且那裡的國際品牌和Kirkland品牌的商品種類有限）。</li>
</ul>

<p><u>Cold Storage<u>
現在，讓我們來聊聊Cold Storage。在新加坡有約50多家Cold Storage分店，如果要找個香港的對比，可以想像成Welcome。這裡的價格稍微高一些，但提供了許多進口選擇。</u></u></p>
<ul>
  <li>Cold Storage有一些主要的分店：</li>
  <li>Cold Storage（普通超市）</li>
  <li>Cold Storage fresh（高檔體驗）</li>
  <li>Jason’s Deli（更像是便利店的體驗）</li>
</ul>

<p>#<u>昇菘 Sheng Shiong<u>
這家主要分布在新加坡的核心地帶。老實說，我在新加坡待了五年，但似乎只踏進過一家昇菘。價格似乎比Fairprice和Cold Storage便宜（正如這篇文章所證實的那樣）。我對昇菘沒有偏見，只是它離我住的地方較遠。</u></u></p>

<p><u>Giant<u>
Giant 是一家來自馬來西亞的大型超市。這裡的價格非常優惠，選擇也非常豐富。
Giant有一些主要的分店，名稱簡單明了：</u></u></p>
<ul>
  <li>Giant hypermarket</li>
  <li>Giant超市</li>
  <li>Giant express</li>
</ul>

<p>#### 
那麼，日本和中國的超市連鎖店如何呢？
在過去幾年中，新加坡出現了一個新興的超市類別，就是日本和中國的超市連鎖店（大規模的韓國超市連鎖店還沒有進入這個市場）。以下是我最喜歡的幾家：</p>

<p><u>Don Don Donki（DDDK）<u>
這家日本超市連鎖店在新加坡有約15家分店，雖然價格稍微高一些，但他們的產品真的很棒，特別是肉類和米袋。他們還出售熟食，如便當、章魚燒，價格實惠。過了晚上9點，熟食會有更多的折扣。不過，我覺得他們的蔬菜有些價高，所以我會避開那個區域。</u></u></p>

<p><u>Mediya<u>
Mediya就像唐唐唐，但不會播放瘋狂的音樂。他們有兩家大小可觀的店，提供大規模進口的日本產品。個人而言，我非常喜歡他們的豆製品和肉類貨架。</u></u></p>

<p><u>思家客<u>
這是一家2020年開業並迅速擴張的中國連鎖雜貨店（約有15家分店）。Scarlett專門經營當地中國小吃、糖果和飲料，還有一小部分的農產品和冷凍食品。順便一提，他們有10升裝的啤酒。</u></u></p>

<p><u>裕華 Yue Hwa<u>
聽起來耳熟能詳嗎？對，這就是在香港的裕華。他們提供各種各樣的中國乾貨和醫療產品（包括中國、香港、台灣的商品），位於唐人街的旗艦店甚至販售家居用品。特別是我會在裕華囤積餅乾捲。但請注意，店內並沒有新鮮農產品。</u></u></p>

<h4 id="那麼美食雜貨店呢">那麼，美食雜貨店呢？</h4>

<p>有很多店都屬於這個類別，所以我只會強調一些眾所周知或我經常光顧的店。</p>

<p><u>Little Farms<u>
在6個地點，小農場提供高品質的天然和有機農產品。個人而言，我很少在他們那裡購物，因為他們的產品相當昂貴。唯一的例外是他們的鷹嘴豆泥/醬料 - 他們的選擇實在是太美味了。</u></u></p>

<p><u>Culina<u>
Dempsey是美食和高檔生活的天堂。Culina Marketplace是那裡供應各種美食的好地方之一。事實上，Culina是許多Fairprice Finest店的肉類供應商。我曾在Culina Bistro用餐，覺得很一般，但整個市場有很多美食區可以參觀，包括麵包店、魚販、肉店、新鮮農產品和乾貨區。</u></u></p>

<p><u>Hubers<u>
如果我要辦燒烤派對，這是我首選的肉類店。它比上面列出的所有雜貨店都有最廣泛的新鮮和冷凍肉類選擇，你可以根據不同的價格範圍購買。Hubers還有一些你可以選擇的調味選項。</u></u></p>

<h4 id="到街市值得嗎">到街市值得嗎？</h4>
<p>新加坡的街市常與小販中心位於同一個綜合建築內，但規模比香港小得多。雖然水果、蔬菜和魚店很常見，但我發現有更少的肉店，尤其是專營牛肉的肉店。你通常會看到已經切好的家禽/豬肉/牛肉，而不是整個動物的屍體，這在香港街市很常見。總的來說，我覺得新加坡的購物體驗相對平淡。除了偶爾在這裡買水果和蔬菜之外，我不建議在街市購物。</p>

<h4 id="新加坡哪些食品比香港貴">新加坡哪些食品比香港貴？</h4>
<p>總之，由於進口稅的原因，所有東西都比香港貴。一些特別昂貴的物品包括：</p>
<ul>
  <li>熟肉類（火腿、培根、香腸約比香港貴30％）</li>
  <li>酒精（新加坡對煙酒類課徵高額稅款）</li>
  <li>冰淇淋（Ben and Jerrys +Häagen-Dazs 的一品膳成本約為11美元/品膳，是美國的1.7倍)</li>
  <li>奶酪（與歐洲相比荒謬）</li>
  <li>沙拉葉菜</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="我常去的雜貨店">我常去的雜貨店</h4>
<p>我幾乎每天都做飯，所以我經常光顧雜貨店。以下是我的雜貨店戰略：</p>
<ul>
  <li>急需食材：我住的地方附近的Fairprice</li>
  <li>日常食品：Fairprice Xtra Vivo City / Cold Storage Fresh Great World City</li>
  <li>新鮮水果和蔬菜（如果時間允許）：我住的地方附近的街市</li>
  <li>火鍋/燒烤：我住的地方附近的Don Don Don Ki</li>
  <li>牛排/西式肉類：Hubers肉店</li>
</ul>

<p>就這樣。開心購物！不要忘記訂閱以查看更多此類內容。</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Food" /><category term="Groceries" /><category term="Singapore" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[嘿，大家好！今天我們要來聊一聊新加坡的必去雜貨店和超市，以及我選購特定雜貨的心得。在開始之前，我要先坦白，我可是超市迷。我特別喜歡在國外逛各種不同的超市，所以今天的主題讓我非常興奮，希望你也能感受到同樣的興奮。]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/grocery.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/grocery.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">學車必讀指南：一次通過新加坡駕照考試的心得分享</title><link href="/driving/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="學車必讀指南：一次通過新加坡駕照考試的心得分享" /><published>2023-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/zh/driving</id><content type="html" xml:base="/driving/"><![CDATA[<p>我爸總是堅持要我拿到駕照。在他的年代，駕駛證是找份工作的途徑，因為開卡車或計程車至少能保證你有基本薪水。顯然，時代已經改變。在新加坡，由於公共運輸系統十分健全，駕駛從來都不是必需的。然而，對於那些想要開車的人來說，獲得新加坡駕照可能有些棘手。受日本駕照考試系統啟發，新加坡的駕照考試以難度大而聞名。今天，我將解析如何取得駕照，並分享我第一次考試如何（幾乎）成功通過。</p>

<h4 id="什麼是取得合格駕駛執照qdl的過程">什麼是取得合格駕駛執照（QDL）的過程？</h4>

<p>新加坡的法定駕駛年齡是18歲。對於大多數人來說，3類或3A類駕照已經足夠，它允許你駕駛載重不超過3000公斤，最多可載7名乘客（不包括駕駛員）的汽車。</p>

<p><u>對於持有外國駕駛證的人…<u></u></u></p>

<p>…程序相當簡單。根據交通警察網站所述：</p>

<ol>
  <li>在新加坡的任何駕駛中心通過基本理論考試（BTT</li>
  <li>持有有效的合格外國駕駛證</li>
  <li>持有由許可機構提供的駕駛證記錄摘錄，其中包括外國駕駛證首次發放日期和駕駛證到期日期；</li>
  <li>持有有效的國際駕駛執照（IDP</li>
</ol>

<p>&lt;u?對於沒有外國駕駛證的人…<u></u></p>

<p>…則需要多些步驟。</p>
<ol>
  <li>在駕駛中心註冊</li>
  <li>通過眼睛和色彩測試</li>
  <li>通過基本理論考試（BTT）：50個問題，50分鐘，45/50通過</li>
  <li>通過最終理論考試（FTT）：50個問題，50分鐘，45/50通過；只有在通過基本理論考試後才能進行</li>
  <li>開始上路駕駛課程：在駕駛學校或透過私人課程進行；</li>
  <li>完成三次駕駛模擬器課程：只有完成5次實際駕駛課程後才能進行。這些模擬器就像你在遊戲中心玩的駕駛遊戲，只是速度更慢，且更具教育性</li>
  <li>通過實際駕駛考試（PDT）。評估內容包括：巡迴測試-在指定的測試場內完成各個站，以測試平行停車、垂直停車、方向變換、緊急停車、爬坡、坡道行駛、通過彎曲課程、通過S形課程。這些站點的順序不固定，取決於測試場內的交通狀況. 公路測試-在道路上行駛，測試方向控制、道路禮儀、變換車道和迴轉。</li>
</ol>

<p>備註：如果你在巡迴測試中失敗，你將無法在其他部分的考試中上路行駛。</p>

<h4 id="駕校對比私教選擇的抉擇">駕校對比私教：選擇的抉擇</h4>
<p>這問題已被廣泛討論了（例如 GetGo 的這一篇文章），所以我就不再重複。不過，我會提醒你一些需要注意的事項。</p>

<p><u>駕駛學校<u></u></u></p>

<p>新加坡有三個主要的駕駛學校：</p>
<ul>
  <li>Comfort DelGro Driving Center，簡稱CDC - 位於烏美（東部）</li>
  <li>新加坡安全驾驶中心（Singapore Safety Driving Center，簡稱SSDC）位於兀兰（北部）</li>
  <li>武吉巴督驾驶中心（Bukit Batok Driving Center，簡稱BBDC）位於武吉巴督（西部）</li>
</ul>

<p>首先，有必要了解，新加坡的大多數駕駛學校都位於市郊，主要是為了提供足夠的空間用於訓練設施。所以，如果你住在市中心，就必須考慮通勤的時間。現在，讓我們來分析一下選擇駕駛學校的優缺點：</p>

<p>優點：</p>
<ul>
  <li>針對初學者提供結構化的課程。</li>
  <li>預約訓練場地方便。</li>
  <li>初次考試合格率較高。</li>
</ul>

<p>缺點：</p>
<ul>
  <li>在大多數情況下，學費較高。</li>
  <li>結構化的課程需要更多時間投入。</li>
  <li>需要爭奪駕駛時間段，使用學校的預約系統。</li>
</ul>

<p><u>私人教練<u>
由於新加坡的法規變化，私人駕駛教練的數量逐漸減少，但它們仍然可以找到（我是通過一個網站找到我的教練的），稍後我會分享更多我的經歷。</u></u></p>

<p>優點：</p>
<ul>
  <li>靈活的課程安排</li>
  <li>可根據你的需求自定義時間表</li>
  <li>教練可以在你家附近接你</li>
  <li>通常比駕駛學校更經濟實惠</li>
</ul>

<p>缺點：</p>
<ul>
  <li>教練的水平可能有所不同</li>
  <li>需要提前預約訓練場地</li>
</ul>

<p><u>我的駕駛經驗和我如何奇蹟般通過駕駛考試<u>
在我的情況下，由於我在美國已經有一些駕駛經驗，所以我選擇了私人駕駛教練的路線。在幾年前搬到新加坡之前，我已經完成了大約30小時的駕駛課程。甚至我嘗試參加了當地的駕照考試，但結果很不理想（當時我幾乎撞到了另一輛車）。但是，考慮到我的「經驗」，我認為選擇私人駕駛教練是一個更靈活的選擇。通過私人教練，我參加了一些課程，以熟悉駕駛技巧，並練習在左側行駛（美國是右側行駛）——聽起來很簡單，對吧？</u></u></p>

<p><u>選擇武吉巴督驾驶中心（BBDC)<u>
我選擇了武吉巴督驾驶中心（BBDC），主要是因為它距離我住的地方較近。他們的報名系統有些混亂。記住，提前預約報名、筆試和路試，因為通常需要等待1.5個月。不用擔心在BBDC帳戶中多充值一些錢，一旦你通過考試，他們會退還多余的錢給你。我選擇了3A級駕照，因為我認為學習手動操控沒有必要。</u></u></p>

<p><u>考過我的BTT和FTT<u>
首先，不必買那些昂貴的考試書籍。我花了太多時間準備這些筆試，這是我無法挽回的時間。最簡單的方法是在網上搜索例題（例如這個練習考試網站），然後盡可能多地進行練習。這些問題都是多選題，大多數都是常識，但請花時間回答，不要感到緊張，即使有些20歲的年輕人在前5分鐘就通過了。但千萬不要忽略學習道路標誌-這些肯定會出現在考試中。考試結束後，你將立即知道自己是否通過。</u></u></p>

<p>此外，我還做了兩套詳盡的學習筆記，如果有興趣，可以聯繫我，我很樂意分享。這些筆記幫助我復習和記憶重要的知識點，也有助於我在考試中更有信心</p>

<p><u>選擇一位教練<u>
我選擇了陳先生，一位年過70的資深教練。起初，他不情願接受我作為學生，因為他已經滿額了。但通過堅持和說服，我最終成功說服了他。他的費用包括一次性註冊費、課程費、帶練習場的課程費以及考試車輛租金。由於通脹，現在的費用可能會更高，但他的指導和建議是無價的。他在教授駕駛技巧方面非常有耐心，並給予了實用的駕駛提示。在他的車上，我一直感到非常安全，這對於培養駕駛信心非常重要。</u></u></p>

<p>為了更好地備戰考試，我們在BBDC附近的駕駛課程中熟悉了考試路線，並在蔡厝港附近的一個臨時停車場練習停車以及S / 曲線課程。通過幾節課的練習，我恢復了駕駛的信心。但要注意，賽道是我最困難的地方，因為那裡有其他人在練習，還有人在參加考試，感覺非常繁忙。在最後的考試之前，我總共去了賽道5次，這有助於我更好地熟悉考試條件。</p>

<p><u>考試當天<u>
參加考試是我人生中最讓人緊張的經歷，甚至比任何工作面試、高管演講或體育比賽都要緊張。考試當天，我在教練的車裡熱身，然後在交通警察辦公室等待我的考官。一位體重達200磅的男士出現了，告訴我他是我的考官，然後硬擠進了我的小車。開始時，我表現得不錯，但在賽道的某個部分，我不小心踩下了煞車。真是太傻了。我當時以為我失敗了，但考官沒有說任何話，所以我繼續考試。最終，我通過了賽道，完成了道路考試，然後返回駕駛中心。我在交通警察辦公室等待了長達15分鐘，才終於得知我通過了！雖然我犯了18個違章，但考官可能認為我是一位安全而謹慎的駕駛者，所以對我寬容了一些。我顯然非常幸運，但這也是一種成就感。</u></u></p>

<p>通過考試後，我走到BBDC櫃檯，領取了合格駕駛執照（QDL）的文件。就在我走出BBDC中心的那一刻，天空突然開始傾盆大雨，我再次感到非常幸運。</p>

<p><u>駕照取得的關鍵統計數據<u>
獲得駕照花了6個月 - 我在4月30日參加了BTT考試，並在11月9日通過了PDT考試。 總共上了16小時的駕駛課程 - 包括PDT考試前的暖身課程，我總共上了十二次80分鐘的課程。 花了1430美元 - 包括駕駛學校的註冊費、駕駛課程和汽車租賃費用。</u></u></p>

<p>就這樣！自從我通過考試以來，我在新加坡開車了幾次，還有一次在國外。公共交通仍然是我首選的通勤方式，但至少我已經掌握了駕駛作為一項生活技能。我建議我的朋友們不要坐在我的車裡，但實際上，我並不是一個那麼糟糕的司機。非常感謝您的閱讀，請不要忘記訂閱以獲取類似的內容。</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="學車" /><category term="新加坡" /><category term="駕照" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[我爸總是堅持要我拿到駕照。在他的年代，駕駛證是找份工作的途徑，因為開卡車或計程車至少能保證你有基本薪水。顯然，時代已經改變。在新加坡，由於公共運輸系統十分健全，駕駛從來都不是必需的。然而，對於那些想要開車的人來說，獲得新加坡駕照可能有些棘手。受日本駕照考試系統啟發，新加坡的駕照考試以難度大而聞名。今天，我將解析如何取得駕照，並分享我第一次考試如何（幾乎）成功通過。]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/road.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/road.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">香港美食達人親評，新加坡點心之最竟藏此地</title><link href="/dimsum/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="香港美食達人親評，新加坡點心之最竟藏此地" /><published>2023-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/zh/dimsum</id><content type="html" xml:base="/dimsum/"><![CDATA[<p>嗨各位美食愛好者！今天要跟大家聊一聊新加坡的點心餐廳，尤其是我心中的佳餚和黑名單。作為一位來自香港的吃貨，我深信我們有一種特殊的舌尖，能夠分辨出點心的好壞。是不是鮮蝦餃的皮太厚了？豉油的味道過鹹或者過甜了嗎？春卷是不是油炸得不夠乾爽？每當我享受點心的時候，這些疑問總在腦海中縈繞。雖然我不是專業的評審，但我真心想表揚那些在點心製作方面做得出色的餐廳。好消息是，新加坡有著不少出色的點心餐廳，接下來就讓我們一探究竟，看看我心目中的美味和不推薦的地方吧！</p>

<p>首先，讓我分享一下我在各個點心餐廳進行的品味測試。說實話，我比較偏愛咸味的選擇，所以對於甜點心的品評可能不太多，請大家見諒。
我們先來談談茶，這可是我們點心之旅的開始。一杯好茶不僅能夠清潔口腔，更應該有著清新的口感和濃郁的香氣。接著是燒賣，這道廣東經典菜可是代表之一。鮮蝦的大小和豬肉與蝦的比例需要剛剛好，這樣才能帶來最美味的口感。再來是蝦餃，也是廣東菜的瑰寶之一。蝦餃的口感受很多因素影響，包括鮮蝦的大小、皮的厚度以及餡料的調味。而牛肉球則是我極愛的點心之一，評價標準包括牛肉中面粉的含量、是否添加了乾橙皮，以及肉汁的保留程度。蒸排骨搭配大蒜和豆豉是最棒的組合，注意過多的面粉會讓排骨失去原有的肉質口感，太小的排骨又可能讓人覺得不夠滿足。最後，叉燒包絕對是一道考驗餐廳手藝的點心，饅頭的鬆軟程度和叉燒醬的調味都是至關重要的。</p>

<p>最後，讓我們揭曉大家一直等待的名單：</p>

<h3 id="---每週週末值得一試的可靠選擇">$$ - 每週週末值得一試的可靠選擇</h3>

<p><u>添好運點心專門店 (Tim Ho Wan)−香港的OG<u>
首先，讓我們來到添好運點心專門店，這是一個來自香港的經典品牌。這個品牌的創始廚師曾在四季酒店的三星米其林中餐廳「龍景軒」工作，後來決定開設自己的點心店。令人驚奇的是，在開業僅一年內，位於旺角的原始添好運店就獲得了一顆米其林星，實在是令人矚目。他們後來也在新加坡展開了業務，在島上擁有12家以上的分店（可能是特許經營）。雖然新加坡的菜單略有不同於香港，但品質始終如一</u></u></p>

<p>必試菜品：酥皮焗叉燒包，這是對香港經典叉燒包的一種新嘗試，外層是酥皮，有點像菠蘿包，絕對是一道令人垂涎的美食</p>

<p><u>樂天小香港 (Cantonese Paradise)−本地可靠的連鎖店地點<u>
這個連鎖店隸屬於「樂天集團」，在整個島上分佈著多家分店。他們以優質的香港菜、點心和燒臘而聞名，雖然環境可能參差不齊，但食物的品質很少讓人失望。有趣的是，如果你在樂天集團工作超過10年，居然還能獲得一枚免費的勞力士手錶！</u></u></p>

<p>必試菜品：XO醬炒蘿蔔糕，這款菜品和在小販中心找到的蘿蔔糕截然不同，我對XO醬的獨特風味情有獨鍾，這道菜簡直讓人欲罷不能。注意：以上僅為個人意見和推薦，每個人的口味偏好有所不同。建議您自行品嚐並形成自己的判斷</p>

<p><u>寶一點心 (Treasures yi dian xin) - 星期日的必選之地<u>
別將這家餐廳與香港的一點心或小販中心的一點心混淆，這裡是至寶集團的一部分，與味之樂相似，提供正宗可靠的點心。如果你恰好在Orchard地區，這將是你星期日午餐的最佳選擇。</u></u></p>

<p>必試菜品：簡單而美味，入味且多汁。</p>

<p><u>香港傳奇 (Legendary HK)- 茶餐廳風格的點心<u>
雖然我在香港老字號的首選通常是米飯或麵食，但他們的點心卻出奇的美味。在這裡，你甚至可以透過餐廳入口處的玻璃窗一睹點心製作的全過程。如果你想要品嚐家鄉的味道，香港老字號絕對是你的不二之選。</u></u></p>

<p>必試菜品：任何一款粥，份量十足，極其鬆軟且濃郁的味道讓人回味無窮。</p>

<h4 id="---超越期望的高尚體驗">$$$ - 超越期望的高尚體驗</h4>

<p><u>華樂酒家 (Wah Lok) - 經濟實惠的奢華<u>
這家位於卡爾頓酒店的餐廳絕對值得一試。歷經歲月的洗禮，這個歷史悠久的餐廳在價格上並不貴，卻能呈現出經濟實惠的奢華。他們的包子和餃子飽滿多汁，炒飯則不會過於油膩，每粒米飯都清晰可見。華樂的點心菜單絕對是物超所值。</u></u></p>

<p>必試菜品：蝦餃，這款餃子由巨大的蝦和薄薄的外皮組成，絕對是新加坡最佳的蝦餃之一。還有鹹魚雞粒炒飯，這道菜或許只在中國新年時才能品嚐，但如果你有機會，一定不能錯過。這款炒飯散發出的香氣絕對令人難以忘懷。</p>

<p><u>江南春 (Jiang Nan Chun) - 高檔奢華<u>
接著，我們將進入四季酒店的江南春，這個高檔奢華的餐廳定會讓你驚艷。隨機的一個星期日，我決定前往這家擁有米其林星星的餐廳，點了菜單上的每一款點心，還點了幾道開胃菜。江南春以其一流的服務，高品質的茶和精緻的糖葫蘆蔬菜而聞名，每一道點心都讓人難以忘懷。雖然菜單上的所有點心都表現出色，但我對他們的蒸點更加著迷。</u></u></p>

<p>必試菜品：江南春的叉燒也是不容錯過的，稍微有些燒焦，多汁卻不過軟，是新加坡最好的叉燒之一。龍蝦帶子餃則用精緻的米皮包裹著優質的食材，實在令人愛不釋手。</p>

<p><u>玉樓 (Jade) - 我的首選點心「自助餐」<u>
每位只需58元在福樂頓酒店，就能享受到15款點心的美食盛宴。儘管不是傳統的無限自助餐，你不能重複點同一道菜，點心數量也有限制，但玉樓餐廳的廣東菜味道一流，給你帶來現代風格的用餐體驗。</u></u></p>

<p>必試菜品：紅燒菘露蛋白蟹肉燕窩羹的濃郁口感和深海龍蝦粥的豐富肉塊都是必試之選。</p>

<p>需避免：叉燒、脆皮龍蝦餃和時令蔬菜。</p>

<h4 id="我的黑名單">我的黑名單</h4>

<p>有幾家地方我覺得被過度炒作，價格過高或者過於花俏。簡單概述一下原因：</p>
<ul>
  <li>瑞春點心 - 過度炒作，品質普通，用料平庸</li>
  <li>黑社會的MASA - 風格超過實質</li>
  <li>樊女士 - 價格過高，面向外國人</li>
</ul>

<p>需要注意的是，這只是我的個人評價，你的口味可能有所不同。如果你還有其他點心推薦，別忘了告訴我，我會毫不猶豫地前去品嚐。記得訂閱我，以免錯過我即將分享的下一篇美食文章。讓我們一起迎接下一場美食探險吧！</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="美食" /><category term="香港" /><category term="新加坡" /><category term="點心" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[嗨各位美食愛好者！今天要跟大家聊一聊新加坡的點心餐廳，尤其是我心中的佳餚和黑名單。作為一位來自香港的吃貨，我深信我們有一種特殊的舌尖，能夠分辨出點心的好壞。是不是鮮蝦餃的皮太厚了？豉油的味道過鹹或者過甜了嗎？春卷是不是油炸得不夠乾爽？每當我享受點心的時候，這些疑問總在腦海中縈繞。雖然我不是專業的評審，但我真心想表揚那些在點心製作方面做得出色的餐廳。好消息是，新加坡有著不少出色的點心餐廳，接下來就讓我們一探究竟，看看我心目中的美味和不推薦的地方吧！]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/dimsumjade.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/dimsumjade.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">揭示建立穩定國家的公式：新加坡的三大支柱</title><link href="/stablenation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="揭示建立穩定國家的公式：新加坡的三大支柱" /><published>2023-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/zh/stablenation</id><content type="html" xml:base="/stablenation/"><![CDATA[<p>1991年，新加坡政府倡導了五項共同價值觀，這些價值觀成為塑造新加坡國民認同的重要支柱。其中，蘊含著以下核心理念：a）國家高於個人、社區高於團體 b）家庭是社會基石 c）社區的支持與尊重是關鍵 d）共識遠勝於衝突 e）種族與宗教和諧共存。這些價值觀富含理想主義色彩，為新加坡的成長定下堅實基礎。</p>

<p>從理念到現實：三大支柱的構築 然而，當我深入探索新加坡的成功秘訣時，我發現這背後還有三個關鍵因素。我將其稱之為「三大H」，每一個因素都關乎人類基本需求，共同構築著新加坡社會的根基。它們是：</p>
<ul>
  <li>住房 (housing) - 「我有一個溫馨的家」</li>
  <li>小販 (hakwers) - 「我能輕鬆享受經濟實惠的美食」</li>
  <li>和諧 (harmony) - 「我生活在安全和諧的環境中」</li>
</ul>

<p>正是這三大因素，將新加坡引領向可持續發展的道路。聯合國的2030年可持續發展目標中（目標2、9、10、11）所提倡的要素，在這裡得到了真切體現。而最終，這三大支柱共同形成了每個國家都追求的「希望」。</p>

<h4 id="住房">住房</h4>
<p>即使過去五年裡房價波動頗大，新加坡的公共住房計劃仍然是為每個人提供遮風避雨的最佳範本。事實上，世界銀行讚揚新加坡建立了全球最佳的公共住房計劃。 從上世紀40年代初，新加坡政府就開始推動公共住房（HDB）計劃，以改善人口急劇增長帶來的居住問題。政府鼓勵人們擁有房產，將這種擁有逐漸演變為社會穩定的基石，形成了擁有房產的社會階層。簡言之，這是對新加坡未來與繁榮的共同財富。 雖然我不會在此詳細探討公共住房的細節（如BTO、轉售和發展地點）、私人住房或租賃市場，但我想著重指出下表，以清晰比較新加坡和香港的公共住房情況。</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: left"> </th>
      <th style="text-align: center">新加坡</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">香港</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">公民擁有住房</td>
      <td style="text-align: center"><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2022-06-27/how-much-will-singapore-rents-rise-surging-prices-put-expats-under-pressure#:~:text=Singapore%20abolished%20rent%20controls%20in,Ministry%20of%20National%20Development%20said.">90%</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center"><a href="https://www.legco.gov.hk/research-publications/english/2021rb02-socioeconomic-implications-of-home-ownership-for-hong-kong-20210301-e.pdf">50%</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">公共住房比例</td>
      <td style="text-align: center"><a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/966747/population-living-in-public-housing-singapore/">80%</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: center"><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/society/article/2182106/why-public-housing-shortfall-will-remain-thorn-hong-kongs">45%</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left">每個家庭月收入上限</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">$14K SGD ($10.4K USD)</td>
      <td style="text-align: center"><a href="https://www.housingauthority.gov.hk/en/flat-application/income-and-asset-limits/index.html">$30.9K HKD</a> ($3.9K USD)</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>新加坡90%的公民擁有自己的住房，而香港僅為50%，這突顯了兩地住房機會的明顯差異。特別是在公共住房方面，差距更加明顯。這凸顯了新加坡致力於創造最低生活質量，將住房視為人們的普遍需求。而當我們將目光投向新的公共住房收入上限時，新加坡的上限比香港高出2.6倍。香港的公共住房雖然專注於低收入家庭，但缺少關注提高生活質量的意願與理念，這也在其高基尼係數上得到反映。</p>

<h4 id="小販">小販</h4>
<p>美食與文化的交匯處 解決飢餓問題並確保國家更健康且更有生產力，是一個重要的課題。在新加坡，透過小販中心來解決這個問題成為一個成功的範例。 曾經，提供有組織的空間並提高攤販衛生標準的方法，如今已成為新加坡人生活中不可或缺的一部分，並且被聯合國教科文組織列為人類非物質文化遺產的代表作品。小販中心以親民的價格匯聚各種民族的著名本地美食。五年前，普通的雞飯或肉腸面售價為3至3.5新加坡元。而現在的價格約為5新加坡元。這個價格比自行烹飪要便宜，因此約有25％的新加坡人每天在外用餐。
香港也有類似的選擇，例如茶餐廳、大排檔和熟食中心。儘管價格對大眾來說仍然可負擔，約為7新加坡元，但相較於新加坡，這是一個40％的增加。考慮到兩國家庭收入中位數相似，新加坡在價格親民方面優勝。</p>

<h4 id="和諧">和諧</h4>
<p>共同維護安全與凝聚力 為了簡化說明，我將「和諧」定義為「在我的生活環境中，我作為一個個體的安全感」。這可以從種族、宗教和身體安全的角度來看。雖然實現完全的和諧是困難的，但政府已制定了細緻的政策，致力於確保安全和社會凝聚力。其中一些例子包括長期保持種族組成的CMIO配額（華人、馬來人、印度人、其他族裔之間的比例），在整個新加坡範圍內（不僅限於城市地區）建設公共住房，並確保每個主要種族和宗教都有兩個公共假日。至於香港，近年來的一些動盪局面不容忽視。</p>

<p>有了以上的三個H，它們也為國家帶來了「希望」(hope)。這三個H成為新加坡成功之路的基石，儘管在過程中遇到各種挑戰，但其堅實的基礎將繼續是該國的競爭優勢。</p>

<p>別忘了立即訂閱，以免錯過任何精彩內容！</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="新加坡" /><category term="移居" /><category term="住房" /><category term="美食" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[1991年，新加坡政府倡導了五項共同價值觀，這些價值觀成為塑造新加坡國民認同的重要支柱。其中，蘊含著以下核心理念：a）國家高於個人、社區高於團體 b）家庭是社會基石 c）社區的支持與尊重是關鍵 d）共識遠勝於衝突 e）種族與宗教和諧共存。這些價值觀富含理想主義色彩，為新加坡的成長定下堅實基礎。]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/sdg.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/sdg.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">攻略新加坡公民身份：揭秘成功獲取PR的關鍵</title><link href="/singapore-PR/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="攻略新加坡公民身份：揭秘成功獲取PR的關鍵" /><published>2023-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/zh/singapore-PR</id><content type="html" xml:base="/singapore-PR/"><![CDATA[<p>大家好！在前幾篇文章中，我已經和大家分享了我從美國到新加坡的移居經歷，以及我對這個過程的一些疑慮。現在，我非常興奮地要分享一些關於獲得新加坡永久居民身份的寶貴經驗與技巧。儘管我並不是律師，但作為一個成功獲得PR的人，我相信我的分享將對計劃移居新加坡的你有所幫助。</p>

<p>首先，讓我們明確一點：千萬不要浪費時間和金錢去找移民代辦。他們的收費昂貴，回報有限，甚至可能使用一些奇怪的手段來吸引你，比如所謂的永居成功計算器等等。我認識的朋友們中有很多人因為和代辦合作而感到後悔，他們最終並未獲得永居身份。這或許不能代表所有情況，但這一點值得我們深思熟慮。讓我們從基本知識開始。</p>

<h4 id="新加坡永久居民身份-pr-意味著什麼">新加坡永久居民身份 (PR) 意味著什麼？</h4>

<p>首先，我們需要了解什麼是新加坡永久居民身份（PR）。這是一種移民身份，允許你在新加坡居住、工作和學習，且沒有時間限制（當然還有一些細微差別，稍後我會解釋）。新加坡約有52萬名永久居民，佔總人口的9%。每年對PR的數量有約3萬個的限制，而申請的人數則高達約10萬份。</p>

<h4 id="有幾種主要方式可以獲得新加坡永久居民身份">有幾種主要方式可以獲得新加坡永久居民身份：</h4>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>全球投資者計劃（GIP）
如果你有足夠的資金，這可能是一個相對容易的途徑。你可以通過以下方式之一申請PR：1）投資1000萬新加坡元創業，2）投資2500萬新加坡元在GIP選定的基金中，3）在新加坡設立一個至少擁有2億新加坡元資產管理的單一家族辦公室。從2020年到2022年，GIP計劃批准了約200個PR申請。</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>外國藝術人才計劃
 這個途徑適用於那些在藝術領域有才華並符合一定標準的人。不過，對大多數人來說可能較為遙遠。</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>專業人士/技術人員和熟練工人計劃（PTS）
 這是大多數人使用的途徑，特別是那些持有就業通行證（EP）的人。這也是我選擇的途徑，因為我既沒有足夠的資金，也沒有藝術才華</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>重要的是要注意，通過這個途徑獲得PR的人主申請者將豁免國家服務的要求。</p>

<h4 id="為什麼要申請pr它又有哪些好處">為什麼要申請PR，它又有哪些好處？</h4>

<p>獲得新加坡永久居民身份有許多好處，例如：</p>

<ul>
  <li>無限制地留在國家：在目前的裁員環境中，PR已經成為那些想要在新加坡長期居住的人的一個強有力的選擇。此外，如果你的父母希望在新加坡逗留，你還可以為他們申請長期探親護照（LTVP）。</li>
  <li>就業機會優勢：PR在就業方面有一些優勢。政府規定，公民和PR在就業機會方面享有優先權。此外，PR可以參與更多賺錢的事業，而就業通行證（EP）則只允許全職工作。此外，PR還可以獲得就業再培訓福利，提升技能，應對失業。</li>
  <li>購買HDB二手房：這雖然對大多數人來說可能不是最重要的因素，但是對於一些人來說可能很重要。不過需要注意的是，單個PR並不具資格購買HDB二手房。</li>
  <li>CPF（公積金）貢獻：類似於401K（美國）/ MPF（香港）的退休金基金。這是一個優點和一個缺點。它有助於儲蓄並提供穩定的利率，但大多數人在其他地方投資資金可以獲得更高的回報。</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="有資格申請新加坡公民身份">有資格申請新加坡公民身份</h4>
<p>PR是獲得新加坡公民身份的擺脫。對於護照較弱或希望長期在該國定居的人來說非常有益。</p>

<h4 id="新加坡pr有哪些缺點">新加坡PR有哪些缺點？</h4>
<p>主要有兩個：</p>
<ol>
  <li>如果PR希望在新加坡以外的地方逗留，則需要符合再入境許可（REP）的要求
 再入境許可（REP）是重返新加坡所需的。它們每5年到期一次，因此儘管PR在紙面上提供了留在該國的途徑，但REP才是真正決定您是否保留新加坡PR的因素。更新的因素包括您是否納稅，是否在新加坡工作等。這確保那些擁有PR身份的人實際上在新加坡並做出貢獻。</li>
  <li>兵役義務
 這是真正令人擔憂的事情。“根據其父母的贊助或以外國學生的身份獲得PR身份的男性申請人，需要在16歲半時登記兵役，並在18歲時安排最早的機會入伍”。無論從安全還是時間最佳利用的角度來看，這是我同輩中申請PR的主要阻礙。</li>
</ol>

<h4 id="成功的pr申請者有哪些因素">成功的PR申請者有哪些因素？</h4>
<p>這是根據我所知的成功PR申請的檢查清單：</p>
<ul>
  <li>職業經驗：擁有聲譽良好且薪酬豐厚的工作，填補新加坡的人才缺口（例如研發、科技）有所幫助。這表明您能夠從人才和稅收的角度對新加坡的經濟做出貢獻。</li>
  <li>教育水平：教育程度越高越好（至少學士學位）。您正在與最優秀的人競爭，所以我認為這是必要的。</li>
  <li>年齡：人口老齡化的情況下，年輕人更有優勢。</li>
  <li>停留時間：沒有硬性規定，但我建議申請人在該國停留2年以上。這表明您的承諾和融入程度。</li>
  <li>與新加坡社會的融入：在我看來，這是最重要的因素，因為新加坡強調和諧。移民機構建議申請人捐贈或自願參與志願活動，以表明他們關心當地的事業和個人。雖然我認為這不是必要的，但它是融入的一部分。</li>
</ul>

<p>那麼，為什麼獲得PR如此困難？其中一個原因是申請人數眾多。有人還說，根據新加坡社會構成的種族比例，存在配額制度，因為“新加坡公民人口中每個種族的比例在二十年間保持穩定”。但是，關於種族配額的具體數據並不明確，因此我不會去推測。</p>

<h4 id="我的pr申請經歷">我的PR申請經歷</h4>
<p>我在2020年2月的COVID時期申請了PR。整個過程花了九個月的時間（根據新加坡移民局網站上的平均時間為六個月），在2020年11月收到了結果通知。</p>

<p>根據上述檢查清單，我個人的資格和成功因素如下：</p>
<ul>
  <li>在一家大型科技公司擔任商業角色，擁有出色的績效和發展軌跡</li>
  <li>就讀世界排名前25的大學獲得學士學位</li>
  <li>二十多歲，未有子女</li>
  <li>在新加坡停留了2.5年</li>
  <li>會講廣東話，來自香港（我認為這有助於融入）。這是我認為香港人有優勢的一點，因為兩地之間有相似之處</li>
</ul>

<p>作為我的申請的一部分，我還附上了一些增值文件，以幫助自己脫穎而出。雖然申請表中沒有正式的空間供增值文件使用，但可以將這些文件上傳到申請中的任何空白文件欄位中。這些文件包括：</p>
<ul>
  <li>求職信 - 介紹我的背景，為什麼選擇新加坡以及我如何能夠貢獻和融入社會</li>
  <li>來自新加坡公民的兩封推薦信 - 介紹我們的關係，為什麼我對這個國家有好處</li>
  <li>簡歷 - 我的專業資格和學術背景</li>
</ul>

<p>其他人也會附上他們的獎項或志願者證書，但我沒有這些。如果你想要一份我的求職信和推薦信的副本，請隨時與我聯繫。</p>

<p>當我得知我的申請成功時，我非常開心。反正我本來對此沒有太高的期望。最後，如果你的申請不成功，只要在一年後再試一次，但在重新申請時，確保你的申請有實質性的變化，例如工作變動、家庭狀況改變等。</p>

<p>祝願大家在永久居留申請中一帆風順！如果你有任何疑問，不要猶豫，隨時與我聯繫哦。還記得要訂閱，以便獲取更多類似內容！期待與你們分享更多精彩！</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="新加坡" /><category term="移居" /><category term="PR" /><category term="永久居民" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[大家好！在前幾篇文章中，我已經和大家分享了我從美國到新加坡的移居經歷，以及我對這個過程的一些疑慮。現在，我非常興奮地要分享一些關於獲得新加坡永久居民身份的寶貴經驗與技巧。儘管我並不是律師，但作為一個成功獲得PR的人，我相信我的分享將對計劃移居新加坡的你有所幫助。]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/sgpr.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/sgpr.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">新加坡必看！我移居前的頭五大煩惱曝光</title><link href="/top-concerns/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="新加坡必看！我移居前的頭五大煩惱曝光" /><published>2023-03-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-03-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/zh/top-concerns</id><content type="html" xml:base="/top-concerns/"><![CDATA[<p>在前文中，我已分享我為何決定搬到新加坡的原因。然而，在做出這個決定之前，我確實抱持著一些疑慮。這些疑慮來自各方各面：政府和公司的數據、與移居者的對話、當地新加坡人的看法、網上的研究，以及在移居前兩年的兩次提前訪問。以下就是我當時的五大擔憂：</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>薪水減少40%
從舊金山搬到新加坡，我的薪水無情地縮水了40%，簡直令人心疼。這種薪資下降是由於人工成本的差異所致，因為新加坡的成本遠低於舊金山。考慮到生活成本和稅收，我的估計是淨收入下降了大約15-18%。另外，股權的價值也下降約30%，對我的總收入造成了重大影響。我在新加坡又花了1.5年的時間，並在晉升後才重新達到了在美國剛畢業時的起薪水平。</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>炎熱潮濕的氣候
舊金山的氣候全年涼爽乾燥，新加坡則是一年四季炎熱潮濕，每天的溫度輕易超過攝氏30度（即使在12月）。這裡沒有明顯的季節變化，雨水也是無法預測的。或許因為我曾在香港度過夏天，我原以為能輕鬆適應炎熱，但結果證明我大錯特錯。此外，新加坡還有一種讓我這個過敏患者困擾的塵蟎變種（搜索blomia tropicalis）。</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>有限且乏味的範圍
新加坡的面積僅有紐約市的一小部分，只有720平方公里，這使得在這麼小的地方很難有太多機會和活動。因此，你會看到不少人（尤其是外籍人士）經常前往東南亞附近的國家度假。由於自然資源和地勢的限制，新加坡的戶外活動機會相對有限。雖然逛購物中心、看Netflix和外出用餐都不錯，但卻不是最具挑戰性的選擇。</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>人工建構的氛圍
新加坡的發展確實受益於李光耀的經濟模式，但這個國家的現代化主要側重於進步，而不是保留。例如，著重於標準化住房，忽略了傳統村落的保護。這使得新加坡有時給人一種人工建構的感覺，彷彿為了滿足社交媒體上的期待而建造。儘管政府正在努力將藝術融入社會，但某些方面仍然顯得有限。相比之下，香港在發展和保留之間取得了更好的平衡，融合了獨特的歷史遺產和現代風景。</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>嚴格法律、過度管制和審查
新加坡以世界最嚴格的法規聞名，從禁售口香糖、公開示威需許可、LGBT審查，到禁止借用鄰居Wi-Fi。死刑合法，鞭刑更是刑罰。一步錯誤，似乎就會被趕出國！雖然這議題充滿爭議，五年後我發現新加坡嚴格制度確有其優勢，特別是保障國家穩定。
回顧清單，前兩項疑慮合情合理，後三點更複雜。期間有其他擔憂浮現（封閉性社會、高物價困擾），也有諸多疑慮被證明為錯誤。</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>接下來，我將分享如何首次嘗試取得永久居民身份。現在訂閱，別錯過精彩內容！</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="新加坡" /><category term="移居" /><category term="舊金山" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[在前文中，我已分享我為何決定搬到新加坡的原因。然而，在做出這個決定之前，我確實抱持著一些疑慮。這些疑慮來自各方各面：政府和公司的數據、與移居者的對話、當地新加坡人的看法、網上的研究，以及在移居前兩年的兩次提前訪問。以下就是我當時的五大擔憂：]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/top5concerns.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/top5concerns.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">我的跨國奇幻之旅:從香港到新加坡</title><link href="/relocating-to-Singapore/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="我的跨國奇幻之旅:從香港到新加坡" /><published>2023-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/zh/relocating-to-Singapore</id><content type="html" xml:base="/relocating-to-Singapore/"><![CDATA[<p>今天和大家聊聊我搬去新加坡之路。我從香港踏上美國求學，畢業後幸運地加入了一間不錯的科技公司。當時，我在舊金山的生活美好極了，可以品嚐到Mission區的墨西哥捲餅，清晨在Presidio公園漫步，生活過得很悠閒。但是，我始終知道待在美國並不是我長遠的計劃。現在，讓我分享一下當初我為何做出這個離開美國的決定吧：</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>渴望新鮮感： 言下之意，我對在灣區的生活感到有些無趣。經過五年的居住，我想走出目前的舒適區，開始嘗試更多可能性。年輕的我充滿好奇心，渴望一探其他國家的風情。</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>不安全感： 舊金山的流浪問題相當嚴重。晚上9點後，徒步行走幾乎是不可能的，而在香港或新加坡這是再普通不過的事情。而且，這座城市的整潔度遠不如想像中的好。走過Embarcadero、Market Street或坐過BART的人都知道，這個城市散發著一股尿臭味，而這在一個如此富饒的地區顯得相當諷刺。</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>移民麻煩： 我經歷了F1簽證→OPT工作簽證→H-1B簽證的過程，還好我順利地通過了H-1B的籤選（當時成功率約40%）。這個過程充滿了繁文縟節，讓人疲於奔命。即使獲得了H-1B，我知道我不想在美國長期居住。特朗普政府讓事情變得更加復雜，而且現在也不是移民的最佳時機。我知道在獲得綠卡之前，一切還會變得更加複雜，但我根本沒有想繼續追求綠卡。為什麼呢？下面是我的想法：</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>高稅與昂貴醫療保健： 聯邦稅約佔收入的25%，再加上州稅約10%。你工資的 35% 就這樣沒了。此外，美國的專業術語令人頭疼，例如預扣稅、醫療保險、社會保障等等。這一切對我來說實在是過於複雜。同樣的情況也出現在醫療保健領域。我一直不明白，為什麼美國的醫療保健不是免費和公共的，這種現象似乎是資本主義的最壞體現。</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>通勤浪費時間： 我每週一到週四都要搭乘公司的接駁車來回舊金山和南灣。平均而言，我早上6點50分搭乘接駁車，早上8點到達，下午4點30分搭乘接駁車，下午6點到達。儘管我通過打盹、工作、看YouTube等方式打發時間，但每個工作日花2.5小時在路上對我來說是毫無生產力的。</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>當初我有沒有堅定地把新加坡作為移居的地點？沒有。在我成長的過程中，新加坡只是另一個東南亞國家，一個陽光海灘的地方，不引人注目。我小時候去過那裡幾次度假，坦率地說，我對那個地方一無所知。那麼為什麼會轉移到新加坡呢？</p>

<ol>
  <li>我獲得了一份令人難以置信的工作機會。我的公司計劃允許在不同國家之間調動，而新加坡是我們的亞太區總部。亞太市場正在迅速增長，因此出現了大量具有出色職業前景的職位。雖然香港同樣國際化和友好於外籍人士，但科技機會有限。這也是我不考慮返回香港的主要原因之一。</li>
  <li>我的感情關係。我喜歡我當時的伴侶，希望繼續我們的旅程。她為了進一步學業而搬到新加坡，所以作為一個實際的人，我不得不搬遷以繼續這段關係。我向所有讀者提供一個建議 - 無論如何都不該只為了伴侶而移居到一個國家。總是要有其他理由來補充，因為如果你們的關係破裂，你會自責不已。</li>
  <li>新加坡離家人更近。我更喜歡從新加坡到香港的4小時飛行，而不是從舊金山到香港的15小時飛行。</li>
</ol>

<p>把這兩個原因列表合在一起，就足以吸引我去新加坡。回顧過去，我非常高興做出了來到這裡的決定，還有許多其他原因被添加到了“為什麼選擇新加坡”的列表中。想想低稅、治安、醫療保健、旅行機會、便利性等。我以後會解釋這些原因。</p>

<p>雖然過渡相對順利，但它並不是沒有自己的擔憂。立即訂閱以在我下一篇文章中了解更多信息。</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="新加坡" /><category term="移居" /><category term="舊金山" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[今天和大家聊聊我搬去新加坡之路。我從香港踏上美國求學，畢業後幸運地加入了一間不錯的科技公司。當時，我在舊金山的生活美好極了，可以品嚐到Mission區的墨西哥捲餅，清晨在Presidio公園漫步，生活過得很悠閒。但是，我始終知道待在美國並不是我長遠的計劃。現在，讓我分享一下當初我為何做出這個離開美國的決定吧：]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/assets/images/relocationfromsf.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/assets/images/relocationfromsf.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>